[{"topic": "Amusement+Parks", "question": "Of all the rides and features within Company ABC, which is your favorite?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know that you are familiar with the entertainment options offered at Company ABC. Briefly talk about your exposure to the entertainment options here and which has been your favorite.", "\"I spent the day at Company ABC last weekend and I couldn't get enough of XYZ. It was so much fun and I felt that the ride time was long enough to justify the wait in line. Overall, I had a really amazing time.\"", "\"I have not had the chance to visit your grounds until today and cannot wait to try XYZ; although, it all looks like so much fun!\""]}, {"topic": "Amusement+Parks", "question": "At Company ABC we do everything we can to reduce wait times for our rides. During peak hours, the wait times can still be up to one hour. How would you handle a customer who was really impatient and angry while waiting in line?", "answers": ["No matter the industry, you will always come across customers who are impatient, do not like to wait, and act as a disturbance to others. Do you have any training in customer dispute resolution? Perhaps you have handled a situation like this before? Assure the interviewer that you are capable of professionally, and maturely, handing a situation like this.", "\"I have had my fair share of customer dispute resolution from previous roles in retail and restaurants. When a customer is impatient, angry, or an overall disturbance I will politely ask them to calm their voice and have a productive conversation with me so that I can help them to achieve what they want. This generally diffuses the situation.\"", "\"If I cannot calm an upset customer down, I will call my supervisor or security - depending on the severity of the customers' actions. If I were the manager and could not calm the customer down, I would ask them to leave. I understand that the customer comes first; however, not at the cost of an enjoyable environment for other visitors.\""]}, {"topic": "Amusement+Parks", "question": "Describe to me your ideal employer.", "answers": ["A job search isn't just a one sided hunt. You must also feel as though this is a good fit for yourself. Tell the interviewer what your ideal employer looks like. Be specific and be sure to keep the conversation positive. Avoid speaking poorly of any previous managers or organizations.", "\"My ideal employer is one that brings charisma and passion to their work. I work best with organizations who have a penchant for learning and promote their employees based on performance.\"", "\"For me, an ideal place of employment is a place of mutual respect and continued growth.\""]}, {"topic": "Amusement+Parks", "question": "What would you do if a warning light came up on a ride that you were running?", "answers": ["At Company ABC you can be assured there are strict regulations surrounding rides and safety. Talk to the interviewer about your initial instinct in a situation like this. It is absolutely okay to ask the interviewer for details on the process when this happens.", "\"If a warning light came on a ride that I was running I would be sure to shut the ride down, call a supervisor, and notify everyone in line that the ride was temporarily disabled for regular maintenance. I would not want to alarm any visitors.\"", "\"Can you tell me a bit about your protocol surrounding a situation like this? I would follow your company protocol to a tee in situations such as this.\""]}, {"topic": "Amusement+Parks", "question": "Tell me about one of your goals. How are you working towards it?", "answers": ["If the interviewer asks you any general questions about goals, try to focus your answer on something career-oriented. The job you're interviewing for could help you achieve your goal by teaching you the skills and giving you valuable experience. Demonstrate that you are proactive and willing to take action in order to reach your goals.", "\"I want to go to graduate school to become a licensed social worker. I'm excited about this job because it will give me more experience with children and family. I think that the more exposure I have to the public, the closer I am getting to achieving my goal.\"", "\"Currently, I am saving to go on a 3 month trip through Europe. Working here will help me reach my goal financially and, because this is a seasonal job, I can take my trip during the off-season.\""]}, {"topic": "Amusement+Parks", "question": "What made you apply for this position with Company ABC?", "answers": ["Now is the time for you to express your enthusiasm for the company and the position that you applied for. Perhaps you are looking for a position that allows various tasks or maybe this company has a reputation for allowing career growth and continued development.", "\"I applied for this position because the hours of this role is exactly what I am looking for, and I really enjoy the environment here.\""]}, {"topic": "Amusement+Parks", "question": "At Company ABC we are considered a top-notch entertainment facility. In your opinion, what makes us stand out from others in our industry?", "answers": ["It is important to research Company ABC, and their potential competitors, before you interview with them. Is this a tourist attraction in a city full of attractions? Of all the local entertainment options, how does Company ABC stand out?", "\"Our city offers many attractions for tourists and families looking for affordable entertainment. There is a lot of competition, in a sense, but I feel that Company ABC stands out because you offer such a huge range of fun and entertainment options in one stop!\"", "\"I believe you stand out from your industry competitors because you have the best online reviews and your admission prices are affordable for everyone.\""]}, {"topic": "Amusement+Parks", "question": "This position will require you to be on your feet for most of the day. Are you capable of handling the physical strain?", "answers": ["Working at Company ABC will be challenging to you physically as much of your day will be spent walking, standing, and talking to the public. Assure the interviewer that you can handle this type of physical activity on a daily basis.", "\"I am a very active person and the majority of my jobs have been physically demanding. As long as I have the appropriate footwear, I am good to go!\"", "\"I have a mild restriction on standing because of a knee surgery I had last year. I am physically capable of standing a few hours at a time but would make sure to rest my knee on my breaks.\""]}, {"topic": "Amusement+Parks", "question": "At Company ABC we seek to hire enthusiastic and energetic individuals. How would you describe your personality?", "answers": ["This is a great time to show the interviewer that your personality will fit well with the workplace culture at Company ABC. How would your friends, co-workers, and previous employers best describe you? Talk a bit about your personality and be sure to refer to your glowing references as well!", "\"I would describe my personality as bubbly, positive, and high-energy. My previous co-workers would say the same about me. My current supervisor is willing to provide a great reference on my behalf as well. She often comments on my great teamwork and willingness to go above and beyond.\"", "\"I am confident, friendly, and a go-getter. Are these personality traits that you are looking for in your next hire?\""]}, {"topic": "Amusement+Parks", "question": "Because Company ABC is a family attraction, there are many crowds. Children sometimes become separated from their parents. What would you do if you saw a small child who was crying and alone?", "answers": ["Company ABC will have clear guidelines on how to handle children who have been separated from their guardians; however, the interviewer would like to know more about your personal instinct in a situation like this.", "\"I have worked retail in a shopping mall setting and we were always told to immediately bring the child to the closest security guard who would then bring them to the customer service kiosk. That is where most parents will go first when they notice that a child is lost. If this happened at Company ABC, my first instinct would be to do the same.\"", "\"Can you tell me a bit about your protocol surrounding a situation like this? I would follow your company protocol to a tee in situations such as this.\""]}, {"topic": "Amusement+Parks", "question": "At Company ABC we value the health and safety of our customers. What would you do if a park visitor fainted after participating on a ride?", "answers": ["Health and safety is an incredibly important factor for Company ABC as they want to avoid any negative reviews, or lawsuits. The interviewer is most interested in your personal instinct in a situation like this. How would you react?", "\"I am sure that Company ABC has strict protocols surrounding situations like this. My first instinct would be to call the on-site medics. I would not touch or move the individual to avoid causing further injury. If it was heat exhaustion, I could offer them a cold bottle of water and wait with them until the medics arrived.\"", "\"Can you tell me a bit about your protocol surrounding a situation like this? I would follow your company protocol to a tee in situations such as this.\""]}, {"topic": "Amusement+Parks", "question": "What would you do if you saw an unfamiliar  person in Company ABC uniform with no ID badge?", "answers": ["Most amusement parks have very high security for the protection of their visitors. The interviewer would like to know what your instinctive reaction would be if you were suspicious of an unauthorized person on site. It is absolutely okay to ask the interviewer how they would prefer these types of situations to be handled.", "\"My instinct would be to report the person immediately and not approach them directly. If I could safely snap a photo of them on my smartphone, I would do that too. Anyone posing as an employee likely has criminal intentions so a clear photo, or description of the person, would be important.\"", "\"Can you tell me a bit about your protocol surrounding a situation like this? I would follow your company protocol to a tee in situations such as this. Has this ever happened at Company ABC?\""]}, {"topic": "Amusement+Parks", "question": "At Company ABC you will be working around children and other vulnerable persons. We conduct a full criminal background check on all employees. Are you willing to comply?", "answers": ["Company ABC is very responsible when it comes to the safety of their visitors and employees. You should have no problem complying with a background check - even if you have a mark on your criminal record. Be honest and immediately disclose anything you feel the interviewer should know.\n\r\nIf you have a clean criminal background: \"I am happy to comply with any form of background check that you require. My record is squeaky clean!\"", "\"I am happy to comply with any form of background check that you require. My record is squeaky clean!\"", "If you do not have a clean criminal background: \"I am happy to comply with any form of background check that you require. I will disclose to you that I have a DUI charge from a couple of years ago. I have no restrictions and have gained my drivers' licence back.\""]}, {"topic": "Amusement+Parks", "question": "At Company ABC we have a mandatory uniform to create unity among our staff. Are you comfortable wearing a uniform?", "answers": ["There are many up-sides to wearing a uniform to work! For one, you don't have to decide what to wear everyday. Assure the interviewer that you are aware of the uniform standards with Company ABC. If you have not seen the uniforms, you can absolutely request a sneak peak before agreeing.", "\"I have worked in positions where uniforms are required and I fully understand why some organizations prefer their employees wear them. Could you show me what the uniforms look like?\"", "\"Uniforms are very important in this industry so, yes, I am comfortable with this policy. I would love to see the uniforms before I fully commit, of course.\""]}, {"topic": "Amusement+Parks", "question": "What do you think might be the greatest challenges of working at an amusement park? How will you overcome these?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to know that you have a realistic understanding of the position requirements. Keep your answer simple. It is absolutely okay to ask for clarification on the role if you do not fully understand what challenges are in store for you.", "\"I think the greatest challenges in this role will be to learn the proper operation of the rides and other equipment. I will be sure to pay keen attention during training and ask questions along the way.\"", "\"I believe the greatest challenge in this role will be the physical aspect of the position as I will be required to stand and walk around most of the day. I will get used to the additional activity after just a couple of days, I'm sure.\""]}, {"topic": "Amusement+Parks", "question": "At Company ABC we stress the importance of teamwork, in all that we do. Are you a team player?", "answers": ["Yes!  No matter where you work you need to be a team player to help a company achieve its goals, so be prepared to tell the interviewer, \"Yes, I am a team player!\"  \n\r\nExpand on this by sharing your philosophy on the importance of teamwork and being a part of a team.", "\"I am a team player. I recognize that there may be days where I need to perform duties outside of my usual job description to help out, or I may need to spend time mentoring and coaching new employees to ensure they are fitting into the team.\""]}, {"topic": "Amusement+Parks", "question": "Why were you fired or let go from your last job?", "answers": ["Being terminated does not have to be an embarrassing or shameful situation. If you were terminated, be open and honest with the interviewer regarding your dismissal. Be sure to let the interviewer know that you can provide positive references despite a previous termination.", "\"I was terminated from my last position due to my inability to relocate to the new location that my company was opening. It was unfortunate but I am confident that I will find the right fit again shortly. Despite my termination, I am able to provide you with strong work references.\"", "\"My position was seasonal and I knew that the role would come to an end after the summer months. I am happy to provide you with strong references, regardless.\""]}, {"topic": "Amusement+Parks", "question": "Tell me about a time that you naturally took on a leadership role without being asked. Did you enjoy being a leader? Were you happy with the outcome?", "answers": ["Being a leader gives us a different perspective and allows others to grow. Explain that you enjoy helping others grow, and you are the type of leader that hopes to inspire others.", "\"In my current position, we break our team every day into smaller groups of 10, with one leader. Yesterday, I quickly realized that I was the most seasoned of the group and so it was natural for me to be the leader since I had the majority of the answers. I really enjoyed that aspect of the work and was complimented by my supervisor on the end result. Everyone worked well together and knew the goals of the team.\"", "\"I naturally take on a leadership role every day, with our new and junior staff. I like to train others and show them the best practices to make their work life a bit easier.\""]}, {"topic": "Amusement+Parks", "question": "Do you feel that you are currently paid what you are worth?", "answers": ["Many employees will look for new work if they feel that they are underpaid and underappreciated. Talk to the interviewer about your current compensation and whether or not you feel it is fair. \n\r\nIf you feel you are currently paid what you are worth: \"I feel that my current employer pays me fairly; however, I would like to see an increase in pay with an increase in responsibilities.\"", "\"I feel that my current employer pays me fairly; however, I would like to see an increase in pay with an increase in responsibilities.\"", "If you do not feel you are currently paid what you are worth: \"I know that I am underpaid compared to my industry colleagues. My company is small and they do what they can but this is part of why I am seeking a new position.\""]}, {"topic": "Amusement+Parks", "question": "Have you ever been advised by a fellow employee or supervisor to lie about a situation?", "answers": ["Ethical dilemmas in the workplace will come up from time to time. Assure the interviewer that you are able to handle these types of dilemmas with professionalism and poise.", "\"I have never been told to lie to a fellow employee or supervisor on the job. If I were to be asked to lie I absolutely would not do that. I am not the type of personality to be pushed around on the job. I will always be myself and keep my integrity first.\"", "\"I have worked with colleagues who were dishonest and I really won't entertain the idea. I don't think that lying in the workplace is an option.\""]}, {"topic": "Amusement+Parks", "question": "How would your co-workers describe your attention to detail?", "answers": ["It is always best to support your reply with a real life example. Talk to the interviewer about your level of attentiveness when it comes to details on the job.", "\"My co-workers would describe my attention to detail as very strong. I can very easily point out spelling discrepancies in communication and will notice the small things. I think big-picture as well but have always had a knack for the small details.\"", "\"Attention to detail is important, especially in this industry where safety is of utmost importance. I believe that my coworkers would definitely describe me as having strong attention to detail.\""]}, {"topic": "Amusement+Parks", "question": "Would you consider yourself a creative person?", "answers": ["Talk to the interviewer about any creative interest that you have and how you have implemented that creative desire in the workplace.", "\"I do consider myself to be a creative individual. One example of this would be the telephone sales scripts that I crafted for our inside sales team. They were lively and effective, and sales increased by 23% in the first 90 days of implementation.\"", "\"I do consider myself a creative person and it will help me in this role with Company ABC because I will be spending a lot of time around kids and families where you need the ability to have creative fun!\""]}, {"topic": "Amusement+Parks", "question": "Rate your communication skills from 1-10 with proper examples backing your given rating.", "answers": ["On a scale of 1-10, how skilled are you in communication? Why did you choose that particular rating for yourself?", "\"I rate my communication skills as a 9/10 as I will, on occasion, have times when I am not as clear as I would like to be. My supervisor and co-workers will attest to my clear and concise communication skills. Because I am an open leader, my team will let me know if I need to clarify anything.\"", "\"Communication is very important in the amusement park industry. I would rate my communication skills as a 7 out of 10 because there is always room for improvement. Because I am an open leader, my team will let me know if I need to clarify anything. Communication needs to run smoothly, both ways.\""]}, {"topic": "Amusement+Parks", "question": "What accomplishment do you believe was the most difficult for you to achieve?", "answers": ["Being able to face a challenge or difficult situation, and still gain some type of accomplishment in the end, is very satisfying. Talk to the interviewer about a time when you were able to come out on top despite being faced with an obstacle.", "\"In my career,so far, I feel that the most difficult accomplishment for me to achieve were the 3 back-to-back promotions in my current company. Because promotions are granted based on results, I had to put in a lot of overtime hours, and hustle, to get there.\"", "\"At this point in my life the most challenging accomplishment was when I graduated with my degree while working full time. It took a lot of dedication and I am very proud of myself for the accomplishment.\""]}, {"topic": "Amusement+Parks", "question": "What is your greatest weakness?", "answers": ["Pick a weakness that is not a core skill for this position. You can be candid in your answer; recognizing that you really aren't great at something and acknowledging your need to improve.  Be sure to have an action plan in place for improving on this weakness. \n\r\nPerhaps you are watching TED talks to gain skills in a particular area, reading the latest-and-greatest book on the subject, or maybe you are taking a seminar at a nearby community center. We are all human with our own weaknesses, so don't be afraid to share yours!", "\"I believe I could improve on some technical skills including Excel and PowerPoint. Currently I am at a beginner to intermediate level; however, I would be more comfortable at an advanced level. I have enrolled myself in an evening/weekend workshop for the next six weeks. We will see how stellar my skills are after that course!\""]}, {"topic": "Casinos", "question": "What questions do you have for me?", "answers": ["It's always a great idea to have questions ready for the interviewer. Review the company website and other online resources to ensure the queries you have are not mundane, or redundant. The last thing an interviewer wants to hear is a list of items you could have found the answers for from merely watching a video on their company site! \n\nHere are some sample questions: \n\n- When would you like to have this position filled? \n- How long has this role been vacant? \n- Is this a replacement search or a newly created role? \n- What is your favorite part about working here? \n- What is the company's primary goal for this position in the next 12 months? \n- Is there anything from my background and experience that I can clarify for you? \n- What do you see as the most significant change in this industry over the past three years? \n- Is there any reason why you would not hire me?", "\"I would like to ask if there is anything in my background on which you need clarification? Also, after discussing everything today, is there any particular reason why I would not be the best fit for this casino manager role?\"", "\"I appreciate you opening the floor for questions. I am wondering what your timeline is for a decision on this opening? Also, what was the biggest struggle the last blackjack dealer encountered in this role?\""]}, {"topic": "Casinos", "question": "What would you do if a co-worker asked you to help them steal?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know how you would react if put in an awkward, or potentially harmful situation like being asked by a co-worker to steal with them. Theft can occur in many ways in the workplace and is not necessarily reserved to blatantly taking a product. Ensure that you are aware of the different ways a co-worker may try to pass stealing off as 'no big deal.'\n\n- Timecard fabrication, also known as 'buddy punching' where you punch in for a coworker who is not present\n- 'Borrowing' money from the cash register \n- Falsifying vendor or expense accounts \n- Taking items from the lost and found \n- Stealing data or documents containing trade secrets \n- Taking expensive office supplies like ink, or adding personal items to supply orders \n- Billing hours to clients that they did not work \n\nOf course, you already know how to answer this question! Express that you would never engage in this type of behavior and discuss how you would go about reporting this type of situation. If this has happened to you in the past, you can talk about the case.", "\"I once had a coworker ask me to punch in for her when she was late. She didn't want to lose hours on her time sheet! I simply laughed and told her that she needed to wake up a bit earlier if she wanted to be at work on time. She apologized later for asking me to do something unethical. It didn't happen again.\"", "\"Stealing is wrong, no matter which way you slice it. I have zero tolerance for unethical behavior and would report the situation immediately.\""]}, {"topic": "Casinos", "question": "How would you determine complimentary hotel rooms, meals, or other discounts to regular players, or those with large betting totals?", "answers": ["Many casinos, especially casino resorts, will have budgets and allowances for comping rooms, food, and other goods for players who spend a lot of money. An example of this may be someone who is considered a 'high roller' at the MGM Grand. The more they gamble, the more they are offered in the sense of free hotel stays or free upgrades to luxury suites. Talk to the interviewer about your understanding of how casinos make these decisions.", "\"I understand that comps are usually based on what the pit boss sees as loyal play and an appropriate award. In the casino where I currently work, we reward long-term loyalty. The more often a customer comes to our casino, the more points they earn towards a suite, free meals, and more.\"", "\"I am newer to the casino industry, so I am unsure of the exact calculations; however, I would guess that Company ABC rewards big betters and also frequent and loyal customers. Is this correct?\""]}, {"topic": "Casinos", "question": "Casino environments can become emotional and heated. How do you handle uncomfortable customer service situations?", "answers": ["As fun as casinos can be, they can also breed highly emotional responses from patrons. Some of the highly emotional factors include alcohol consumption, bright lights and loud sounds, and the chance of losing significant amounts of money. Talk to the interviewer about your ability to overcome difficult or uncomfortable situations that may arise from an unhappy customer.", "\"If faced with a very uncomfortable customer service situation, I would escalate the situation to my manager, who was perhaps better with customer dispute resolution. I understand that you cannot make everyone happy at all times, but I will certainly try my best. Do you offer customer dispute resolution training at Company ABC?\"", "\"I am passionate when it comes to delivering happy and harmonious customer service. A healthy and positive collaboration is an essential part of running a great, and safe, casino. If, no matter how hard I try, I am unable to make a client happy I will refer them to another floor manager with a different personality or sales style.\""]}, {"topic": "Casinos", "question": "How do you think our casino can best compete with online gambling services?", "answers": ["Since the start of online gambling, brick and mortar casinos have seen a significant shift in their business, and have had to adjust. The interviewer would like to know if you are aware of the effect the internet and online gambling would have on the casino business, and if you have any insight into how Company ABC can remain competitive. \n\nSome ways that casinos could compete with online gambling services include: \n\n- Offering food and beverage specials\n- Focusing their advertising pitch on the benefits of gambling in a real casino\n- Creating a buzz around the unbeatable casino atmosphere that you cannot get from home \n- Focus on the fact that you can win more often, and bigger bets, at a land-based casino", "\"I think that Company ABC has an incredible menu and cocktail bar so, I would focus on enticing people with your delicious menu. Would you rather be at home, gambling online all along with a frozen dinner, or in the buzz of this beautiful casino with amazing food and drink options? That's how I would spin things to compete.\"", "\"Many popular games are not available online so, to compete with these online gambling services, I would focus my marketing efforts on those games that are only available in land-based casinos.\""]}, {"topic": "Casinos", "question": "Competition for this role is tight. Why should we hire you?", "answers": ["Interviewers want to hear about that one unique skill that sets you apart from the other candidates applying for this job. Think of your answer as your 'elevator pitch' or your qualifying statement. If you can't think of ways that you are unique, ask a few friends or family members what they feel sets you apart from other people. Their observations may help you understand how you are perceived.\n\nPerhaps you already know what sets you apart! This skill could include any educational accolades, exceptional achievements, additional industry related training, a second language, or how involved you are in the community. Don't be afraid to brag about yourself a bit. In an interview, you are your most influential advocate.", "\"I have over a dozen years of experience in management at one of your largest competitors. I have a proven track record of successes there and will bring that knowledge with me. I also offer creative solutions on how to position your casino against the competition, and ideas that will help elevate your establishment to the next level. Having been a part of the industry for nearly half of my life, I have seen a ton of change and have adapted to every change or innovation with ease and excitement, and I look forward to doing that for Company ABC as well.\"", "\"You mentioned earlier in the interview process that you were struggling with maintaining staff and retaining them. I have an incredible onboarding strategy that took my current company from a 35% turnover rate to just 5% in twelve months. I will turn this pain point around for you.\""]}, {"topic": "Casinos", "question": "How did you prepare for this interview?", "answers": ["The interviewer is putting you on the spot just slightly! They want to hear the steps that you took to prepare for your interview today. The wrong answer is that you are winging it! Even if you did not have a lot of time to prep for the meeting, or it was a last-minute booking, chances are you still took the time to search the company online or read through the job description. You can be brief and quickly touch on the ways that you prepared for the meeting.", "\"I prepared for this interview by researching the history of your casino, and the job description provided to me. I am confident in my candidacy for this role and look forward to showing you my skill set.\"", "\"I am well versed in what Company ABC offers and have spoken with a couple of my friends who have worked for your organization in the past. Since booking this interview yesterday, I have been researching online, both your company history, your reviews, and the requirements of this role.\""]}, {"topic": "Casinos", "question": "What are the signs of gambling addiction, and how can we promote healthy gambling habits?", "answers": ["According to the North American Foundation for Gambling Addiction, approximately 2.6% of the U.S. population has some type of gambling issue. That adds up to nearly 10 million people in the United States who struggle with a gambling habit. This issue adds up to approximately 6 billion dollars each year, which impacts the U.S. economy and citizens. \n\nCasinos often collaborate on public service announcements and other private efforts related to gambling addiction and the social issues that may come along with problem gambling. If properly used, casinos have a unique position to promote a positive gambling mindset. \n\nSome of the signs of gambling addiction include: \n\n- Chasing a loss, or claiming they will only stop once they win\n- Increasing bet amounts, whether they are successful or not \n- Increased or dramatic agitation at a loss\n\nShare with the interviewer how you think a casino could have a healthy partnership with gambling and promote normal gameplay and habits.", "\"Ethical gambling is an essential topic in the casino industry. The signs of gambling can be tricky when you don't spend every day with someone; however, we can be on the lookout for regulars, or people who are more boisterous at the table than others. One way that I believe Company ABC can promote healthy gameplay is to have hotline numbers readily available in open sight for players. You may not be able to save someone from a gambling addiction, but we can play our part in making resources readily available to our patrons.\"", "\"One of the biggest signs of gambling addiction that I look for is high levels of agitation and heavily emotional responses when the table does not turn in their favor. When this happens, the casino I currently work for may ask a player to step away for a breather. Our staff all have access to hotline cards that they can pass along if needed, or leave in a visible location for our guests to easily access.\""]}, {"topic": "Casinos", "question": "Have you ever been advised by a fellow employee or supervisor to lie about a situation? How did you handle this ethical dilemma?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know how you would handle an ethical dilemma. Ethical dilemmas in the workplace will come up from time to time. Assure the interviewer that you can control these types of difficulties with professionalism and poise.", "\"I have never been told to lie to a fellow employee or supervisor on the job. If I were to be asked to lie, I absolutely would not do that. I am not the type of personality to be pushed around on the job. I will always be myself and keep my integrity first.\"", "\"Yes, I have been asked to lie on the job before. In a previous role, our chip count was off. My co-worker wanted to go home, and he suggested that I lie about our count. I refused to lie, and we stayed late. I would always choose honesty over lying, any day.\""]}, {"topic": "Casinos", "question": "Who are our biggest competitors, and what does Company ABC do better?", "answers": ["It is critical that you research Company ABC and their most vigorous competitors, before your interview. What do they do best, and who is trying to do it better? Speak openly with the interviewer about your ability to work competitively and how you plan to contribute to their continued success.", "\"I understand that Casino ABC is within proximity to you. I have been there before, and the most notable differences include the fact that Company ABC has a much better dining experience, with three full restaurants and two bars available to your patrons. Ample choice is important, and I believe it makes a significant impact on people when they are deciding where to go, and spend their money.\"", "\"I worked for one of your larger competitors, Casino ABC, and am somewhat familiar with the others including Casino XYZ. Company ABC stands out on many accounts, including your excellent online reviews, your drive for exceptional customer services, and the quality of dealers that you hire. These factors make all the difference and are a significant reason why I have applied to work at Company ABC over any of your competitors.\""]}, {"topic": "Casinos", "question": "How should Company ABC portray ourselves on social media platforms like Instagram, or Facebook?", "answers": ["Depending on your region, gambling laws can differ as can how a casino is allowed to market and advertising. Generally speaking, social media allows for more flexibility when it comes to promoting the act of gambling. If you are following Company ABC on social media, mention it. Comment on what you enjoy about their social media posts. Discuss how you would promote Company ABC if you were in charge of their social accounts.", "\"I follow Company ABC on Instagram and love your feed. If I were to be in charge of your social accounts, I would even further amplify how much fun it is to spend an evening gambling at your establishment.\"", "\"Food and great cocktails often draw a crowd so, if I were to be in charge of Company ABC social media accounts, I would put an even bigger focus on your food and drink offerings. That aside, I think your company's social media accounts are awesome. I follow you on Instagram and Twitter, and often share your posts.\""]}, {"topic": "Casinos", "question": "Do you enjoy gambling?", "answers": ["There is no right or wrong reply to this question; however, the interviewer may be looking for an indication of gambling addiction. Consider replying short and sweet, explaining that you understand the draw to gambling but that you are also responsible when playing during your personal time.", "\"I think that gambling can be a fun activity, but also needs to be exercised responsibly. I will play the slots now and then but not on a regular basis.\"", "\"Gambling can be fun but to be honest, I have the most fun watching other people participate. The energy is buzzing, and when someone wins big, it can be a stimulating experience to witness.\""]}, {"topic": "Casinos", "question": "Take a few minutes to bring your resume to life for me, highlighting your experience in the hospitality industry.", "answers": ["The interviewer is looking for an overview of your background. Because this question is so open ended, it can be easy to run away with your answer and even put your foot in your mouth. Offer a less than 5 minute brief of your related education or training, and then touch on the last 5-10 years of your career, depending on how far along you are in your professional career. You can discuss your volunteer experience and don't forget to talk about any extraordinary skills you may have.", "\"I would be happy to give you a brief overview of my background! After graduating with my Diploma in Hospitality, I went to work for my family's retail business as a floor manager. After a year, I realized that although working for the family may sound nice, it's best to keep business and family separate. I was not earning what I wanted to earn, and it's hard to ask family for a raise. So, I am now looking for a management role within a larger organization where I can grow, and earn my way into promotions while developing myself professionally.\"", "\"My hospitality career goes back a few years. My first dive into a service role was overseeing a team of floor sales representatives, five in total. This year I was promoted and moved to a district management role, which is where I am today. Here, I manage a team of twelve plus three temporary staff who often rotate. Before my hospitality management career began, I was working in a retail environment and attending post-secondary at the same time. My degree is in Business, with a focus on organizational management.\""]}, {"topic": "Casinos", "question": "What do you know about casino security and surveillance?", "answers": ["Casinos must have very tight security and surveillance across every inch of the gambling areas. Discuss with the interviewer if you have any security training. If you do not have experience in casino security, express that you are looking forward to taking the training available with Company ABC.\n\nCasinos will take security measures that include: \n\n- Employee background checks \n- Video surveillance \n- Physically present security officers \n- Digital tracking of chips and cash \n- Floorplan and employee coordination/placement", "\"I have taken some training in digital tracking devices for chips and cash. It's important that I fully understand the security measures present at the casino where I work so that I can know which areas we are most secure, and which areas we may be slightly vulnerable. What type of training does Company ABC offer in regards to security and surveillance?\"", "\"In my current role with Casino ABC, I received training in CCTV monitoring. It was my responsibility to ensure that all the cameras were in place before we opened our doors in the morning. Casino security is robust, and there is a lot to learn. I look forward to additional training from Company ABC.\""]}, {"topic": "Casinos", "question": "Are you able to work, standing up, for long periods of time?", "answers": ["Your ability to perform the everyday physical tasks associated with this role will significantly determine if you are the successful candidate. With that said, it is critical that you are truthful with the interviewer regarding your physical capabilities. Depending on your region, you may not be required to disclose medical issues, but you should be honest about roadblocks you may face. An employer that sees a great fit in you may make modifications to accommodate.", "\"I can stand for extended periods of time; however, I have had knee surgery from an athletic injury years ago. It can become inflamed if I am not wearing the correct footwear or if the floor is particularly hard.\"", "\"I do not have any physical limitations and can complete all tasks outlined in the job description.\""]}, {"topic": "Casinos", "question": "Are you willing to take a series of background checks?", "answers": ["As you know, casinos handle a great deal of money on a daily basis. Security and safety are one of the top concerns for any casino. Background checks that Company ABC may require of you could include: \n\n- Credit checks\n- Social security trace\n- Employment verification checks\n- Education verification \n- Reference checks\n- Drug screening\n- Criminal record checks\n\nShare with the interviewer that you will comply with any background check they require.", "\"I understand that the casino industry requires a great deal of compliance when it comes to security and safety matters. I will comply with any background check that you require.\"", "\"I am willing to complete any background check that you require. My criminal record is clean, my credit is strong, and I do not participate in any illicit drugs.\""]}, {"topic": "Casinos", "question": "Tell me about a time when you have made an unpopular decision.", "answers": ["You cannot make everyone happy all of the time. When you work in a hospitality based role, you are faced with numerous personalities and preferences every day. Also, your team will be made up of a wide range of people. Talk to the interviewer about a time when you had to make a decision that you knew was for the better of the company, but perhaps unpopular among your staff or clients. How did you come to a decision, and how did you deal with the effects of your unpopular decision.", "\"Just this year I needed to implement split shifts among my serving staff. Our staffing costs were too high, and we had a severe drop in patrons between 2-4PM. Some of our staff threatened to quit, while others were just fine with the decision. I knew it would be unpopular; however, I stuck with my decision because I knew it would significantly help our bottom line over time. I was correct, and after just six months, we reduced staffing costs by 15%.\"", "\"This past month I decided to terminate our lead customer service agent. The decision did not come easy as he was a longstanding member of our service department. With that said, this particular person had 3x the customer complaints than any other team member, was regularly tardy, and had two no-show incidences the month before. He was beloved among the team, so the news was not welcomed. I knew it was the right decision and luckily, our team bounced back quite quickly afterward.\""]}, {"topic": "Casinos", "question": "Honesty is an essential virtue of our employees. What makes you an honest person?", "answers": ["Being an honest person means making the right decisions, even when nobody is looking. It's having integrity in your actions, words, and thoughts. Because gambling establishments need to be very careful who they hire, the interviewer needs to know, without a doubt, that you are reliable. Give an example of a time when you chose honesty above all else.", "\"In my current position, I am responsible for the cash deposit on a daily basis, as well as chip disbursements, and signing off on the counts. In the two years that I worked there, I have never encountered a discrepancy. I best show my integrity by being a consistently reliable employee.\"", "\"Honesty and integrity are two values at the center of my being. I like to think I practice this in the workplace by always doing the right thing by the company, its customers, and its people. I have three letters of reference with me, all of which attest to my honest nature.\""]}, {"topic": "Casinos", "question": "What is your casino game of choice?", "answers": ["If you are applying for a dealer role, you will likely be asked which games you prefer to deal, or where your expertise may be. You may prefer Blackjack, Craps, or Roulette. Whatever your game of choice, be sure to outline your amount of experience and level of training. You want to avoid pigeonholing yourself into just one type of game so be sure to express that you are interested in learning a variety of dealer games and that you look forward to training with Company ABC.", "\"I have been a Blackjack dealer for four years, and have dealt Roulette for two years. With that said, I am open to learning any game as I am a quick study and interested in expanding my repertoire.\"", "\"I do not come with a preference when it comes to the games I could deal here at Company ABC. The bulk of my training and experience is in Craps; however, I most look forward to learning a variety of games and becoming a very well rounded dealer.\""]}, {"topic": "Casinos", "question": "Are you familiar with our dress code at Company ABC? How do you feel about wearing a uniform?", "answers": ["Uniforms are very important in the casino and hospitality industry as they show unification amount a team, and help customers to identify better who can help them when they have a question or other need. If you have seen the uniforms at Company ABC, express that you are aware of the dress code and are willing to comply. If you have not seen the uniforms at Company ABC then you should ask to see them before accepting. Do be sure to let the interviewer know that you understand the importance of unification in the workplace.", "\"I have seen the uniforms at Company ABC and am happy to comply. They are classic options, and I believe they stand out enough that a patron could quickly identify an employee when they have a need.\"", "\"I understand the importance of a well-laid out dress code in the hospitality industry. If you don't mind, could you please show me what the uniform expectations may be?\""]}, {"topic": "Casinos", "question": "What does customer service mean to you?", "answers": ["Excellent customer service goes beyond doing precisely as your expected, and it's more than having a smile on your face when the customer is looking. Excellent customer service means that you actively seek out the opportunity to deliver more than the standard. It means thoroughly listening to your customers when they tell you what they need. Also, it equals offering support when your customer may be a little bit in over their head. Be sure to echo the jargon used on Company ABC social media accounts and website when it comes to keywords related to their service mantra. Keep your answer brief but ensure that it packs a punch.", "\"For me, customer service means actively seeking out opportunities to give the customer a better experience than they expect, or perhaps had the last time.\"", "\"Ensuring that my customers are satisfied with their experience every time. That is what good customer service means to me. This level of service may mean bending the rules a touch to deliver what they need. For instance, I will extend the return policy by a reasonable amount if it means a happy customer who will give a solid review.\""]}, {"topic": "Casinos", "question": "Casino rules can be stringent. How would you react if a patron was breaking a rule?", "answers": ["The phrase, 'rules are meant to be broken,' does not apply when in a casino environment. Tight security, avid video surveillance, and a rulebook as thick as a New York phone book equal little room for rule breaking. The interviewer would like to know that if a patron were breaking a rule, you would not be a silent bystander. Ask about the policies at Company ABC, and assure the interviewer that you would take the measures asked of you when it comes to reporting infractions.", "\"If a patron were breaking a rule, I would report the situation to security and ensure that the situation was dealt with swiftly. I will be sure to learn the rules and regulations at Company ABC quickly. You can rest assured that I will comply with all rules.\"", "\"I have been trained to avoid making a scene at all times so, if I were to see a patron breaking a rule, I would either report it to security or quietly pull the patron aside. My reaction would also be based strongly on the rules and regulations outlined by Company ABC, which I look forward to learning.\""]}, {"topic": "Casinos", "question": "How do you build rapport with your clients?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know your methods when it comes to getting to know your customers and building trust with them. When you have a great relationship with the stakeholders, you will be more successful in your work and more likely to stay longer-term. \n\nSome ways that you can build rapport with your clients include: \n\n- Do what you say that you will\n- Ask them questions about themselves\n- Use the same jargon and industry terms they use \n- Set clear expectations, on both sides, from the start\n- Remember their names \n- Show your extensive knowledge base \n- Always be presentable in looks and actions", "\"To build client rapport, I am sure always to do what I say. In the hospitality industry, its essential that my patrons feel 100% confident that I will deliver over and above their expectations, ensuring they want to return.\"", "\"The number one rule of building a solid rapport with your regular casino client base is to remember! Remember their names, their kids' names, important dates, where they last went on vacation, and their favorite golf spot. When you remember details, it shows that you care. This approach has never failed me.\""]}, {"topic": "Casinos", "question": "The environment at Company ABC is incredibly diverse. Discuss how you embrace diversity.", "answers": ["Diversity and inclusion are hot topics, and critical ones, across all employers and industries. Some ways that you can embrace diversity include: \n\n- Building community groups within your workplace, such as an LGBTQ Allies Club or a Women in Leadership group\n- Encourage diversity and inclusion training \n- Offer employee development courses geared towards minority groups \n- Celebrate all holidays and events such as pride week, and Hannukah \n- Support those of different faiths, for instance - allowing regular prayer times for your Muslim employees \n\nShare with the interviewer how you have helped support, or pave the way, for diversity in the workplace.", "\"In my current position, I started a Women in Leadership club, open to women and those who support women, when it comes to development and career growth opportunities. We meet once per week during our lunch break and discuss how we can make a difference and how we can support each other.\"", "\"As a visible minority myself, I make a conscious effort to include others in learning about my unique culture. Also, I am broad-minded with it comes to the needs and differences of others. Diversity to me is not simply a matter of culture but also of gender identity, age, and more. I am conscious of being sensitive to others in every action that I take in the workplace.\""]}, {"topic": "Casinos", "question": "What would you do if you saw a dealer breaking the rules?", "answers": ["There are many rules within the casino environment, and they are often based on honesty. Co-worker relationships need to be filled with trust and also boundaries. Tell the interviewer that you will be sure to follow their procedures when it comes to reporting co-worker dishonesty or incidences that you feel are inappropriate.", "\"If I saw a dealer breaking the rules, I would immediately report the incident, according to Company ABC regulations. If I were the manager, I would discreetly pull the dealer off of the floor.\"", "\"It is imperative to me that I trust my co-workers, and that I am a trustworthy employee in return. If I were to witness an incident that was inappropriate, dishonest, and against the rules, I would report the incident immediately.\""]}, {"topic": "Casinos", "question": "Tell me something about yourself that I wouldn't know from reading your resume.", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to get to know you apart from your resume. You are indeed not obligated to discuss personal matters such as your kids, or relationship status, for instance. Stick with a couple of fun facts to show the interviewer that you are a real person, too. Your answer should be unique so that you are a memorable candidate!  \n\nFocus on unique non-work related skills or hobbies. For instance, you might share that you enjoy beat-boxing or making origami swans. Be prepared for the interviewer to stop you and ask you to perform your skill on the spot when it's possible! (This will make you unforgettable!)", "\"I am an avid marathon runner and have traveled to 10 countries in the last eight years to compete in a variety of races. I am a competitive individual and enjoy keeping fit.\"", "\"I am a certified yoga instructor, and I spent three months after college traveling and doing yoga. I spent six weeks in Asia and another six weeks in Latin America, and it was a fantastic experience that helped me to grow as both a yogi and a professional.\""]}, {"topic": "Casinos", "question": "Looking at your resume, you've had a number of job changes. What would make me think that you will stay with Company ABC?", "answers": ["Most hiring managers will consider more than two jobs in the past five years to be frequent movement. Take some time to explain your career progression to the interviewer. Be sure to avoid speaking poorly of any of your previous employers. This question is not the time to ramble on about how your former company did you wrong. Short and sweet is most appropriate here.", "\"I have had a couple of unexpected moves in the last few years. You will see that my tenure, before the latest two positions, was solid. Company ABC went bankrupt shortly after I joined. Most recently, with Company XYZ, they decided to move their headquarters to Texas, and I am not able to relocate my family.\"", "\"The last two positions on my resume were internships and not long-term positions. The role before that was to get me through school. I am now looking for a full-time role related to my new Hospitality degree.\""]}, {"topic": "Casinos", "question": "When have you made a mistake delegating tasks to your team members?", "answers": ["Being able to delegate to your team correctly is an essential part of successful management. Talk to the interviewer about a time that you have appointed in error. Be sure to discuss how you repaired the mistake.", "\"Earlier in my career I would delegate tasks at random, thinking that everyone had the skills to complete any company-related task. I found that these employees would procrastinate on these tasks if they seemed overwhelming or if they did not understand them. After a bit of time, and some learning, I began to delegate based on personality type and skill-set. This method proved to be much more effective, and I follow this delegation style to this day.\"", "\"In the past, I have delegated some of my managerial duties, when I am not working, to the most tenured employee as would seem natural. These employees have the most experience, so they should be the best equipped to help run the department if I am on vacation. However, it soon became clear that they were in sales for all of these years for a reason; it's what they are good at and what they like to do. They were neither cut out for nor interested in, the administrative side of management. Because of this, I'd come back to some bizarre schedules or poorly planned floor plans and would have to spend twice as much time undoing their work. I soon learned that it is not the length of employment that makes the best acting manager, but rather the person and personality.\""]}, {"topic": "Casinos", "question": "How do you feel about working evenings and weekends?", "answers": ["Many casinos are open late, or even 24 hours a day. The interviewer wants to see that you are willing to put in the work that it takes to be a team player. When you first begin with Company ABC you may receive the less desirable shifts. Whatever efforts are required, show the interviewer your willingness to make it happen.", "\"I am fully prepared to work any hours provided to me. I am excited to be joining Company ABC and will happily work evenings, weekends, and even holidays.\"", "\"Evenings and weekends are fine with me. I will take as many hours as you will offer me. I am a hard worker and understand the importance of overdelivering at work.\""]}, {"topic": "Casinos", "question": "Do you have confidence in your communication skills? What is your communication style?", "answers": ["Casino environments require incredible levels of communication. They have complicated operations with many moving parts, a lot of staff, and a plethora of security needs. \n\nStrong communication makes all the difference when it comes to workplace success. Never underestimate the importance of being able to express yourself adequately. Efficiently communicating through body language, and written or oral communication can make a huge difference in the relationships with your coworkers, your boss, and your patrons.  \n\nAssure the interviewer that you are confident in your communication abilities. You can refer to any communications course or workshop that you have taken. Or, you can discuss a time when a manager told you that you had excellent communication skills! Reaffirm your answer by describing your communication style in a few words. \n\nSome great options are: \n\n- Professional\n- Diplomatic\n- Attentive\n- Logical\n- Objective\n- Sincere\n- Personable\n- Perceptive\n- Trustworthy", "\"I have always been a strong communicator; however, after I took a weekend long communications workshop last year, I can confidently say that my communication skills are above average. I would describe my communication style as attentive, energetic, and sincere.\"", "\"As a hospitality manager, if I am not effectively communicating, a lot can go wrong. I like to address complicated topics by breaking them down into simple to understand terms and turning large roadblocks into smaller goals to prevent anyone on the team from feeling overwhelmed.\""]}, {"topic": "Cruises", "question": "How do you handle yourself in large crowds of people?", "answers": ["Cruise ships can hold thousands of passengers, with the worlds' largest holding over 6,000 people at a time. With that many people under one roof, the interviewer needs to know that you can handle the capacity of people without becoming overwhelmed or moody. Talk to the interviewer about a time when you have been exposed to large crowds. Assure the interviewer that you can handle the pressure and challenges that come along with this workplace environment.", "\"I have worked many Black Friday retail rushes and popular concerts to know that I am okay in a large crowd of people. Although I do appreciate my personal space and alone time now and then, I do find it energizing to be around large amounts of people.\"", "\"Large crowds of people are no problem for me. I have worked on cruise ships with capacity from 3,000-5,000 people with no issues. I am a true extrovert, so I do find it energizing to be around many people at one time.\""]}, {"topic": "Cruises", "question": "How would you go above and beyond to make a guests' vacation their best trip ever?", "answers": ["It is crucial that you answer this customer service based question with enthusiasm and clarity. Try to dig deeper than the usual 'service with a smile' response. Give specific examples on how you would make a guest of Company ABC feel like they just took the vacation of their dreams.", "\"I know how I would like to be treated on my 'home away from home' and would start by remembering guests names, and their preferences. I would greet them with a smile every time, and ask them about their day. Asking how I can better serve them is also a great way to ensure that they are receiving more than expected during their cruise vacation.\"", "\"Customer service is one of my key strengths. I will commit to delivering the best service ever, ensuring a memorable trip, by providing more than just their basic needs. Asking a guest how their excursion was, helping them with a difficult gift shop jewelry purchase, or even memorizing the names of their children, are all excellent ways to go above and beyond. I look forward to attending the superior customer service training from Company ABC as well.\""]}, {"topic": "Cruises", "question": "How would you handle a rude customer?", "answers": ["When you work on a cruise ship, everything you do is customer service based. You will often come across rude individuals, which is inevitable, in the customer service game, unfortunately. The interviewer wants to know that you can handle such a situation with professionalism. Give an example of a time that you had to deal with a challenging customer situation. Be sure to include the positive outcome. \n\nSome ways that you can efficiently handle a rude customer:\n\n- Remain kind, polite, and pleasant\n- Actively listen to their grievances \n- Apologize for the situation \n- Maintain a neutral tone of voice\n- Avoid taking anything they say, personally", "\"When I was working as a bartender, I handled many rude customers who were also intoxicated, which always adds a challenging twist! I made sure to let anything rude they said to slide off my back like it was nothing. I just kept smiling, and doing my job! I still handle rude customers this way. Smile, and move on, disallowing any hurt feelings.\"", "\"I have thick skin when it comes to customers. This resilience to rude allows me to remain calm kind, and polite while they unload their feelings. Also, it's amazing what a warm smile will solve when a customer is rude to your face. Try it - it's nearly impossible to be mean to someone who is smiling at you!\""]}, {"topic": "Cruises", "question": "How do you feel about the Company ABC dress code and code of conduct?", "answers": ["Cruise lines have dress codes for safety, customer service, and professional reasons. When there are thousands of people vacationing on a ship, the crew need to be easy to locate, should a guest need anything. Before you reply to this question, you should have a firm idea of what the dress code looks like, and the expectations that will be placed on you when it comes to the code of conduct. If you are unsure, it is best to ask upfront for a copy of the dress code, and code of conduct. Of course, Company ABC will do their best to place only realistic and healthy expectations on you.", "\"I have looked through your employee code of conduct and have seen your dress code online. I am happy to comply with both and find them very reasonable. Will I be provided with a uniform, or do I need to purchase them through your organization?\"", "\"I am sure that the code of conduct and employee dress code are very reasonable. Do you have a copy of each that I could review?\""]}, {"topic": "Cruises", "question": "Tell me about your training in customer service, hospitality, or another related field.", "answers": ["Working on a cruise line means that you will be serving others, at all times of the day. A cruise ship job does not stop at 5 PM, and you may be required to deliver 'service with a smile' at all hours of the day. The interviewer would like assurance that you have training in the world of hospitality and customer service. Discuss any on-the-job training you have received or any coursework you have committed to, related to customer service.", "\"I have spent the past eight years in a hospitality environment, first with boutique hotels, and then in resort hotels. My customer service training has included topics such as balancing professionalism with personality, effective communication, and dispute resolution.\"", "\"I am newer to my career but have taken a course in dispute resolution and strategic problem solving while attending university. My new business administration degree also offers a great deal of knowledge when it comes to savvy decision making and clear communication.  I am confident in the knowledge that I possess and look forward to furthering my training with Company ABC.\""]}, {"topic": "Cruises", "question": "Do you like being around people?", "answers": ["Working on a cruise line means working around people day in, and day out for the course of your shift. This schedule could mean months without going a day by yourself. Assure the interviewer that you can handle such a social based role. Share the types of people or situations that you enjoy. It's essential to maintain a positive angle when addressing this question.", "\"I would consider myself an extrovert, and I do love working closely with a team and my customers. I enjoy a wide range of personalities. The more I can interact with people in a day, the better. I like to be in the middle of the action!\"", "\"I am a people person, as I would hope are most people seeking a career on a cruise ship. I enjoy having a great conversation with someone and getting to know them. The art of conversation is how I build wonderful rapport levels with my clients and co-workers alike.\""]}, {"topic": "Cruises", "question": "Name the top 3 qualities you would look for when hiring cruise line staff.", "answers": ["If you look through a variety of job postings from Company ABC you will see there are common characteristics they seek when hiring new employees. \n\nThese characteristics include: \n\n- Pride in your customer service\n- Positive personality\n- Willingness to adapt\n- Regard for safety \n- Respectful and trustworthy \n\nShow the interviewer that you are aware of what it takes to be a successful employee at Company ABC. If you were in charge, who would you hire and why?", "\"If I were hiring cruise line staff, I would look for people who could adapt to changing situations, who were quick problem solvers, and who carried a positive attitude everywhere you go. I believe that I fit the bill in all three of these areas. My references could vouch for this as well.\"", "\"Hiring cruise line staff is likely a difficult task since you want to find people who excel in customer service, who can handle the unique lifestyle and at the same time, stay as long-term as possible. I imagine the industry attracts more transient individuals that you would prefer. If I were hiring, I would look for someone dedicated to the hospitality industry, has a genuine interest in travel, and who wanted to work in a close-knit team environment. I would be sure to check references as well.\""]}, {"topic": "Cruises", "question": "Working on a cruise line means long hours and trying guests. How do you handle extended periods of stress?", "answers": ["Working on a cruise ship is not all fun and games, and the interviewer would like to know that you are aware of potential stressors on the job. Just like in any customer service role, you will be under times of stress with grouchy guests, and straining physical activity. Assure the interviewer that you can handle these times with professionalism and poise. If possible, give examples of a time when you have been under pressure in the workplace.", "\"I have been under extended periods of stress before, from my time in University and earning a double degree, to working in the service industry in busy and high-pressure environments. When I am feeling extra stressors, I will take a minute to collect myself with a few deep breaths, and remind myself of the positive things I experienced that day. Taking myself back into a mentality of gratitude always helps.\"", "\"I am no stranger to extended periods of stress. I have worked internationally in the past, away from all family and friends. I have also worked in high-pressure retail sales environments. When I feel added pressure, I will ask to take a quick breather if possible. Most of the time, removing myself from the situation for just a couple of minutes will help. If that is not possible, I will run through a list in my head of all the good things that happened that day. I find that when I stop dwelling on the stressors, and more on the positives, things turn around for me.\""]}, {"topic": "Cruises", "question": "If you could set sail to any place in the world, where would you go, and why?", "answers": ["This question is one of interest, but also may be one to test your geographical knowledge. The last thing you want to reply with a city and country that do not exist, for instance! Other than that, there indeed is no right or wrong answer to this question. Choose a unique destination that will make you a stand-out candidate. If you choose Paris, for the Eiffel Tower, you may not be memorable.", "\"I love to travel and have had many great opportunities in the past few years. If I could choose any destination for my next, I would pick to stay at the Icehotel in Jukkasjarvi, Sweden. It's so interesting to me that I could stay in a hotel carved entirely out of ice. Also, the town has historic buildings to explore, such as an old church dating back to approximately 1607.\"", "\"I have a bucket list, actually, and would love to tell you about it! A couple of years ago I made a list of the most fascinating UNESCO World Heritage sites and decided that I would choose one from North America, Central America, the Caribbean, South America, Africa, Asia, and Europe. So far, I have visited Leon Cathedral in Nicaragua, and Ephesus in Turkey. Next, I am planning for the Paleolithic Caves in Spain. It's important to me that I am well traveled and exposed to what our beautiful world has to offer.\""]}, {"topic": "Cruises", "question": "Have you ever planned an international vacation?", "answers": ["Since you are applying to work for a travel-based company, you should be ready to highlight any experience you have planning vacations for yourself. Discuss where you have traveled, and be sure to mention the best of your experience. If you have planned a cruise vacation before, give some details on your trip, how you designed it, and what you loved about it.", "\"I have planned two international vacations before. One was a cruise for myself and my parents, with Company ABC actually. I used a travel agent to ensure that all of the details were perfect. We had an excellent time exploring the ship, the port towns and took in a few excursions. The other vacation I planned, I booked online by myself. It was a simpler resort vacation in Costa Rica.\"", "\"I have not been lucky enough to do any international travel. I have planned a 12-week US-wide road-trip in the past, right after I graduated from university. One of the reasons why I am so excited to work for Company ABC is for the international travel opportunities. I realize that I will not be vacationing per se; however, to even be able to see these places all over the world briefly, is enough for me.\""]}, {"topic": "Cruises", "question": "In this role, you will be traveling for three months on, and two weeks off. How will you manage this with your personal life?", "answers": ["As a cruise ship member, your schedule could be a few weeks at sea, up to a few months at a time. Before Company ABC hires you, they need to be sure that you can handle the schedule without it affecting your personal or family life. Briefly touch on the ways that you have prepared your family and friends for the potential change. Let the interviewer know that you are ready to set sail!", "\"I have already prepared my family for the fact that I may be away for a few months at a time. They are very excited for me and think this will be an unforgettable experience. I am not new to travel so being away from home will not be an issue for me, regarding homesickness, for instance.\"", "\"I have already lined up care for my dog, and a temporary housemate to help me with the cost of rent, and home maintenance while I am away. This opportunity is a great one for me and those who matter the most, fully understand how important it is that I succeed and feel supported. Everyone is doing their part to make it work.\""]}, {"topic": "Cruises", "question": "Do you have any talents or unique hobbies we should know about?", "answers": ["This question is similar to the 'tell me something I wouldn't know from reading your resume' question.  When cruise lines look to hire, they love to entertain candidates with a lot of potential in multiple areas. For instance, perhaps you are excellent with bartending, and you can assist on the entertainment side of the ship. Discuss any talents or hobbies that you may have. You can give a more relaxed response to this question.", "\"I grew up playing basketball and was the captain of my college basketball team. I learned a lot about leadership, healthy competition, and being a team player. I am open to trying new things and, should you need someone to help with the sports and activities side of your program, I could be an excellent resource.\"", "\"I have many hidden talents! I love to act, sing, and dance. If you think I could incorporate that into a bartending act, we could be onto something! Seriously though, I am interested in a multitude of topics and am happy to fill in where needed.\""]}, {"topic": "Cruises", "question": "Are you CPR and First Aid certified?", "answers": ["Keep your response brief as this is a very straightforward question. If you are CPR and First Aid certified, be sure to bring proof of your certification with you to the interview. If your certificates are expiring soon, let the interviewer know that you have plans to renew them. If you are not certified, it's best that you offer to become certified, at your own expense, before their desired hire date. Being proactive like that will say a lot about your work ethic.", "\"I am not currently CPR or First Aid certified; however, I have researched options close to me and have found a couple of courses that begin next week. I am eager to work for Company ABC and will do what it takes to be a viable candidate.\"", "\"I have valid CPR and First Aid certifications which I have brought with me today. Would you like to take a copy for my candidate file?\""]}, {"topic": "Cruises", "question": "How do you interpret the term \"ship life\", and what do you expect from our workplace culture?", "answers": ["'Ship life' is the term used by workers on cruise ships, referring to the unique workplace culture and lifestyle they lead, by working for weeks or even months at a time, on board a cruise ship. The interviewer would like to know that you have a reasonable understanding of what ship life will bring you, the good and the bad. It's vital to Company ABC that you join their organization with realistic expectations, and not thinking that the job is all fun and games because you will be traveling around the world. Discuss what you understand to be the workplace culture aboard a cruise ship.", "\"I believe the term 'ship life' is referring to the unique position crew members are in, working on a ship for long periods of time. I understand that working on a cruise ship is not all fun and games like in movies, for instance. What I expect from your workplace culture is a sense of community but also some growing pains as you get accustomed to working on a ship with potentially hundreds of nationalities and differences. I am eager for the excellent training and new experiences; however, I know that some days will be more emotionally challenging than others.\"", "\"From my understanding, 'ship life' is the way of life onboard a ship, where you work, eat, sleep, and play day in and day out. Working on a cruise ship is a unique experience, and I do know, not always fun and easy. I am prepared to put in the hard work in exchange for life-changing experiences and opportunities. I expect that your staff is well-trained, embracing of diversity, and inclusive by nature. Is this accurate to say?\""]}, {"topic": "Cruises", "question": "Have you ever been on a cruise? What was your experience?", "answers": ["Before you can fully understand what life is like working on a cruise, you should take one! The cruise experience is a vacation in a league all its own. Never-ending entertainment, delicious dining, and unique shopping. A cruise ship can indeed have it all. Share with the interviewer your experience on a cruise. What stood out to you the most? What memory do you always return to when you think about that trip? If you have never taken a cruise, be sure to do some research by reading travel blogs.", "\"I was on a Christmas family cruise a couple of years ago with Company ABC. My experience was so wonderful, that is when I vowed to come back as an employee one day. I loved the variety and that I could spend nearly every day in a new city or country, exploring the culture and trying new things. I am excited to help give this opportunity to the guests of Company ABC.\"", "\"Although I have never been on a cruise vacation, I have read about them on a variety of travel blogs and performed a great amount of research before coming here today. I look forward to learning more about the ways that Company ABC creates unforgettable experiences for their guests.\""]}, {"topic": "Cruises", "question": "Why do you want to work for Company ABC over other cruise lines?", "answers": ["It's essential that you can articulate why this role with Company ABC is superior to similar positions with their competitors. Perhaps you connect with the company mission and values, maybe they offer employee perks beyond what their competitors advertise, or they have a much better industry reputation. Whatever your reasoning may be, assure the interviewer that you bring dedication to working for Company ABC and that you are excited to be their newest representative.", "\"My interest in working for Company ABC comes from the fact that I had an incredible family vacation on your cruise line a few years ago. My experience was unforgettable, and I am excited to have the opportunity to share that with other people who trust Company ABC for their special holidays. I appreciate all of the amenities that you offer and that your customer service goes far beyond the minimal expectations.\"", "\"When I was researching cruise line jobs, the job postings from Company ABC stood above the rest. They are upbeat and welcoming, just like the experience that you offer those who vacation with you. Your workplace culture, branding, and overall vibe speak the loudest to me, over any of your competitors. I would be a proud representative of Company ABC.\""]}, {"topic": "Cruises", "question": "To work with Company ABC you will need to complete a full background check, along with a medical examination. Are you okay with this?", "answers": ["Complete background checks are a must for any cruise ship related position. The only correct answer to this question is a 'yes.' If you do have a mark on your record, or any reason why there could be a hiccup in your onboarding, now is the time to mention it.", "\"I am happy to comply with any background and medical checks required to work for Company ABC. I appreciate that you are very careful who you employ, as I realized that your staff is privy to sensitive information and situations.\"", "\"I will agree to any background checks that you require. I should disclose to you that I had knee surgery three years ago; however, I have the all-clear from my doctor to perform work functions as per normal. I can walk and stand for long periods of time, and can lift 75 pounds, repeatedly.\""]}, {"topic": "Cruises", "question": "Tell me about your experience working around children.", "answers": ["Many cruise lines offer a family-friendly environment, with kids clubs. These clubs often offer activities and care from babies all the way to teenagers. Entertainment and care could include large playrooms, special kid-friendly menus, crafts, water parks, and other programs. The interviewer needs to know that you would be comfortable working around children of all ages. Talk about your experience working with kids, including the ages you have worked with and the types of activities that you have led. If you do not have experience working around children, that is okay. Discuss that you are a kid at heart and are confident that you can make any day fun, and safe, for kids of all ages!", "\"I have worked as a babysitter since I was 12 years old. I have been a volunteer for Girl Guides a few years running as well. I have worked with kids in outdoor adventure programs, water programs, and also activities such as crafts and cooking. Most of the kids I have worked with are ages 4-9; although, I believe that I can make any day fun for all ages!\"", "\"I have not had direct work experience with children; however, I am the oldest of four siblings, and did a lot of free babysitting for my parents growing up! I am a kid at heart and enjoy making kids laugh. I can assure you that I would work very hard to make the kids club experience at Company ABC a safe and memorable one.\""]}, {"topic": "Cruises", "question": "Which area of our ship do you have the most interest in working?", "answers": ["When applying to a cruise line, you will have a plethora of options when it comes to choosing a department or area of interest. Opportunities may be available in: \n\n- Guest services\n- Food & Beverage\n- Gift Shop\n- Casino \n- Cruise programs\n- Human resources \n- Jewelry \n- Medical \n- Engine \n- Music\n- Salon\n- Surveillance and security\n\nThere are hundreds of opportunities available. Be ready to highlight for the interviewer the areas which you are most interested.", "\"I have a solid background in food and beverage, with many years of bartending as well as upscale dining service. I could fit well with any position in the F&B department.\"", "\"I have a background in security and surveillance. When I saw that you have an opening for a Surveillance Operator, I knew I had to apply. I have formal STCW training (Standards of Training, Certification, and Watchkeeping) and am passionate for the hospitality industry.\""]}, {"topic": "Cruises", "question": "How do you feel about living in shared accommodation while working on our ship?", "answers": ["Employees who work on cruise ships share very tight crew assigned living quarters. Think of your college dorm room, perhaps smaller, but on the water. These little bunks will include a couple of single beds, a desk or table, and a small bathroom for the most part. The interviewer would like to know that you can handle this type of living situation, with total strangers, for weeks at a time. Be honest in your response, and, if you have had exposure to a similar living arrangement, you can certainly bring this up.", "\"Cabin crew living arrangements sound a great deal like the arrangements I had in university! I have talked to a couple of people who have worked on cruise ships before, and they all say that it's tough for the first couple of weeks, but then you get used to it. I know that depending on the level I am on, it could be loud from the engine hum or the water. I trust that Company ABC knows how to best pair employees when it comes to roommate situations.\"", "\"I have had roommates in the past, but perhaps not in such proximity. So long as we remain respectful of each others' space, I see no problem living cozy for a few weeks. I will think of it as the tiny house trend!\""]}, {"topic": "Cruises", "question": "The crew of Company ABC greatly range in background, ethnicity, and culture. Tell me about your exposure to diversity.", "answers": ["On most cruise lines, you can see dozens, if not hundreds, of backgrounds and ethnicities represented. Cruise lines are well known for their vast diversity when it comes to hiring. Nearly any culture you can think of will be represented on the ship. Assure the interviewer that you embrace diversity and are driven to include those, no matter how different they are from you.", "\"I understand that the crew at Company ABC will represent nearly any culture I could imagine. I genuinely enjoy getting to know those who are different from me and learning from them. My time in university, I was exposed to people of all different beliefs and lifestyles. I have also traveled around the world, giving me valuable exposure to a variety of cultures and experiences.\"", "\"One of the reasons why I am so interested in working for Company ABC is the fact that you do embrace diversity so much. I want to know people different from me and expand my knowledge far beyond my own backyard. I look forward to meeting your diverse crew!\""]}, {"topic": "Cruises", "question": "What type of promotion, or long-term opportunities, would you be looking for from Company ABC?", "answers": ["It takes Company ABC a long time to properly train each of their employees which is why it's important to them that they hire for as long-term as possible. Many people experience long-term, enjoyable careers in the cruise industry. Take a look at the types of roles that you could earn your way into, and express any interest that you may have in these future opportunities.", "\"I am interested in earning my way into a Cruise Assistant Director role over time. I know that it will take years of dedication and training, but I am passionate for career growth in the cruise industry and am willing to do what it takes. I read that you have an opening which requires more HR and personnel training than I currently have. Do you recommend a specific training path?\"", "\"Looking through the Company ABC website I see that you have a lot of opportunity for leadership growth which includes multiple management and director type of roles. I have a keen interest in the Director of Hospitality position you currently have posted. I know it would take some time for me to work my way into a role such as that; however, I am willing to do what it takes to get there. I am in this job search to find a long-term opportunity.\""]}, {"topic": "Cruises", "question": "Do you think that you can sustain the cruise ship lifestyle for the long term?", "answers": ["The cruise ship lifestyle is a challenging one, and not everyone can sustain its demands for the long term. What characteristics do you have that would help you to endure the hardships (along with the fun!) for the long run? Discuss how you will manage this lifestyle for months, if not years, to come.", "\"I do believe that I can sustain this lifestyle for the long term. I am an extrovert who loves gaining new experiences. I do not need a lot of downtime to recharge, and am known for my high levels of energy. With the correct training, I believe I can succeed in this role with Company ABC for the long term.\"", "\"I have put a lot of research into the cruise ship lifestyle before submitting my application. I believe that the speed here would suit me since I am highly energetic and like to be kept busy. I view this position with Company ABC as a lifestyle based role, and a long-term opportunity.\""]}, {"topic": "Cruises", "question": "Describe the typical Company ABC customer, and the type of vacation they are seeking.", "answers": ["According to Cruise Lines International Association (CLIA), the typical cruise vacationer is: \n\n- 93% Caucasian\n- 46 years or older\n- 65%+ have post-secondary education\n- 80%+ are married\n- 58% work full-time\n- 90K+ household income \n\nShow the interviewer that you have done your research on the typical customer that Company ABC may attract.", "\"I understand that the majority of your customers are upper-level income earners, mostly married, ages 45 and over. I have also read that many of your customers come back for a cruise every three years which is an excellent rate considering the planning and cost associated with such elaborate vacations. I would say that your average customer is seeking a blend of adventure and luxury. Is this correct?\"", "\"I have been on a couple of cruises through Company ABC and found that your cruises are very family oriented. My research tells me that your customers are seeking a vacation out of the ordinary, where they can leave their cares at home. Is this accurate to say?\""]}, {"topic": "Cruises", "question": "How would you deal in an emergency situation, while at sea?", "answers": ["Safety and emergency response will be an integral component of your training, should you be hired by Company ABC. \n\nIf you have received training in cruise line emergencies, discuss this training with the interviewer. \n\nIf you are new to the cruise line industry, express how you would instinctually deal in an emergency. Also, let the interviewer know that you look forward to receiving proper training.", "\"I have been training in emergency response and would follow these steps. First, remaining calm, I would help guide our guests to the muster station. Next, I would suit up the guests with lifejackets, starting with the children and their parents. I would then carefully follow the steps given to me by the captain, depending on the nature of the emergency.\"", "\"I understand that ships have special emergency procedures that all cabin and crew are trained on before setting sail. It's important to remain calm and in control during these situations, to avoid any panic and unnecessary chaos. Although I have no training on cruise ship emergency management, I do believe that the first step would be to guide everyone to the muster point and start suiting the most vulnerable guests with lifejackets first.\""]}, {"topic": "Cruises", "question": "How much do you think this job should pay?", "answers": ["This question is merely another way for the interviewer to ask about your desired pay for this role. Be honest about what you are hoping to make, but you should also avoid asking for too little, or for too much. Using an online salary calculating tool, like the ones from Glassdoor or Indeed, will help you to determine the average ask for your position. You can also use your current salary as part of the basis for your ask.", "\"I am currently earning $15/hour plus travel benefits and a robust health care plan. I am up for a raise to $17/hour in the next couple of months. My ideal salary is $17-19/hour plus health and travel benefits, which I believe is a fair ask for this role.\"", "\"I am newer to my career, so I performed some research on the topic, hoping to gain an understanding of the average pay for service staff on a cruise line. The ranges I saw were $14-18/hour depending on experience. Is this in line with what Company ABC offers for this role?\""]}, {"topic": "Cruises", "question": "When a problem requires a quick solution, how do you respond?", "answers": ["When it comes to complex problem solving, decisions are not always readily reached. It takes practice, experience, and confidence to learn what sorts of decisions yield the best results. Walk the interviewer through your process when it comes to making quick decisions. Do you rely on past experiences? Perhaps you go with a gut feeling. Maybe you have read case studies that you lean on in these instances. \n\nCruise ship problems that require you to act quickly can be emergencies such as knowing where the fire extinguisher is and grabbing it fast enough to put out a grease fire in the kitchen. Other quick decisions could be if you are asked to take on a new responsibility and are only given five minutes to decide if it's something you are prepared to take on. Going with your gut is a skill, and the more you learn to trust your intuition, the easier it becomes to make these types of decisions. Demonstrate that you are confident and able to react swiftly when the need arises.", "\"I thrive under pressure and always have, so when I'm given a time-sensitive situation to address, I light up and get down to business. I am more impactful and even more creative when I have little time to do much besides jump in and take charge. This ability to make fast decisions is especially helpful in the cruise industry when there is a customer service issue or an emergency.\"", "\"As a customer service agent in the cruise line industry, I need to make a multitude of decisions, on the fly, for a variety of guests at a time. I rely partially on the instinct that I have built as an expert in the service industry and part in past travel experiences that may be similar. I am sure always to exude an air of control and confidence when making decisions.\""]}, {"topic": "Cruises", "question": "Have you ever worked in a cross-functional environment?", "answers": ["Cruise ships are heavily cross-functional since all departments and personnel work closely together to create a pleasant and cohesive guest experience. If you have worked for a cruise line in the past, you may have been asked to collaborate between the kitchen and the child care facility. Maybe you have floated service between the pool and the casino. Your ability to work with cross-functional teams will be a significant asset to Company ABC.", "\"I have worked in many cross-functional environments. Currently, I lead the dining service team and collaborate with the kitchen management and bartending staff very regularly. We all work well together to ensure an amazing dining experience for our guests.\"", "\"The cruise line which I currently work for is highly collaborative. We are a 'complete guest experience' organization, so we have meetings together with our casino, watersports, entertainment and excursions, dining staff, and also our cabin crew on a daily basis. Goals are clear, and we all understand how each department works to complement the other.\""]}, {"topic": "Cruises", "question": "Describe your working relationship with your previous or current colleagues.", "answers": ["In a cruise ship environment, you are working very closely with your co-workers, day in and day out. The interviewer would like to know more about your ability to have a harmonious relationship with your colleagues. Avoid talking about any previous workplace drama and do not speak poorly of your colleagues, past or present. Keep your reply positive and upbeat.", "\"All of the colleagues I have worked with have shared a very respectful relationship. We have similar goals and challenges, and we exchange knowledge to accomplish those things to the best we can. Each of us has a part in the company's success, and we utilize communication to make it happen.\"", "\"Our team is amazing! We support each other when customers are a bit cranky, we help each other reach the ships' sales targets and goals, and we help to cover when someone needs a few hours off. I understand that Company ABC offers a collaborative workplace culture similar to this, which is why I was motivated to apply here.\""]}, {"topic": "Cruises", "question": "Are you bilingual?", "answers": ["Many cruise lines will give preference to candidates who are multi-lingual. Because the guests of Company ABC will collectively speak a multitude of languages, they seek to hire a diverse crew who will be able to accommodate that diversity. Discuss any languages that you speak, ranking yourself as beginner, conversational, or fluent, to give the interviewer a firm idea of what to expect from you. If you are willing to learn an additional language, this is an excellent opportunity to show you are eager to succeed.", "\"I come from an English and Spanish speaking home, so am fluent in both languages. Because I speak Spanish, I also pick up on similar languages such as French, quite quickly. If there are other languages you would like me to study; I am happy to learn.\"", "\"I speak primarily English, although I am a beginner in Mandarin and German. I took both languages in high school for a few years, allowing me to understand basic phrases. If you think it would be helpful, I can commit to learning these languages on a deeper level.\""]}, {"topic": "Entertainment", "question": "What has made you ready for this responsibility with Company ABC?", "answers": ["Discuss with the interviewer all of the things you have done to prepare you for this particular opportunity.", "\"I have spent the past 8 months reading leadership books and have taken 2 leadership workshops in that time frame. I have never felt more ready to take on the responsibility of leading a team.\"", "\"I believe that my recent education has prepared me for this responsibility. Not only by giving me the knowledge that I need in the entertainment industry, but also the connections and network.\""]}, {"topic": "Entertainment", "question": "Since Company ABC has an invested interest in the entertainment industry I would love to know - what do you do for entertainment on your off time?", "answers": ["It's definitely okay to add a personal touch to your interview if you are asked a question like this. Show the interviewer a bit about your personality. This is a great time to give a unique answer which will make you stand out from other candidates. A lot of people will answer by saying they like to hang out with family and friends. If YOU talk about that time you went parasailing - you'll definitely be delivering a more memorable interview!", "\"I love to work hard and play hard! This year I decided to try some new forms of entertainment. I have taken up mountain climbing as well as salsa dance lessons. These experiences have been an immense amount of fun and have taken me out of my comfort zone.\"", "\"I like to dabble in a variety of fun things such as cooking lessons, photography courses, and sip and paint nights. I think that it's important to experience a variety of entertainment types to get to know your personal likes and interests on a deeper level.\""]}, {"topic": "Entertainment", "question": "What sources do you look to when you need to solve a complicated problem?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to know that you are able to think outside the box, or even ask for help, when you are stuck on a complicated problem.\n\nMaybe you look to a mentor or boss for advice. Perhaps you have handbooks, manuals and systems you turn to for help. Offer some relevant examples based on your industry. If you work in the medical field, you may turn to textbooks, online research, colleagues or even patient's history to find the right solution. If you work in customer service, you may ask the customer what they need in order to find the best way to solve the problem. \n\nShow the interviewer that you are knowledgeable and equipped to handle these types of scenarios.", "\"When I am faced with a complicated problem, I will look to the resources that my current company has provided me. The answer is almost always in there. If it's more of a moral dilemma vs. a knowledge based dilemma, I will ask my supervisor for his thoughts and opinion since I value him as a mentor and expert in our industry.\"", "\"In order to solve a complex issue, I will reach out to a manager or mentor from a previous role to ask them how they've handled such issues in the past. I am always ready to dive back into our handbook, but these types of scenarios are often not covered there, which is why I really value a human, experiential approach. I know that there are so many folks in the industry who have so much to teach me and have probably already \"been-there-done-that\", so I love to utilize them as a resource.\""]}, {"topic": "Entertainment", "question": "How do you handle communicating bad news to a fellow worker or subordinate?", "answers": ["One of the toughest parts of communication can be delivering bad news to people that you work with and care about. Whether it is delivering a less than positive work review or terminating someone - it doesn't come easy. Assure the interviewer that you are able to handle this type of task in a clear, concise, and professional manner.", "\"I certainly do not enjoy communicating bad news to a co-worker but I do have experience in doing so. When this type of task is required of me, I make sure to practice empathy. Truth is always key, so I will be honest and clear when communicating the news. For instance, if I am to terminate someone's employment I will not sugar coat the reasons why. It's best they know so that they can learn from the experience.\"", "\"Bad news should be delivered quickly but with empathy. I don't enjoy delivering disappointing news but I am confident in my ability to deliver it in a tactful way.\""]}, {"topic": "Entertainment", "question": "Company ABC has many industry competitors. Why do you want to work for us?", "answers": ["The interviewer is looking for specific examples on why you are choosing Company ABC as opposed to any of their competitors. Choose some reasons that will include the company values, the potential growth opportunity, and the sense of pride you would feel if you were hired on with Company ABC. The last thing the interviewer would want to hear is that their opportunity does not stand out or that this is 'just any job' to you.", "\"I chose to apply to Company ABC because your industry reputation is the best of anyone in your market. Your online employee reviews are very positive as well. Through my research on Company ABC I came across a common theme of respect and strong values which I greatly appreciate. I would be very proud to work here!\"", "\"I feel that Company ABC would nurture my desire for growth and prepare me for career advancement with the appropriate training.\""]}, {"topic": "Entertainment", "question": "How can we motivate you on the job?", "answers": ["Every employer should know how each staff member is best motivated. Talk to the interviewer about the variety of ways in which you are best motivated on the job.", "\"I am best motivated through words of praise and recognition for a job well done. I do like to know that my efforts are being noticed. In my current position we have a leader board and I do like that concept because it creates a healthy bit of personal competition in me as well.\"", "\"I am motivated by knowing something about the end customer and being able to relate to them as a person. A personal touch is always helpful for me.\""]}, {"topic": "Entertainment", "question": "What type of work environment allows you to be the most productive?", "answers": ["Are you able to be productive in any environment? Are there particular types of environments that you find distracting? Discuss your preferences with the interviewer. Be sure to research the type of environment that is offered in this position prior to the interview.", "\"I understand that your work environment is very collaborative. I come from a similar environment and found that I could be very productive when there was the \"", "\"I am able to focus well in most environments and am quite self-driven and disciplined. So long as the overall vibe is collaborative and positive, I can be very productive.\""]}, {"topic": "Entertainment", "question": "How do you like to encourage ideas in others?", "answers": ["Encouragement to others is a great skill to possess. Talk to the interviewer about your ability to encourage creative ideas in your team members.", "\"I like to encourage other people to be creative in their thinking and present ideas to the company, no matter how off the wall they may seem. Some of our most successful employees are ones who are confident in their ability to bring forward their unique ideas. I encourage participation through an open door policy and strong praise for those who show initiative.\"", "\"Whether I am training formally or not, I am always the go-to for mentor-ship. It's something that I am really passionate about. I love to see others succeed and help them do so through creating a comfortable learning environment.\""]}, {"topic": "Entertainment", "question": "Company ABC is looking for great problem solvers. When a major problem arises, what is your first reaction?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to know if your reactions to problems reflect maturity and professionalism. How you react will greatly determine how you fit with their existing team. \n\nPerhaps your computer crashes and you realize you may have just lost all of your hard work. Or maybe you are limited on time and have a deadline rapidly approaching. Demonstrate to the interviewer that you take a very methodical approach to problem solving, rather than reacting in an impulsive way when a problem occurs.", "\"When a major problem arises, my first instinct is to take a step back and absorb what just happened. I then go into \"", "\"I have taught myself to become much calmer with my first reactions when problems arise. Now, I will step back and review my options for solving the problem rather than allow myself to become frustrated.\""]}, {"topic": "Entertainment", "question": "Do you prefer to work in a team based position or individually?", "answers": ["In which situation are you the happiest and most productive? Talk to the interviewer about your preference when it comes to teamwork or working individually. Be sure to avoid pigeonholing yourself into one particular scenario (IE: I only like to work by myself).", "\"I have found, in the past, that I work best in an individually driven environment; however, I can certainly be productive in a team based setting as well.\"", "\"I can work successfully in either.  I am comfortable sharing the workload and responsibility with others, or hunkering down and getting it all done myself.\""]}, {"topic": "Entertainment", "question": "At Company ABC we seek to hire those who have a true passion and interest in our industry. What excites you most about what we do?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to be assured that you have a clear passion for what they do at Company ABC. You should be prepared to discuss your industry involvement or how you stay up to date on the industry's hot topics. Show the interviewer that you will be a fully engaged team member, if hired.", "\"I've had a keen interest in cinema, the arts, and entertainment since I was a child. My curiosity is always present when it comes to changes and current events in this industry. I follow your company blog and keep a close eye on other industry related publications and trends from online sources.\"", "\"I am most excited about the opportunity to work with Company ABC because you are a leader in the market with a passion for growing your employees into industry professionals. This truly would be a dream job for me!\""]}, {"topic": "Entertainment", "question": "Have you been exposed to the customer experience at Company ABC? If so, tell me one highlight and one area you feel we fell short.", "answers": ["It's very important that you have some sort of personal experience to share with the interviewer, in regards to your exposure to Company ABC. Talk about the impression you had, and your overall customer experience. Keep your response positive, and your constructive feedback light.", "\"I have been a customer in the past and the factor that stuck out most to me was that your employees all seemed to be really happy. It made me want to work here! If I could offer any opportunity for improvement, I would say that your online experience could be a bit more streamlined for mobile users.\"", "\"I am a regular customer here, and my experiences have all been great. That is one of the reasons I chose to apply here!  I cannot make any comments on where you have fallen short during my visits but one suggestion I do have is to make your phone directory a touch simpler for the customers who call in. Attention spans can be short, and the less options, the better.\""]}, {"topic": "Entertainment", "question": "We have put a lot of time and effort into creating a great workplace culture at Company ABC. How will you contribute to our positive team environment?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to be sure that you will be a strong fit for the workplace culture at Company ABC.  Be prepared to give examples of the ways in which you will contribute, and fit in with, their positive team environment. You can learn more about the culture at Company ABC by researching them online, taking note of the tone in their job postings, and reading the 'About Us' and 'News' sections on their website.", "\"After researching Company ABC I believe that your workplace culture is best described as lighthearted, energetic, and supportive. These are my strongest personality traits so I do see a very strong alignment between your company culture and what I would bring here, if hired.\"", "\"I am a very positive person who is always willing to lend a hand, and go over and above the expectations on me. What I bring to the workplace will fit in really well with the culture at Company ABC. I appreciate that you have such a positive team environment.\""]}, {"topic": "Entertainment", "question": "Everybody we hire at Company ABC should have strong customer service abilities. Give me 3 words that best describe your customer service style.", "answers": ["Whether you have worked directly in customer service, or not, the interviewer wants to be assured that your perspective on customer services aligns well with the values at Company ABC. Be sure to research the organization's customer service attitude so that you can be prepared with answers that will resonate with the interviewer.", "\"Customer service is obviously at the center of your success at Company ABC. I look forward to contributing to your success! I would describe my customer service style as attentive, patient, and enthusiastic.\"", "Additional words that could describe your customer service style: \n\n- Empathetic \n- Caring\n- Concerned \n- Patient\n- Thorough \n- Authentic"]}, {"topic": "Entertainment", "question": "We think it is important to have a streamlined hiring process. How have you found the hiring process at Company ABC so far? Do you have any suggestions?", "answers": ["Great companies will always be looking for ways to streamline their hiring process and improve the candidate experience. You can be honest with the interviewer on your experience; however, keep your reply positive. \n\nIf you have found the process to be slow and frustrating, you could express that by saying \"I have experienced faster candidate screening processes in the past but I am sure you are doing your best with the amount of applications you receive.\" \n\nThis would be a much better response than saying \"Your process is very slow so I would work on fixing that.\"", "\"I have experienced faster candidate screening processes in the past but I am sure you are doing your best with the amount of applications you receive.\"", "\"I have found Company ABC to be very professional throughout this process and have found the experience to be a positive one.\""]}, {"topic": "Entertainment", "question": "We offer a multitude of career paths at Company ABC. How would you like to see your career grow with us?", "answers": ["An easy way to become familiar with the growth avenues available at Company ABC would be to search their online job board or Google for previous job openings. If there are any job postings that catch your eye, you should research what it would take to be qualified for the role. Display to the interviewer that you can see a long term fit with Company ABC by expressing your interest in the potential growth.", "\"While researching Company ABC I came across a job posting for a Corporate Events Manager. The position caught my eye immediately and I was excited to see that Company ABC offers exciting roles on all levels. This is a position I would love to grow into over time.\"", "\"Ideally, I would love to see myself growing into a more prominent leadership role within your organization. My career interests align very nicely with your company's goals which helps me to see a great long term fit here.\""]}, {"topic": "Entertainment", "question": "Why do you think that working for Company ABC will be an improvement over your current situation? Why are you looking for a new job?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to be assured that their position will be a long-term fit for you rather than just a band-aid, short term fix from your restlessness in your current job. Be careful to avoid speaking negatively about your current place of employment and focus on what Company ABC will offer you, why you're excited about their organization, and how you see a long term with with them.", "\"I have been seeking a change within a company who puts their client experience first, treats their employees with a fair attitude and has a reputation that I can brag about. My current company has been good to me the past 3 years; however, with recent restructuring within management I no longer feel it's the most conducive environment for me. I am really excited about what I've seen from Company ABC so far and think this would be a fantastic place to work.\"", "\"I have been passively seeking a new position for quite some time and haven't jumped on anything yet because I want to make sure it's the right fit. I feel that this job is right for me, at this point in my career, because it offers an opportunity for me to utilize my recent education in business while giving me an opportunity to advance in my knowledge within the entertainment industry.\""]}, {"topic": "Entertainment", "question": "Being the best in your industry is great but it also brings its own challenges. What do you foresee as the biggest challenge for you in this role with Company ABC?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to see that you are not just wearing rose-colored glasses, thinking this job will be perfect 100% of the time. They want to ensure that realistic expectations are set right away. \n\r\nTalk to the interviewer about a challenge you think you may face in this role. Be sure to complete your answer by also discussing how you plan to overcome that challenge! A challenge could include learning a new industry, learning a new software program, being in a customer facing role again, etc.", "\"I believe the biggest challenge for me will be to learn your internal P.O.S system. From what I understand, it is a robust system. I do consider myself very tech savvy so I am confident that I will pick it up quickly.\"", "\"Because I am newer to your industry, I feel that the biggest challenge will be to learn the proper lingo and verbiage used here. I look forward to learning, though!\""]}, {"topic": "Entertainment", "question": "How do you like to be recognized for your accomplishments?", "answers": ["We all like to be recognized in some way for our accomplishments in the workplace. Share with the interviewer how you would like to be recognized for your hard work. Through gifts? Financial perks? Public recognition? Kind words? Title promotions?", "\"I am very much an over-achiever and find that the best way for me to be recognized for a job well done is to be given words of kindness and recognition. I am easily encouraged and the best reward for me is to know that my hard work is being noticed.\"", "\"I am a highly competitive person who is compensation driven. I like to be recognized for my accomplishments through monetary bonus' or contests where the stakes are high.\""]}, {"topic": "Entertainment", "question": "Have you ever taken a role in a company that hasn't fit into your long-term career plans?", "answers": ["Most people have taken on a position that was not a fit for them in the end. It's best top openly discuss any positions that you have held that were not a fit. This will assist the interviewer in being able to properly place you within their organization. Be sure to end your answer on a positive note, discussing how you bounced back from the misstep.", "\"Yes, you will see that from March to May 2007 I held a role as a Business Development Representative with Company XYZ. This particular role was not what I was expecting and had little to do with management and more to do with cold calling onto C-suite level clients. This wasn't nurturing my plan to grow the management side of my career, so I resigned after just 2 months. Luckily I landed a wonderful job immediately after and grew with that company for the following 6 years.\"", "\"I have been fortunate to make very well-researched employment decisions so far in my career. I ask a lot of questions in my interviews and take the time to review all contracts before signing them.\""]}, {"topic": "Entertainment", "question": "How do you get along with others at work?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to gauge if you can maintain healthy relationships in the workplace. What are the dynamics of your working relationships? Think about what you enjoyed about some of your relationships with past coworkers. Good communication, sense of humor, and support are all great qualities that make co-worker relationships healthy.", "\"I get along great with my coworkers. I try to maintain a positive attitude and be supportive, whether I am offering to assist someone who is overwhelmed, or if I am taking time to listen to someone who is having a bad day.\"", "\"My previous managers have often commented on my ability to get along well with others in the workplace. I enjoy getting to know my colleagues, understanding what makes them tick, and what they value most inside and outside of the workplace.\""]}, {"topic": "Entertainment", "question": "When you suffer a setback, how does that emotionally affect you and your work?", "answers": ["Everyone handles the stress and disappointment of setbacks differently. Discuss with the interviewer how you typically cope with setbacks in the workplace.", "\"Experiencing a setback is always disappointing, and can be a bit disheartening, but I understand that it happens from time to time. If I experience a major setback I will take a few moments to debrief with my manager and discuss what I could have done differently. Then, I move on!\"", "\"Setbacks happen for a reason and they do not affect me emotionally in the least. I am a very pragmatic thinker and stay focused despite the challenges that come my way.\""]}, {"topic": "Entertainment", "question": "What was the most difficult part about your training or education?", "answers": ["Share a challenge you experienced in one of your classes or training courses. Maybe the class was difficult because it wasn't one of your strengths. Math and science courses might be tricky for you or maybe the professor was real challenge. Focus on what you did to overcome it, rather than placing your attention on the issue.", "\"The most difficult part of my education was my Statistics course. I overcame this challenge by hiring a tutor. I ended up with a A but it was definitely the result of a lot of work and studying.\"", "\"The most difficult thing for me was the level of homework and study time required. I had always worked while going to high school, but I had to reduce my hours to make time for studying.\""]}, {"topic": "Entertainment", "question": "If you were given a choice, which work related task would you leave for last? Why?", "answers": ["Often times we will leave the tasks that we don't like for last in an act of procrastination. Other times, we will mindfully leave a task for last because we feel that it makes the most sense. Help the interviewer to determine which personality type you are by answering this question clearly.", "\"If I were given a choice, I would leave my documentation tasks for last. I say this because I like to spend my time selling and hitting targets so anything to do with documentation during business hours - I feel takes away from my business development tasks. I do understand the importance of it, though.\"", "\"I tend to leave the hardest assignments for last.  It is not because I dread them, but because I can make a lot more people happy by completing their small requests first and getting them back to work.\""]}, {"topic": "Entertainment", "question": "Stressful situations can arise at Company ABC. How do you handle stress?", "answers": ["Are you someone who is able to handle stress on the job? How do you manage the stressful times? Talk to the interviewer about your ability to manage pressure in the workplace.", "\"I handle stress very well and when you call my references, they will attest to this fact. When I am under pressure on the job, I focus on the task at hand and make sure to not get distracted. Staying on deadline is very helpful and I will delegate when necessary to alleviate some stress.\"", "\"Stress is part of any demanding job and I embrace it to the fullest.  I take good care of myself personally and prioritize my workload to maintain a healthy balance in my stress levels.\""]}, {"topic": "Entertainment", "question": "Tell me about your experience in this field.", "answers": ["It is very important to become acquainted with the job description prior to your interview. When the interviewer asks this question be sure to highlight the related experience that you bring.", "\"I bring all of the experience that you are looking for in filling this position, such as A, B, and C. In addition to being an expert user in A, I also bring 5 years' experience in B.\"", "\"I have 8 years of industry experience with Company ABC and XYZ. Both experiences taught me a great deal about this field and I am excited to continue my career in this industry with your organization.\""]}, {"topic": "Entertainment", "question": "On a scale from 1 to 10, how honest are you?", "answers": ["Do you feel that you are a very honest person or do you have room for growth? This could be a tricky question as nobody is always 100% honest. Answer to the best of your ability and back your reply by speaking about your personal ethics.", "\"I would love to give myself a 10/10 for honesty but truthfully - nobody is 100% honest all of the time. I will give myself an 9 because I always do my best to be as honest as possible.\"", "\"I value honesty and strive to be a trustworthy person in all situations. I would rate myself a 10/10.\""]}, {"topic": "Entertainment", "question": "What is your definition of hard work?", "answers": ["Hard work and dedication can be interpreted differently by everyone. To one person, another person's hard work could seem like slacking. Talk to the interviewer about how you interpret a hard day's work.", "\"For me, hard work means that I did what I could that day to exceed expectations. I come to work early and stay late if needed and I go over and above the requirements without hesitation.\"", "\"I know that I have worked hard if, at the end of the day, I can be proud of the work that I completed.\""]}, {"topic": "Entertainment", "question": "What decisions did you routinely make in your last position?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know more about the types of decisions you are accustomed to making in the workplace. The way you answer this questions will give them a good idea of your level of experience, seniority, and ability to handle the decision making requirements in this potential position. \n\nIf the job you are interviewing for requires you to be decisive and quick on your feet, you will need to be able to provide examples of how you have done these things in the past. If you worked in tech support, you were faced with problems that you needed to find solutions for on a regular basis. If you worked as a sales rep, you may have needed to know how to negotiate and make decisions on prices and benefits you can give your customers. \n\nYou may have been faced with decisions that became so routine you didn't think twice! Refer to these types of decisions and be sure to highlight how these types of decisions have prepared you for a role like this one.", "\"In my previous position I was quite often required to make decisions on staff scheduling as well as hiring and terminating. I feel that role prepared me quite well for a position like this one. I have well-honed decision making skills and my intuition, when it comes to hiring, has been elevated.\"", "\"I regularly made decisions regarding pricing and discounts for customers.  I had a standard set of criteria that I created, and I tried to let that guide me for consistency.\""]}, {"topic": "Entertainment", "question": "How competitive are you?", "answers": ["Being a competitive person is a great thing if you are appropriately competitive in the workplace. Assure the interviewer that you have a great competitive edge when necessary but are still able to balance that competition in a healthy way.", "\"I think that on a scale of 1-10, I would rate myself as a 7 when it comes to being competitive. I love a great competition in the workplace when it comes to sales goals and breaking through last years' numbers. I am not competitive to the point that it would hurt my team or colleagues.\"", "\"I am competitive when it matters. I enjoy a good, healthy competition, in the form of sales contests or incentives. With that said, I don't identify as an overly competitive person who always needs to win. I enjoy watching others win, just as often.\""]}, {"topic": "Entertainment", "question": "How do you deal with a coworker when they stand in the way of your progress at work?", "answers": ["Even some of the best coworkers who are hard-working and entertaining can distract you from getting things done at work. Let's be honest, the funny and entertaining coworkers who like to chat online and send you YouTube videos are often the ones who can get in the way of your productivity. This question gives you a chance to talk about how you set healthy boundaries at work. It can be a difficult task, but you can handle it! Show off your ability to listen and communicate what you need from your coworkers, especially when you need space!", "\"I typically just set the boundary and tell my coworker that I really need to focus, but I'd love to catch up with them at lunch. I've learned to set aside time to take breaks and spend time with coworkers, so I usually just let them know when I'll be available.\"", "\"If I have a coworker who is being a distraction, I will temporarily relocate my work-space or I will ask them to allow me to concentrate. If a coworker understands that you are under deadline or pressure, that usually helps them to understand your need for space.\""]}, {"topic": "Entertainment", "question": "What are your salary expectations?", "answers": ["The best way to discuss your salary expectations are to use your current earnings as an example. Be open, and honest. Transparency is the best choice when salary based questions arise.", "\"Currently, I earn a base salary of $45,000 per year plus a potential 20% annual bonus. Last year my earnings were $52,000 and I would like to stay in the same range or slightly higher.\"", "\"I am currently making $100,000 per year with two bonus opportunities.  I am looking for compensation that is aligned with the role and provides opportunity for growth.\""]}, {"topic": "Health", "question": "What do you think is the most popular product or service we offer at Company ABC?", "answers": ["Your level of knowledge about Company ABC will show the interviewer just how engaged you are in the interview process. Investing time into researching Company ABC before your interview will ensure that you are prepared to impress! Discuss what you think is the most popular offering by Company ABC. This can even be an educated guess based on online reviews, particular products/services they feature on their website, or through their advertising efforts.", "\"There are a lot of great choices at Company ABC that I find exciting so that's a tough question! I see your advertisements for 'Product ABC' quite a lot so I am going to guess that this is one of your most popular offerings.\"", "\"From the research that I have conducted on your social media platforms, and website, I feel that your best services are A, and B. Is that correct? I would love to hear more.\""]}, {"topic": "Health", "question": "We believe in leading by example at Company ABC and seek to hire those who put their health first. What is the best thing you've ever done for your own personal health?", "answers": ["It's absolutely okay to give a personal answer for this type of interview question. Because Company ABC is focused on health and wellness, you should be open and real when it comes to your own personal  journey. Discuss the best choice that you've made for your personal health and the positive impact that choice has had on your life.", "\"The best decision that I ever made for my own personal health was to quit smoking cigarettes. I achieved this 4 years ago and haven't looked back since. I feel so much more energy and of course it's helped my skin as well.\"", "\"The best habit that I started for myself was to go to bed early every day so that I could wake up earlier. I am more productive this way and sleep a lot better, too.\""]}, {"topic": "Health", "question": "How do you handle stress on the job?", "answers": ["Are you someone who is able to handle stress on the job? How do you manage the stressful times? Talk to the interviewer about your ability to manage pressure in the workplace.", "\"I handle stress very well and when you call my references, they will attest to this fact. When I am under pressure on the job, I focus on the task at hand and make sure to not get distracted. Staying on deadline is very helpful and I will delegate when necessary to alleviate some stress.\"", "\"Stress is part of any demanding job and I embrace it to the fullest.  I take good care of myself personally and prioritize my workload to maintain a healthy balance in my stress levels.\""]}, {"topic": "Health", "question": "Give me an example of a time when you went above and beyond.", "answers": ["Display to the interviewer that you are able to do more that the bare minimum. Show that you are able to react appropriately when you see that your employer has a need that goes beyond your usual day-to-day expectations.", "\"Last week I noticed that my manager had not completed the schedule for the following week. Some of the staff were complaining that they didn't have their work schedule yet. Rather than going to my manager with the complaint, I offered to take on some of her work load so that she would have the time to complete the schedule. We worked together for a couple of overtime hours that day and were able to catch her up on everything. It felt good to help but also benefited me by way of organization.\"", "\"Going above and beyond is what I do on a regular basis. I do not insist on sticking with \"the usual\" when it comes to the level of service that my clients receive. I will always lend a hand to my coworkers when they need it, and I offer up a smile even on the tough days.\""]}, {"topic": "Health", "question": "At Company ABC our clients come from all walks of life. Do you have experience with a broad range of people with varying needs?", "answers": ["Assure the interviewer that you will be a great match for their customers, no matter their age, needs, or understanding of the health industry. Discuss the types of customers you have the most exposure to and be sure to highlight your ability to relate to the broad range of clientele at Company ABC.", "\"In my current position I have a range of clients from youth to retirement age. I love to help people of all ages who find value in taking care of their body. I am a friendly and talkative person which makes it easy for me to relate to customers from all walks of life. I look forward to developing relationships with your valued clients.\"", "\"Currently, the majority of clients that I work with are children; however, I am capable of working with a diverse range of clientele. I am comfortable working with all ages and backgrounds.\""]}, {"topic": "Health", "question": "What causes you to feel dissatisfied on the job?", "answers": ["Everyone will have their own particular triggers that cause them to feel dissatisfaction on the job. Talk to the interviewer about any factors that may deflate or discourage you in the workplace.", "\"I can feel dissatisfaction on the job when I am not feeling heard or when there is not a mutual respect among the team members. I work best in more harmonious situations where there is little drama or gossip.\"", "\"I have felt dissatisfied on the job when I feel underpaid and overworked. I don't mind working hard at all but I don't like to feel as though I'm being taken advantage of.\""]}, {"topic": "Health", "question": "What do you hope to gain from this position with Company ABC?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know that you are making a move that makes sense for you and your career, at this time. Share something you are hoping to gain from this role that you are not currently receiving from your current or most recent position. \n\nMaybe the job posting says, \u201cMust be well versed in social media marketing.\u201d  You could reply with: \u201cI love using social media for business marketing but haven\u2019t had as much opportunity to do so in my current position. I see that you are seeking someone well versed and passionate in this area. It's exactly the type of responsibility have missed in my current position.\"", "\"What I am looking for, and hope to gain from this position, is the career growth that I have been missing in my current position. I would love to expand on my sales experience and leadership skills while working with a company that I am proud to be a part of.\""]}, {"topic": "Health", "question": "Where did you come across our job posting, and what prompted you to apply with Company ABC?", "answers": ["The employer would like to know what methods and resources you are using in your job search so they can determine which of their methods is working best. You can expand your answer to include any other exposure you have had to the company.", "\"I initially saw your job posting on LinkedIn, however I have been exposed to your organization many times before through your radio commercials and advertisements on Facebook.\"", "\"For the last 8 months, I have been contemplating a move and keeping my eye out for the perfect opening. When I saw this position open on your website, I knew I had to go for it, and I am so happy I did. It feels right."]}, {"topic": "Health", "question": "Why is this job with Company ABC right for you, at this time?", "answers": ["Discuss with the interviewer why you are looking to make a change, and how this particular role fits well with the changes that you are seeking. Be sure to give a more in-depth answer than the typical \"I am looking for growth\" answer that so many interviewers hear. Be thoughtful and draw upon the research you have done on the company.", "\"This is the right job for me because it is what I have been trained to do.  My education and previous work history are related to the role and the industry, making it a perfect fit.\""]}, {"topic": "Health", "question": "Although not a requirement, we prefer to hire those with some education in health, fitness, or nutrition. Walk me through any education and training you feel would add to your success with Company ABC.", "answers": ["Your education background is likely listed on your resume; however, the interviewer is looking for you to expand on that experience. If you do not have any education directly related to health, fitness, or nutrition you can choose to discuss other areas of your education that will benefit Company ABC. These areas may include business training, technical skills, or sales training for instance.", "\"The majority of my education and training is surrounding sales and marketing. I am happy to spend time learning the health and nutrition portion of your business. Because I am well educated in business, I will be able to make a positive impact in this role right away through my strong up-selling and customer service skills.\"", "\"I recently graduated with my Bachelor's degree in Kinesiology. Some of the courses that I took included Motor Control and Learning, Introduction to Research, Statistical Inquiry, \u200bHuman Anatomy and Physiology. I believe that these courses will benefit my performance when it comes to the programs and services that you offer here.\""]}, {"topic": "Health", "question": "At Company ABC we believe that health is more than just exercising. If you could recommend 3 habits to our clients,  for achieving optimal health, what would you recommend?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to ensure that you have a well-rounded idea of health, which will benefit Company ABC customers. You can discuss the best advice that you would give a potential client or talk about some healthy habits that you follow yourself.", "\"I understand the importance of guiding customers to optimal health through a well-rounded approach. If I could suggest three of my top habits, besides regular exercise, I would recommend drinking plenty of water, getting enough sleep, and avoiding unnatural food ingredients as much as possible.\"", "Here are some suggestions you could make for your clients to achieve optimal health:\n\n- Increasing vegetable intake\n- Consider good fats vs. bad fats\n- Choose good grains such as quinoa or brown rice\n- Eat more lentils \n- Try lemon water\n- Do a healthy cleanse on a routine basis \n- Reduce alcohol intake \n- Eat more fish and less red meat \n- Take the stairs whenever possible!", "Great answer! I would be prepared to expand on your answer. Why are these the 3 habits that you would recommend? This will help give the interviewer insight into your thought process."]}, {"topic": "Health", "question": "Company ABC is asking for 8 years of industry experience and you have just 5. Why do you think you are qualified for this position?", "answers": ["To many employers, the number of years' experience is flexible - so long as you have the results to show for the years that you do have. Talk to the interviewer about your major career successes. This is the time to sell yourself. Make no apologies for your lack of years!", "\"Although I have 5 years' experience vs 8 years' experience I can absolutely do this job well. In my previous role, I was outperforming colleagues who had 12  years of experience. To me, it's all about drive and ability to be a quick study. I have all of these qualities and more.\"", "\"Along with my 5 years working in this industry, I have worked in related industries my entire career. Also, I hope that my graduate degree gives me a little boost in experience over the required undergraduate degree.\""]}, {"topic": "Health", "question": "Do you have experience in corrective discipline and terminations?", "answers": ["Terminations and corrective discipline measures can be very difficult to do but, with experience, they do get easier. Talk to the interviewer about the extent of your experience with terminations and discipline. \n\nIf you do have the experience: \"I have been a part of individual terminations and group lay-offs throughout my career. I am comfortable with these types of tasks.\"", "\"I have been a part of individual terminations and group lay-offs throughout my career. I am comfortable with these types of tasks.\"", "If you do not have the experience: \"I have not been in a position to perform terminations or hold corrective discipline meetings; however, I would be willing to perform these types of tasks with a small amount of training and research.\""]}, {"topic": "Health", "question": "Rate your communication skills from 1-10 with proper examples backing your given rating.", "answers": ["On a scale of 1-10, how skilled are you in communication? Why did you choose that particular rating for yourself?", "\"I rate my communication skills as a 9/10 as I will, on occasion, have times when I am not as clear as I would like to be. My supervisor and co-workers will attest to my clear and concise communication skills. Because I am an open leader, my team will let me know if I need to clarify anything.\"", "\"I will rate myself an 8.5 because I consider myself a strong communicator.  It is the foundation of all success in business.  I am always striving to be a better communicator so I leave the rest of the scale as an aspirational measure.\""]}, {"topic": "Health", "question": "We offer growth opportunities to employees who shine! How would you like to see your career grow with Company ABC?", "answers": ["Before your interview be sure to visit Company ABC career opportunities online. Take note of the range in opportunities. Perhaps there are opportunities in other locations or one particular job posting that caught your eye. Assure the interviewer that you desire a long term opportunity with Company ABC by discussing the career path you would like.", "\"I saw a few leadership opportunities posted on your company website that seemed very interesting. Ultimately, I would like to work my way into a management role that offered opportunities for me to train new staff. I am a strong leader, and coach, and am confident I will shine in those areas.\"", "\"I am interested in a variety of paths with your company. I could absolutely see myself working in your programs department, as a Program Director, as I further my knowledge on your product and services.\""]}, {"topic": "Health", "question": "Company ABC has many strong competitors. In your opinion, how do we stand out from the crowd?", "answers": ["It is important that you research Company ABC before your interview and be sure to learn about their business landscape. Who are their competitors? What are customers saying online? Check out some popular review sites to get an idea of what the public is saying about Company ABC vs their competitors. Keep your answer positive and complimentary.", "\"I believe that Company ABC stands out through the diverse range of products and services that you offer. Your seem to have a more innovative approach than most others in the marketplace.\"", "\"Your company seems to have an extra special touch when it comes to the care of your clients. Your follow up is really great and I enjoy your holistic approach.\""]}, {"topic": "Health", "question": "Have you ever been a customer of Company ABC? If so, describe your experience.", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know that you have experienced what it's like to be a customer / client of Company ABC. It is highly recommended that you try their services and /or products before your interview. 'I have never been a customer here' is never an acceptable answer. Your answer should remain positive and complimentary. Highlight the biggest take-away from your experience.", "\"My first experience as a customer of Company ABC was a couple of years ago when my friend recommend you. My experience was very positive and memorable which is a big reason why I applied here when I saw the job opening. I really got the impression that your employees were knowledgeable and highly trained.\"", "\"I am a regular client here and that's actually how I was able to find out about your job posting. My experiences at Company ABC have always been very positive and I look forward to seeing things from the other side.\""]}, {"topic": "Health", "question": "We believe in continually educating our staff at Company ABC. If we could offer you a course on any topic related to our business, what would you choose?", "answers": ["The interviewer is digging a bit deeper to learn about your specific interests within their industry. Perhaps you already know a great deal about fitness but you want to refine your education in nutrition. Pick one area where you would choose to expand your knowledge, if given the opportunity. Close your answer by expressing appreciation for the potential opportunity.", "\"I have always had a keen interest in fitness and am curious to learn more about the ways in which nutrition directly affects the body. The right foods can actually heal certain ailments and that is really interesting to me. If I could take a course on any topic related to the health industry, I would definitely choose a nutrition based topic. I am even more excited to work for Company ABC knowing that you place so much value on continued education!\"", "\"I love this question as I am a huge fan of continued education. If I could take any coursework related to the health industry, I would take something related to holistic herbal studies.\""]}, {"topic": "Health", "question": "Why is health, nutrition, and weight management important to you?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to get to know you a little bit more from a personal perspective. This type of question is a great opportunity for you to stand out from the other candidates by offering a unique and memorable answer. This is not the time to give a general answer. Keep your reply brief but open and honest. Perhaps you have struggled with your weight, or helped someone in your family overcome an illness through healthy lifestyle changes!", "\"Health and nutrition has been an important part of my life from a very young age. My dad has diabetes and I have seen the positive difference it made when he started to choose a healthy lifestyle. When he exercises and makes the best food choices, he feels so much better. I think everyone should be aware of the major connection between our lifestyle choices and our quality of life.\"", "\"My story is unique because I have been on a personal weight loss journey for the past 12 months. I have lost a total of 90 pounds and have found this strong passion for helping others to see their health related dreams become reality.\""]}, {"topic": "Health", "question": "Have you ever worked in a cross-functional environment?", "answers": ["If you work for a larger company, you may have been asked to work on a project with teams from another department. Your ability to work with cross-functional teams will be a big asset to your potential employer, especially if they are a larger organization. \n\nMaybe you headed a project which required you to collaborate with the members from the engineering and sales teams. You may have had the opportunity to organize a volunteer activity or team building exercise, company-wide. Share any challenges that came up and what you learned from the experience.", "\"I am regularly exposed to cross-functional teamwork in my current position. I believe that when expectations are communicated clearly from the beginning, a cross-functional team project can be very successful. I go into these types of projects with an understanding that everyone has their own strengths and limitations based on their expertise and job function.\"", "\"I have worked in a cross-functional setting for many years. Primarily with the  administrative department and the accounts receivable department. Clear communication is key when collaborating with different teams. Clarity in expectations is of huge importance.\""]}, {"topic": "Health", "question": "Who would you say inspires you?", "answers": ["This question is something that you should have an answer ready for at all times. \r\nPerhaps you look up to a parent who was a hard worker or a teacher who encouraged you to become who you are today. Whomever this inspiring person may be, remember that it's an answer from the heart that the interviewer is looking for.", "\"My inspiration comes from my grandmother. She has spent every day of her life working hard and I have never once heard her complain about being tired and overworked. She taught me the value of a good reputation and I still seek out her opinion when I need inspiration.\"", "\"There are a few individuals in this industry who inspire me. I follow a few industry influencers such as Rich Froning, Jennifer Cohen, and Steve Kamb. They inspire me because they are smart, and encourage healthy eating and smart fitness regimes.\""]}, {"topic": "Health", "question": "What work situations excite and motivate you?", "answers": ["It is important, for your success, that the hiring manager knows how to keep you motivated and excited to come to work every day. Share with the interviewer what they could do to ensure that you are happy and productive.", "\"I am most motivated, on the job, when tasks are organized and the vibe is positive. I really value strong teamwork and good leadership.\"", "\"Paving new paths and creating structures to support organizations excite me the most.  I am self motivated and enjoy seeing my hard work make a difference for an organization.\""]}, {"topic": "Health", "question": "How do you like to encourage ideas in others?", "answers": ["Encouragement to others is a great skill to possess. Talk to the interviewer about your ability to encourage creative ideas in your team members.", "\"I like to encourage other people to be creative in their thinking and present ideas to the company, no matter how off the wall they may seem. Some of our most successful employees are ones who are confident in their ability to bring forward their unique ideas. I encourage participation through an open door policy and strong praise for those who show initiative.\"", "\"I like to make a positive impact on the lives of others and see them grow so I do continually encourage them, verbally. Words of affirmation can be very motivating for most people.\""]}, {"topic": "Health", "question": "How many days were you absent from work last year?", "answers": ["A part of being a diligent employee is to ensure that you are always on time and present when expected. It's great to even be 10 minutes early rather than just showing up right on the dot. Talk to the interviewer about your attendance.", "\"I had zero unexcused absences last year. In total, I took 12 vacation days out of my 15 allotted days. I was sick just 2 and those were accompanied by a note from my Doctor. Once I was late due to a terrible snow storm and I always try to be 10 minutes early for my shift.\"", "\"I was absent a total of 5 days last year, excluding my vacation time. All of my absences were previously excused by my manager.\""]}, {"topic": "Health", "question": "What is your availability?", "answers": ["Before answering scheduling questions, it's important to be clear on the interviewer's  expectations. If you haven't had a chance to clarify their scheduling needs, now would be the perfect time to ask! \n\nConsider asking, 'What are the scheduling expectations for this position?' If they expect you to work 12 hour days, it would be important for you to know that before you respond with, 'Absolutely! No problem!' You want to be sure that you can meet their expectations. \n\nIf it turns out their schedule expectations won't work for you, think about what you CAN offer and see if you can meet in the middle. It's much better to discuss these things in an interview than for you to commit to a schedule that won't work for you.", "\"I am available for full time work which is preferably 8-5 Monday to Friday. I am happy to be a team player and work some overtime, as required. Will these hours meet your expectations?\"", "\"If overtime is required in this role, I am happy to accommodate whenever I can. My only restriction is that I cannot work Wednesday nights as I have an evening course those days.\""]}, {"topic": "Health", "question": "Have you ever been advised by a fellow employee or supervisor to lie about a situation? How did you handle this ethical dilemma?", "answers": ["Ethical dilemmas in the workplace will come up from time to time. Assure the interviewer that you are able to handle these types of dilemmas with professionalism and poise.", "\"I have never been told to lie to a fellow employee or supervisor on the job. If I were to be asked to lie I absolutely would not do that. I am not the type of personality to be pushed around on the job. I will always be myself and keep my integrity first.\"", "\"From my recollection, I have not been asked to lie while in the workplace. I would not tolerate being put in an ethical dilemma.\""]}, {"topic": "Health", "question": "How do you define success?", "answers": ["What does success mean to you? Tell the interviewer how you see success and be sure to tie your answer into the success that you plan to bring to this particular position, should you be offered the role.", "\"I define success by my ability to reach the goals that are set out for me. On a personal level, the things I wish to achieve in my life. On a work level, the targets that are set out for me as well as the professional development that I seek.\"", "\"To me, success means doing what you love and what you are good at, while making a difference in the lives of others.\""]}, {"topic": "Health", "question": "Tell me about a time when you effectively delegated tasks.", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know that you are capable of confidently delegating tasks to your employees or coworkers.\n\nA great leader is someone who can effectively manage their time by ensuring tasks are fairly divided while utilizing the strengths of others. \nDisplay to the interviewer that you have the wherewithal to recognize the strengths of your team by delegating tasks which compliment their individual skill sets.", "\"In my current position I was asked to put together a team for a special client project. I was able to handpick the team members and organize the project execution. I chose my strongest employees in a variety of areas. In our initial meeting, I delegated the tasks while explaining my reasoning. This was a great opportunity for me to show each team member that I had the utmost confidence in their abilities. I played to their strengths and it worked out really well. We delivered to our client on time and under budget.\"", "\"Every month I have a meeting with all team members to talk about our plan for the month and how we will delegate the work. It's a great strategy for us and everyone starts the month with laid out expectations.\""]}, {"topic": "Health", "question": "What type of goals do you like to set for yourself and your team?", "answers": ["What types of goals are you most keen on setting for your employees? Talk to the interviewer about the types of goals that you find most important.", "\"I put my team's goals into three categories. Financial goals, client acquisition goals, and personal growth goals. Financial goals focus on their monetary sales targets for the quarter. Client acquisition goals are the amount of new client relationships that they bring in. And personal growth goals focus on their own professional development. This can include taking a course or reading a new career related book.\"", "\"The goals that my team focus' on most are the amount of happy clients helped, the amount of volunteer hours we have put in, and of course - our profit. We reassess these goals every month.\""]}, {"topic": "Health", "question": "When a problem requires a quick solution, how do you respond?", "answers": ["When it comes to complex problem solving, the decisions do not always come easily. It takes practice, experience, and confidence to learn what sorts of decisions yield the best results. \n\nProblems that require you to act quickly can be emergency situations such as knowing where the fire extinguisher is and grabbing it fast enough to put out small grease fire in the company kitchen. Other quick decisions could be if you are asked to take on a new responsibility and only given five minutes to decide if it's something you are prepared to take on. \n\nGoing with your gut is a skill, and the more you learn to trust your intuition, the easier it becomes to make these types of decisions. Demonstrate that you are confident and able to react swiftly when the need arises.", "\"When an urgent problem arises at work, I always try to respond in a calm and assuring manner. I am a natural leader which means that my team often looks to me for answers. One instance of my fast-thinking was just last week when we had an administrative employee no-show on a very important and busy day for us. I called a temp agency and they had the position filled in just one hour.\"", "\"I react swiftly in emergency situations. Perhaps my skills come from my years as a parent, having to think fast and put out fires! If a quick solution is required I will do a fast overview of the facts and make a decision based on risk factors.\""]}, {"topic": "Health", "question": "What is your current salary?", "answers": ["A potential employer will often base their offer on your current salary. You should be transparent about your most recent earnings and be prepared to back up any salary requests.", "\"I am currently earning a base salary of $78,000 plus a car allowance of $900/month and health benefits. I am looking for a competitive salary in my next position.\"", "\"I am currently making $100,000 per year with two bonus opportunities.  I am looking for compensation that is aligned with the role and provides opportunity for growth.\""]}, {"topic": "Health", "question": "Tell me a little bit about yourself.", "answers": ["Many interviewers will start off with this question, which could throw you off a bit. You've done all of this research on the company but have you prepared to talk about yourself?  \n\nThe interviewer is looking for relevant information to the position you applied for. Respond by mentioning your education, how many years of experience you have in your field, and be sure give some details about your most current position. Conclude your response with a statement about what you are looking for in a position at this time.", "\"With pleasure!  I have over 10 years in experience with selling professional services and am interested in growing my career to the next level. On a more personal note, I love to read, go hiking and spend a lot of my extra time volunteering with the humane society.\""]}, {"topic": "Hospitality", "question": "Why should we hire you?", "answers": ["If you can't think of ways that you are unique, ask a few friends or family members what they feel sets you apart from other people. Their observations may help you understand how you are perceived.\n\nPerhaps you already know what sets you apart! Your answer could include any industry accolades, unique achievements, additional industry related training, a second language, or how involved you are in the community. Don't be afraid to brag about yourself a bit. In an interview, you are your most influential advocate.", "\"You should hire me because I am unlike anyone else you have interviewed before. When I started with my current company, I was the youngest salesperson they had ever hired. That didn't stop me from becoming the #1 sales person in the company within six months. I am dedicated to my craft and engaged in this industry to the point where I commit myself to taking at least one business development or leadership related workshop every business quarter. I am a competitive achiever. You won't be disappointed when you hire me.\"", "\"I have over a dozen years of experience in the industry at one of your largest competitors. I have a proven track record of successes there and will bring that knowledge here to Company ABC. You will see a positive impact from me right away.\""]}, {"topic": "Hospitality", "question": "Have you ever worked in a cross-functional environment?", "answers": ["If you work for a larger company, you may have been asked to work on a project with teams from another department. Your ability to work with cross-functional teams will be a significant asset to your potential employer, especially if they are a larger organization. \n\nMaybe you headed a project which required you to collaborate with the members of the engineering and sales teams. You may have had the opportunity to organize a volunteer activity or team building exercise, company-wide. Share any challenges that came up and what you learned from the experience.", "\"I am regularly exposed to cross-functional teamwork in my current position. I believe that when expectations are communicated clearly from the beginning, a cross-functional team project can be very successful. I go into these types of projects with an understanding that everyone has their strengths and limitations based on their expertise and job function.\"", "\"I have worked in a cross-functional setting for many years. Primarily with the HR department and the Accounting department. Clear communication is key when collaborating with different teams. Clarity in expectations is of huge importance.\""]}, {"topic": "Hospitality", "question": "If you were given a choice, which work related task would you leave for last? Why?", "answers": ["Often we will leave the tasks that we don't like for last in the act of procrastination. Other times, we will mindfully move a job for last because we feel that it makes the most sense. Help the interviewer to determine which personality type you are by answering this question.", "\"If given a choice, I would leave my documentation tasks for last. I say this because I like to spend my time selling and hitting targets so anything to do with documentation during business hours - I feel takes away from my business development tasks. I do understand the importance of it, though.\"", "\"I do not believe in procrastination, so I tend to take on the most challenging aspects of a project first, and then work my way into the easier, less time-consuming portions of my work.\"", "\"Tasks that are on the bottom of my list are tasks that, as soon as you complete it, someone comes and ruins your hard work, for example, cleaning the elevator stainless steel doors, and someone puts their handprints all over it!\"", "Frustrating for sure! This is a clear example and entertaining as well."]}, {"topic": "Hospitality", "question": "What is the most competitive work situation you have experienced?", "answers": ["Think back to a time when you were racing others to achieve the highest sales, were working towards a promotion, or eagerly trying to win a new contract. Show the interviewer that you rose to the challenge and that you were excited to push yourself to be the best. It is a definite plus if you have cheered on your competitors and helped them along the way. Finally, be sure to mention any successful outcome.", "\"My current sales position is highly commission based, so my colleagues and I are quite competitive. Despite being competitive, we have a great work environment where we help each other when someone is struggling to meet their quota. We coach each other on sales techniques and share success stories. The result has been a positive work environment with healthy competition.\"", "\"One of the most competitive work situations I have experienced was driving a sales team to perform beyond quota.  We collaborated to come up with creative goal setting approaches, and our leadership team created recognition incentives to encourage strong performance along the way. It was a challenge, but we beat our all of our competition and made it happen!\""]}, {"topic": "Hospitality", "question": "Because of the nature of our business, we will ask to conduct a complete background check before hiring you at Company ABC. Are you willing to comply?", "answers": ["Are there any reasons why you could not perform the full function of this role? This question is the best time to disclose if you have a criminal record. Full disclosure may not make you exempt from employment with Company ABC - they may need to understand the charge and assess the risk.", "\"I am more than willing to comply with a background check; however, I will disclose to you that I have a mark on my record from a marijuana possess charge 12 years ago. I was a teenager at the time and regret that choice. It's best you know from me as opposed to finding out through a background check.\"", "\"I have a clean record and am happy to comply with any background checks you require. Would you like for me to obtain a police check for you this week?\""]}, {"topic": "Hospitality", "question": "The internet is constantly changing the conversation between Company ABC and our customers. What are your thoughts on the use of social media marketing platforms such as Facebook, Twitter, and Instagram?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know that you are savvy when it comes to the reach of online marketing. How aware are you that every move you make can be quickly scrutinized and immediately commented on, online? Talk about how you have seen social media marketing affect your current or previous employers.", "\"I see that Company ABC has a strong social media platform. You are very engaged with your followers and commenters. I feel that social media marketing has influenced companies to react faster and more openly to customer complaints - which is great. I am 100% on board with where social media marketing is taking the hospitality industry, and I think that Company ABC is doing a great job with online brand management.\"", "\"I think that social media, like all things, can have a positive side, and a negative side. If social media marketing is managed very diligently, I believe it's a great tool to converse with clients and customers in a fast and effective way.\""]}, {"topic": "Hospitality", "question": "Tell me about your exposure to hospitality related software and technology.", "answers": ["No matter your function with Company ABC, chances are, you will need to learn their internal software and technology. Ask the interviewer which systems they use and then discuss how they may be similar to the programs with which you are already familiar.", "\"I have been exposed to a few Point of Sale and Booking Systems that sound similar to what you are using here at Company ABC. I am tech savvy and am confident that I could pick up on your technology very quickly.\"", "\"Could you tell me which programs and software you use? I have used a variety of hospitality related software and technology, so I am confident in my ability to learn your programs quickly.\"", "\"I am familiar with Microsoft programming: outlook, excel, word processing, acrobat, and most computer programs,  HOTSOS, and OSHA regulations.\"", "Excellent! You provide a nice, detailed overview. To go the extra mile, you could also ask which software/technology is used in this particular role, and offer to begin learning.", "\"I am familiar with Microsoft programs such as Outlook, Excel, Word, and Acrobat. I also have training in HOTSOS and OSHA regulations. Could you share with me the programs used in this role? I would be happy to gain a head start in training myself on how to use them.\""]}, {"topic": "Hospitality", "question": "At Company ABC we have many strong competitors. In your opinion, how do we stand out from the crowd?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know that you have researched Company ABC and that you have an understanding of what makes them the best in their industry! List a couple of ways that you feel Company ABC stands out from their competitors. You can find ideas on the company website or online review sites.", "\"When I did an online search for Company ABC, I noticed that your reviews are much more positive than your competitors' reviews. Many of your customers mentioned that you stand out by way of excellent customer service and competitive pricing. I was quite impressed with what I read. Obviously Company ABC is a top choice for many.\"", "\"I think that Company ABC stands out from the crowd because of your strong branding message. Your customers know what to expect when they walk in, and you seem always to match or exceed those expectations.\"", "\"I have been researching other companies versus ABC, and I am quite impressed to say ABC is at the top of this list in satisfied customers and sales!\"", "Good! You seem well prepared to add in your own research, and specifics when the time comes."]}, {"topic": "Hospitality", "question": "At Company ABC many of our positions require you to wear a uniform to work. Are you willing to comply?", "answers": ["Many hospitality based companies will require you to wear a uniform. This decision can also be for security reasons or to help customers be able to identify you better. It is okay to ask to see the outfit before you agree to wear it. If you need any alterations to the uniform for social, religious, or gender reasons - you have the right to ask!", "\"I can understand why Company ABC requires a uniform from most employees. I have seen your uniforms, and they seem very comfortable, and the colors are great. I do wear a hijab so can you please confirm that your uniform allows for that?\"", "\"I have seen your uniforms and am 100% comfortable with that. I've had a dress code for work the last ten years and quite enjoy taking the guesswork out of dressing for work. In addition to being more professional, I believe that uniforms create a better sense of unity in the workplace.\"", "\"Most definitely.  You have an image you want to be portrayed, and I fill a uniform is entirely appropriate.   Also, it allows me extra time before work, not worrying about what to wear!   (Smile)\""]}, {"topic": "Hospitality", "question": "Who would you say inspires you?", "answers": ["Your life's inspiration can come from a book, a mentor, your family, a celebrity, author - literally anyone! Talk to the interviewer about who has inspired your life and why.", "\"I find inspiration in a variety of people and things. I would have to say that the person who has most greatly inspired me has been my grandmother. She always had a smile on her face no matter how hard she worked and she loved everyone. She was well respected and always gave more than she received. I try to live like her as much as I can.\"", "\"My previous manager was a huge inspiration to me. Her passion for this industry was motivating and put the fire in me to climb the ladder in my career.\""]}, {"topic": "Hospitality", "question": "Give me an example of a time when you went above and beyond.", "answers": ["Display to the interviewer that you can do more than just the bare minimum. Show that you can react appropriately when you see that your employer has a need that goes beyond your usual day-to-day expectations.", "\"Last week I noticed that my manager had not completed the schedule for the following week. Some of the staff were complaining that they didn't have their work schedule yet. Rather than going to my manager with the complaint, I offered to take on some of her workload so that she would have the time to complete the schedule. We worked together for a couple of overtime hours that day and were able to catch her up on everything. It felt good to help.\"", "\"I enjoy going above and beyond in my work.  In my last position, I regularly called customers to check in and see how they were doing, even if there was no news or issues with our service to discuss.  I believe going above and beyond for customers is what kept them loyal to us.\""]}, {"topic": "Hospitality", "question": "Tell me about a time when you had to encourage a fellow team member. How was your encouragement received?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know that you can successfully motivate others without it coming across as condescending. For this question, use a scenario when your encouragement was well received and resulted in a positive change or outcome.", "\"Our business development lead was stressing out last month because she was only 88% to quota with just two days left in the month. I sat with her after work, and we brainstormed some great ideas to implement for quick results. She ended up closing the month at 104% and had an amazing ramp up to the next month. I believe that encouragement can come in many forms. In this instance, she just needed someone to bounce ideas off of!\"", "\"A teammate was going to quit due to various frustrations. By putting SMART goals into place that would allow him to understand how he'd get to hit his targets, he changed his attitude at work and ultimately received a promotion. It was great to see him turn around so well.\""]}, {"topic": "Hospitality", "question": "At Company ABC there are many internal growth opportunities. What does your ideal career path with Company ABC look like?", "answers": ["Have you taken a look at the other career opportunities listed on Company ABC website? Before your interview, be sure to research the types of opportunities present at Company ABC. Do any of those positions catch your eye? Dig a bit deeper and find out what it takes to land a role like that! Be prepared to discuss your findings with the interviewer.", "\"I would love to see myself grow into a management opportunity with Company ABC down the road. I saw a job posting for a Hospitality Manager and would like to learn more from you on how I can realistically achieve this type of position.\"", "\"Being on the front-lines of customer service has been a gratifying part of my career; however, when I complete my Human Resources degree, I would like to find a position within your Corporate office, working on policy and procedures. That is where my true passion is.\""]}, {"topic": "Hospitality", "question": "Have you progressed in your career as you have expected?", "answers": ["Career progression can be a touchy subject, especially if you feel that your career hasn't progressed as well as you would have liked. Talk to the interviewer about your career progression and what you would like to see in the future.", "\"Overall, my career has progressed a touch slower than I would have liked. I have held a couple of positions that didn't offer the growth and learning that I was expecting; however, I have bounced back nicely. I feel that this particular position would take my career exactly where it should be.\"", "\"I am satisfied with the pace my career has taken when it comes to growth and opportunity. I have always tried to grow at a rate that will challenge me without skipping important learning steps along the way. I believe it is a big career mistake to skip steps to get ahead, without first earning the knowledge and expertise.\""]}, {"topic": "Hospitality", "question": "When have you worked amongst a diverse group of people?", "answers": ["Are you accustomed to working with a very large or diverse team of individuals? Assure the interviewer that you can handle an environment that offers diversity.", "\"I have worked with diverse groups of people most of my career, including my time in University. I am most comfortable, and happy, in this type of environment because it offers a great learning opportunity.\"", "\"The hospitality industry is probably one of the most diverse work environments you can find. I think diversity in the workplace is a must-have because it creates a company culture of understanding and tolerance. My entire career has been in the hospitality industry so I can safely say that I am well accustomed to differences in the workplace, and I welcome the diversity.\""]}, {"topic": "Hospitality", "question": "At Company ABC we believe in the continued education and training of our employees. If you could choose any area to expand your knowledge, which would you choose?", "answers": ["Discuss with the interviewer the ways that you would expand your industry knowledge and skills if given a chance. Be sure to express your interest in continued education and training.", "\"I am always happy and willing to expand my knowledge when it comes to sales and service in the hospitality industry. I would be especially interested in expanding my skills in strategic prospecting if given the opportunity.\"", "\"Although I am always eager to learn new skills, I haven't given that a lot of thought lately. Do you have any suggestions related to this role? What initially comes to mind, for me, is to gain additional knowledge in cold calling.\""]}, {"topic": "Hospitality", "question": "At Company ABC we prefer to hire those with a business, hospitality, or tourism related diploma or degree. Walk me through your post-secondary education. How has it prepared you for this role?", "answers": ["Your post-secondary education is on your resume; however, the interviewer would like for you to go into further detail. Discuss how your post-secondary education has prepared you for a role with Company ABC. If you do not have any formal post-secondary education, you can refer to your previous work experience or related on-the-job training.", "\"I have a Diploma in Travel and Tourism from Reeves College. This post-secondary experience was very positive, and I was able to learn the hospitality industry inside and out. My favorite course from the program was Marketing and Business Management.  I believe this course gave me a keen eye for the large, and small, ways that I can make a positive change. I look forward to applying that knowledge to this role with Company ABC.\"", "\"Although my related training is all on-the-job training, I am confident that I will exceed your expectations in this role with Company ABC. I bring five years of similar experience from my previous role. That company was particularly strong when it came to their training resources, so I am fully equipped and trained to perform well in this role.\""]}, {"topic": "Hospitality", "question": "Are you currently interviewing with any direct competitors of Company ABC?", "answers": ["It is always best, to be honest, and answer this question with full disclosure in mind. The interviewer is asking this question because they want to know how quickly they need to move to avoid you being scooped by a competitor! Always let the interviewer know that you are actively looking but be sure to reiterate why Company ABC is your top choice. Feel free to ask the interviewer about their hiring timeline as well!", "\"I am active in my job search and have targeted companies similar to Company ABC. Currently, I am in first interview stages with two other organizations. I am hoping to have an offer of employment as soon as possible; however, I am holding out for the perfect opportunity. This role with Company ABC sounds like a fantastic fit for me. When are you hoping to have a decision made?\"", "\"I am selective about where I interview. I chose to apply with Company ABC because you are the best in your business! I am eager to make a move but will not take a position that does not feel like a perfect fit. Do you have a timeline for your hiring decision?\""]}, {"topic": "Hospitality", "question": "At Company ABC we put our customers needs first. What is your customer service philosophy?", "answers": ["Assure the interviewer that you will honor the customer service values at Company ABC. If you take the time to read through their website, you will likely come across a few critical statements on their customer service values. Refer to those particular keywords when answering this question.", "\"I read on the Company ABC website that you continue to be a leader in your industry because of your commitment to bringing the most innovative products and experiences to your customers. This aligns really well with my customer service philosophy. I believe in keeping customers engaged through a seamless and unique experience every time they visit.\"", "\"My customer service philosophy is always to be honest with the customer. I know that Company ABC puts a lot of focus on integrity and honesty, so I believe that our values align well.\""]}, {"topic": "Hospitality", "question": "Working in hospitality can be a thankless job. How can we continue to motivate you to work hard for Company ABC even on the more challenging days?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know how Company ABC can continue to motivate you, even on those days where you may feel like quitting. Retention is vital to Company ABC. Help them learn how they can best retain you. What are your motivators?", "\"Words of encouragement motivate me. If you see me doing something right - even if it is small - tell me that you noticed. I don't need every day to run 100% smoothly, but I sure like to feel appreciated by my employer.\"", "\"I don't mind a good challenge as long as I feel that my performance is making a difference. Because I have a bit of a competitive streak, you can keep my motivated by including me in the conversation regarding the difference I am making through my work and tenacity.\""]}, {"topic": "Hospitality", "question": "Due to the nature of our business at Company ABC, your priorities can change on a dime. Are you able to change focus quickly or does this bother you?", "answers": ["Assure the interviewer that you are quick on your feet and can handle the variety of tasks that will come your way at Company ABC. Give an example of a time when you have had your priorities change on a dime. How did you handle it and what was the outcome?", "\"In my current position I am on call quite often, so I am used to having my schedule and plans change. When this happens, even though it may be frustrating at times, it always works out in the end. I don't mind changing focus when I'm needed.\"", "\"I maintain a stronger focus when able to start and complete a project in one shot; however, if it is required of me to change priorities from time-to-time, I am okay with that as well.\"", "\"Yes, I look forward to a fast-paced environment with challenges.\"", "This is a good start! It would be great to add in some detail on fast-paced environments you have worked in before."]}, {"topic": "Hospitality", "question": "Tell me about a time when you discovered a problem and went beyond regular expectations to fix it.", "answers": ["Your innovative approach may be exciting and unconventional, but can you implement it realistically? Ideas are one thing, but putting them into practice and providing measurable results is where you can add genuine value. \n\nThink of a time you worked long hours and made sacrifices to overcome a challenging problem. Demonstrate your impact and the significance of your solution.", "\"When I worked as an admin assistant at my last job, I was in charge of purchasing. I noticed we had been spending quite a bit of money on paper and plastic-ware. I compared the cost of disposables to the cost of buying permanent dishes and utensils for the kitchen. It turned out we were able to save the company hundreds of dollars each year by simply investing in dishes and silverware!\"", "\"I had a staff member who was stealing supplies. Rumors were going around that she was dishonest; however, there was no evidence. I carefully waited and, after two days, the rumored infractions were caught on camera. At that point, I was able to terminate her employment. I went beyond regular expectations by gaining evidence before terminating her. I knew this would prevent a human resources issue down the road, and it also saved my company from having to pay this employee any severance pay.\""]}, {"topic": "Hospitality", "question": "Tell me about a time when you made a suggestion requesting change in an organization.", "answers": ["In addition to being able to handle change, can you also recognize when change is required and be confident enough to present that to your organization? Talk to the interviewer about a time when you were able to suggest a change in the workplace.", "\"Last year when I was managing front-of-house I noticed a pretty solid opportunity for us to save on overtime hours. I created a presentation and gave it to my manager who took it to upper management. The changes were implemented, and I was very proud of the suggestion that I made.\"", "\"I made a recommendation, in my current role, for a change in vendors when it came to our office supplies. I noticed that our current vendor was becoming increasingly slack with incorrect billing, missing items, and even additional surcharges. I sourced another three options, all local, and presented my findings to my supervisor. We ended up choosing one of the vendors that I found.\""]}, {"topic": "Hospitality", "question": "Rate your communication skills from 1-10 with proper examples backing your given rating.", "answers": ["On a scale of 1-10, how skilled are you in communication? Why did you choose that particular rating for yourself?", "\"I rate my communication skills as a 9/10 as I will, on occasion, have times when I am not as clear as I would like to be. My supervisor and co-workers will attest to my clear and concise communication skills. Because I am an open leader, my team will let me know if I need to clarify anything.\"", "\"I will rate myself an eight because I value communication but, just like most people, I have things to learn. Some ways that I ensure clear communication are by utilizing multiple methods of delivering messages, and I give ample time for questions before implementing changes.\""]}, {"topic": "Hospitality", "question": "How do you like to encourage ideas in others?", "answers": ["Encouragement to others is a great skill to possess. Talk to the interviewer about your ability to encourage creative ideas in your team members.", "\"I like to encourage other people to be creative in their thinking and present ideas to the company, no matter how off the wall they may seem. Some of our most successful employees are ones who are confident in their ability to bring forward their unique ideas. I encourage participation through an open door policy and strong praise for those who show initiative.\"", "\"I encourage people to tap into the best parts of themselves. It helps to ask probing questions to get them to generate ideas on their own. I have found that by painting a long-term vision for where I want to go, my team will often jump in with creative solutions to get us there.\""]}, {"topic": "Hospitality", "question": "When have you created a new product or service?", "answers": ["Using your creative mind, have you ever introduced an employer to a new product or service opportunity? Talk to the interviewer about a time when you have created a new product or service.", "\"In my previous role I was fortunate enough to introduce my company to the idea of a gold level service where, in addition to our general customer service, we added on additional options. Our customer base responded very positively, and we kept the program running for a few years.\"", "\"Growing up, a lot of my neighbors had pets.  I started a neighborhood dog walking, sitting, and vacation service in high school. I made some money and helped my neighbors enjoy their vacations. In my adult life, I continue to seek out opportunities to help others with their day-to-day needs.\""]}, {"topic": "Hospitality", "question": "How do you handle stress?", "answers": ["Are you someone who can handle stress on the job? How do you manage the stressful times? Talk to the interviewer about your ability to control pressure in the workplace.", "\"I handle stress very well, and when you call my references, they will attest to this fact. When I am under pressure on the job, I focus on the task at hand and make sure not to get distracted. Staying on deadline is very helpful, and I will delegate when necessary to alleviate some stress.\"", "\"Stress is part of any demanding job, and I embrace it to the fullest.  I take good care of myself and prioritize my workload to maintain a healthy balance in my stress levels.\""]}, {"topic": "Hospitality", "question": "Tell me more about your most recent position and how it relates to this particular role.", "answers": ["Outline, for the interviewer, the similarities between your most recent job and this particular position. It is up to you to display to the hiring manager that you are the right fit for them.", "\"In my most recent position I had many related responsibilities such as client relationships, customer service, and cold calling. The job descriptions are very similar; however, your role is a slight step up in responsibilities which would provide the growth that I am looking for.\"", "\"I am performing a role very similar to this one at my current employer. However, this role would be a step up for me.  After years of working in the hospitality, I am ready for the challenge of leading a team.\"", "\"Housekeeping Supervisor- Any position in the hospitality industry starts with wanting the best for your customers.  My last position allowed me not only to accomplish this but to educate my staff of the same values.\"", "Great work! You do a nice job tying in your current role and responsibilities with the role for which you are interviewing."]}, {"topic": "Hospitality", "question": "When have you spoken up for cause, knowing that it would directly look unfavorable on you, because it was the right thing to do?", "answers": ["Every manager wants a team player who will not resist company policy or argue about every detail of the workload. However; time may come when you need to speak up about something, and it may not look the best on you. Talk to the interviewer about a time that this may have happened to you on the job.", "\"For the most part, my company abides by all labor regulations. In the case of overtime, they did not abide by the regulations, and I had to speak up for my team. The company was not happy about it because it cost them a lot of money but, in the end, they realized that they were in error.\"", "\"I spoke up to our management team regarding mandatory overtime by the back-of-house staff. I did not believe that the expectations were balanced, so I chose to speak up. I remained respectful, of course, and supported my thoughts with facts and truths. They heard me out, and some significant changes were made afterward.\"", "\"I stood up for my crew member when the other supervisor instructed the crew member to go outside and clean the pool area.  It was at peak temperature of 115 degrees outside.  My crew member was wearing a long sleeve black shirt, black pants, and he had long hair.  I told him not to do it because I did not want him to suffer a heat stroke.  I instructed him to wait until later that evening to complete the task.\"", "This example is perfect and showcases the fact that you are an aware and caring leader. Good job."]}, {"topic": "Hospitality", "question": "What attracts you the most to this particular position?", "answers": ["The perfect fit needs to go both ways. Assure the interviewer that you see this role as a stable fit for you and discuss the reasons why. Be specific.", "\"What attracts me most to this position is the fact that your organization puts so much effort into professional development for your employees. It's awe-inspiring to me.\"", "\"I am most attracted to this particular position with Company ABC because it is a job function that I am familiar with; yet in an industry that is new to me. I look forward to learning more about the hospitality industry.\""]}, {"topic": "Hospitality", "question": "What are you reading right now?", "answers": ["Do you feed your mind on a regular basis? What kind of literature do you prefer and why? Talk to the interviewer about a book that you are currently reading. If you are not now reading a book - talk about one that has impacted you the most.", "\"Currently I am reading 'Ego is the Enemy' by Ryan Holiday. It is a book about ambition, resilience, and success. I feel that every professional should read it - it comes highly recommended.\"", "\"I love to read and usually have two or three books on the go at a time. One is generally based on the hospitality industry, one will be fiction, and the other will be based on business strategies or self-development. The most recent book I finished was \"Big Magic\" by Elizabeth Gilbert.\""]}, {"topic": "Hospitality", "question": "What is your current salary?", "answers": ["A potential employer will often base their offer on your current salary. You should be transparent about your most recent earnings and be prepared to back up any salary requests.", "\"I am currently earning a base salary of $78,000 plus a car allowance of $900/month and health benefits. I am looking for a competitive salary in my next position.\"", "\"I am currently making $50,000 per year with two bonus opportunities.  I am looking for compensation that is aligned with the role and provides an opportunity for growth.\""]}, {"topic": "Media", "question": "Of all the media solutions we provide at Company ABC, which do you know the best?", "answers": ["It is imperative to thoroughly research Company ABC before you go in for your interview. Be sure to look carefully through the 'About Us' section on their website as well as anything to do with their clients or recent projects.", "\"I researched Company ABC a lot before coming here today and see that you recently won an award for being the top (specific specialty) in the industry. This area is one that I specialize in as well. Because of my previous achievements in (specific specialty), I feel that I could make an impact right away.\"", "\"I would say that, without a doubt, visual design is my strongest area of expertise when it comes to media solutions. I have many other areas of strength, such as A and B; however, this is my stand-out skill.\""]}, {"topic": "Media", "question": "What is your favorite publication, and why?", "answers": ["Trick question! If you are interviewing with a company involved in the publication, you will certainly want to mention that you are a fan of their work. No need to say they are your favorite (if they aren't) but at least give them a nod.", "\"I read a wide array of publications and yours, XYZ Magazine, is always in the mix. I especially appreciate your approach on political pieces.\"", "\"I have a range of publications that I rotate. Your publication, ABC, is always in the mix. Among my favorites are also X, Y, and Z. I would love to learn about other options as well. May I ask what your favorite publications are?\""]}, {"topic": "Media", "question": "What work situations excite and motivate you?", "answers": ["It is essential, for your success, that the hiring manager knows how to keep you motivated and excited to come to work every day. Share with the interviewer what they could do to ensure that you are happy and productive.", "\"I am most motivated, on the job, when tasks are organized, and the vibe is positive. I value strong teamwork and good leadership.\"", "\"I love to feel like I am making a difference in the workplace so what excites me most is the idea that I could train and mentor junior employees while growing my leadership capabilities at the same time.\""]}, {"topic": "Media", "question": "Tell me about an organization or group outside of work that you contributed to.", "answers": ["Many hiring managers will choose one candidate over another because of their volunteer experience. They feel that it shows strong character and selflessness - all qualities that make a great employee. Talk to the interviewer about your willingness to give back to your community in some form of volunteerism. If you do not have formal volunteer experience, you can draw on things you do in your spare time to assist friends, family, or even your current employer. \n\nIf you do have volunteer experience: \"For the past eight months, I have volunteered every Wednesday evening at our local animal shelter. I will help with grooming the animals, feeding them, and walking them. It's been an enjoyable experience and rewarding at the same time.\"", "\"For the past eight months, I have volunteered every Wednesday evening at our local animal shelter. I will help with grooming the animals, feeding them, and walking them. It's been an enjoyable experience and rewarding at the same time.\"", "If you do not have volunteer experience: \"I have not formally volunteered in these most recent years, however; I spend a lot of time helping my sister who is a single mom. I will babysit on weekends, cook dinners for her and drive the kids to appointments when necessary. I feel that it is imperative to take care of the needs of the family.\""]}, {"topic": "Media", "question": "What accomplishment do you believe was the most difficult for you to achieve?", "answers": ["Being able to face a challenge or stressful situation, and still gain some accomplishment, in the end, is very satisfying. Talk to the interviewer about a time when you were able to come out on top despite being faced with an obstacle.", "\"In my career, so far, I feel that the most difficult accomplishment for me to achieve were the three back-to-back promotions in my current company. Because promotions are granted based on results, I had to put in a lot of overtime hours, and hustle, to get there.\"", "\"The most challenging accomplishment I achieved was the fluid communication created in my current team. When I first started, communication was so poor that it greatly affected the company's profits. By creating this smooth communication, we were able to increase sales by 155% in the first year.\""]}, {"topic": "Media", "question": "What do you know about our company culture?", "answers": ["Company culture and fit is a crucial factor when considering a career move. Assure the interviewer that you have put thought, research, and consideration of how the company culture will work for you.", "\"I have researched your company through your social media channels and on glassdoor.com. Your employees have great things to say, and overall it seems that you have fun while you work. I am looking forward to joining an organization, like yours, that is upbeat and thoughtful with an eye on helping the community at the same time.\"", "\"I read many positive reviews online about your organization and company culture.  You offer great incentives to keep people motivated, and it seems to be the type of fast-paced environment that values innovation and performance.\""]}, {"topic": "Media", "question": "Tell me about your experiences giving presentations in front of large groups.", "answers": ["Public speaking can be intimidating so assure the interviewer that you are capable of communicating well in front of large groups. Have you taken any courses or training in public speaking? Perhaps you have so much experience that it comes second nature. Assure the interviewer that you are capable of giving presentations.", "\"In my past two roles I have been responsible for regularly presenting to my team of 43 staff as well as to our entire warehouse team of over 200. I have taken a couple of Toastmasters sessions which helped a great deal. I am a confident public speaker.\"", "\"I do not have a lot of experience in presenting to large groups. Perhaps, 4-6 people at most. I am a confident public speaker and am sure that I could present in front of many people.\""]}, {"topic": "Media", "question": "What are your thoughts on the way media is rated for the public (IE: PG, 14A, NR, Mature)?", "answers": ["Media ratings have changed a great deal over the years, and the interviewer would like to know your thoughts on this. Be sure to keep your answer productive and thoughtful.", "\"Media ratings have most definitely loosened over the years. What used to be rated 14A is now often classified as PG. I feel this is because our kids and youth are exposed to so much more now than we ever were as kids and we are becoming desensitized. I do wish that some guidelines would remain tighter, especially surrounding violent content.\"", "\"Because I am newer to this industry, I would need to conduct more analysis on media ratings before I could give you a fully researched answer. With that said, I feel that the majority of media I am exposed to seem to be rated adequately, and clearly. I think it's important for viewers and consumers to easily see ratings before making their decision on whether or not it's appropriate for them.\""]}, {"topic": "Media", "question": "If Company ABC hired you today, what would you accomplish first?", "answers": ["When you start a new position, it is essential to set a goal on how you will make a positive impact quickly after being hired. Tell the interviewer what your impact goal is, should you be the successful candidate.", "\"When we were speaking earlier, about sales targets in this position, you mentioned that most new sales professionals hit their KPI's after 120 days. If hired today, my goal would be to exceed my KPI's after the first 90 days. I plan to make a positive impact very quickly.\"", "\"If hired today, I would start with analyzing all quantifiable data from the last month, quarter, and year to identify any bottlenecks or shortfalls and set a plan to correct them.\""]}, {"topic": "Media", "question": "Market research is important to Company ABC in order to help us understand where to take our business in the years to come. Rate your research skills from 1-10. Do you enjoy conducting research?", "answers": ["In the media industry, research and reliable sources are everything. Assure the interviewer that you are capable of conducting robust and dependable research. Draw on your positive references when answering this question.", "\"One of the reasons why I would love to work for Company ABC is because of your solid reputation for reputable sources and research. In my previous positions, I have always been recognized for my great research skills. When you call my references, they will attest to this as well. There is always room for improvement so I would rate myself as an 8.5 out of 10 for research capabilities.\"", "\"When it comes to research capabilities, I am most definitely a 10/10. An eleven even, if that is allowed! I love researching a large range of products and am very data and analytically minded.\""]}, {"topic": "Media", "question": "Walk me through your experience in the television and/or radio industry.", "answers": ["Take a few minutes to walk the interviewer through your resume. Highlight any particular experience you may have with television and radio. Be concise and be sure to avoid speaking poorly of any previous employers and experiences.", "\"I began my career in media in a volunteer role with my local television station. From there, I started to assist with writing broadcast scripts. I left that role to attend university and recently graduated with my communications degree. I am now looking for my first opportunity in media, and very much look forward to seeing my career grow with Company ABC.\"", "\"I have been working in the television and radio industry for the past eight years. After graduating with my degree in Media Studies and Mass Media, I joined our local radio station as a content writer. From there, I took on a role as a junior editor; then a team leader for a small team of editors. At this point, I am now looking for an opportunity to grow which is why I applied for this role with Company ABC. I love this industry and look forward to continuing my success here.\""]}, {"topic": "Media", "question": "When you suffer a setback, how does that emotionally affect you and your work?", "answers": ["Everyone handles the stress and disappointment of setbacks differently. Discuss with the interviewer how you typically cope with delays in the workplace.", "\"Experiencing a setback is always disappointing, and can be a bit disheartening, but I understand that it happens from time to time. If I experience a major setback, I will take a few moments to debrief with my manager and discuss what I could have done differently. Then, I move on!\"", "\"I expect setbacks in this industry and have become accustomed to them happening. Call it par for the course with working in media. When I encounter a huge setback I will take a few moments to assess the damage, then make a plan with my team on how to proceed.\""]}, {"topic": "Media", "question": "Do you prefer to be behind the scenes or in the limelight?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know more about your personality so they can place you in the correct job function. Would you consider yourself an entertainer or more of a worker-bee? Perhaps you are a blend of both!", "\"I can change from enjoying the limelight to being behind the scenes, simply depending on the type of project. I would say that I am a healthy balance of both; however, I do find myself in the limelight a bit more often. This is because I naturally take on leadership roles and am skilled when it comes to public speaking.\"", "\"My instinct is to be behind the scenes whenever possible. Although I am very outgoing, I often prefer to do the background work, like research and data analysis, and then pass my findings along to someone who is more of a natural in the limelight.\""]}, {"topic": "Media", "question": "In your opinion, what is the most influential form of media today?", "answers": ["Have a meaningful conversation with the interviewer on media influence. With so many forms of media out there, which do you feel is the most influential at the moment? Be sure to back your answer.", "\"I feel that the most influential form of media today is social media and online content. As a whole, the human race wants fast, easy to consume, entertainment news. Our rate of consumption is unprecedented, and the fastest way to access it is through online content sharing.\"", "\"There are many important forms of media today - so many, in fact, that people seem to be getting overwhelmed. I would still say that traditional media, in the form of television and the daily news, is at the top when it comes to the number of people influenced and the quality of the content being distributed.\""]}, {"topic": "Media", "question": "What are your 3 favorite forms of entertainment?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know the types of media and entertainment that you enjoy consuming on a regular basis. Talk to the interviewer about your favorite forms of entertainment and be sure to include why they are your favorite.", "\"My favorite forms of entertainment have always been reality tv, podcasts, and celebrity-based news. I have always wanted to become a gossip columnist and find that these forms of entertainment spark my creativity and keep me informed on trends in the media.\"", "\"There are so many great forms of entertainment media available to us. I am more traditional and would say that my favorite forms still include print media, documentaries, and podcasts that focus on economics and business.\""]}, {"topic": "Media", "question": "What are your career goals in the next 3-5 years with Company ABC?", "answers": ["Assure the interviewer that you are interested in forging a long-term career with them by discussing the career path you foresee if hired. What are your career goals and how do you hope to achieve them, with Company ABC?", "\"In the next few years I would like to move into a more serious leadership function. In my current company, there is little room for growth which is why I feel that working for Company ABC would fit into my long-term career goals. I want to work for you and grow into a leadership role with your organization.\"", "\"5 years from now, I would like to be supervising or managing a team of my own. I feel like I am progressing at a rate that will make this a possibility.\""]}, {"topic": "Media", "question": "The media industry is fast moving and ever-changing. How do you stay on top of changes and trends?", "answers": ["With the fast pace of online content, all forms of media must move quickly to be the first and most reliable source of news and entertainment. Assure the interviewer that you can remain on top of trends in your industry.", "\"Trends and stories are constantly changing, so my favorite sources for industry-related content comes from a variety of online sources such as A, B, and C. These sources are consistent and reliable.\"", "\"I think it's important to stay on top of trends on a regular basis, so I do subscribe to a few podcasts, and I also have industry related google alerts set up. Which are your favorite ways to stay on top of media-related trends and changes?\""]}, {"topic": "Media", "question": "In your opinion, what is the future of local radio?", "answers": ["Talk to the interviewer about your opinion on local radio, and it's future. Remain positive and avoid bashing any forms of media or sounding like a doomsayer.", "\"Local radio has changed a great deal over the years, especially with the launch of services such as Sirius Radio and other satellite services. It certainly hasn't made it obsolete as many predicted. In fact, I think the introduction of competition can be a good thing. It forces local radio to become more progressive and engaging. I believe this trend will continue for many years to come.\"", "\"I recently read an article that radio may be obsolete in the nearer future because of its inability to connect with Generation Z. This generation makes up nearly half of all consumers in the United States. So, the future of radio may be grim if we cannot find a way to make connections with the modern consumer.\""]}, {"topic": "Media", "question": "How do you think that online media has changed traditional print and broadcast media approaches in the past 10 years?", "answers": ["This industry is ever-changing, and all types of media outlets have been scrambling to keep up with the introduction of online media. Talk to the interviewer about your insights when it comes to the changes you have witnessed in traditional media since the introduction of online media.", "\"Online media has changed the way we digest information. Most people look for content online because it's fast and we can read the opinions of others which helps us to form our own. This content is both convenient and dangerous at times as it doesn't necessarily promote free thought. I think that traditional print media has become lighter and more entertainment-driven because of this.\"", "\"I believe that online media has rapidly increased the amount of content that we feel we need in a day. Where it used to be that our parents would watch or read the local news once every morning or evening, we are now constantly logging in, and looking for updates on stories that may not even directly affect us. This response means that newspapers are often struggling with sales, and we have global 24/7 news channels.\""]}, {"topic": "Media", "question": "Do you feel performance should be rewarded over experience?", "answers": ["Do you feel that you should be paid based on tenure, or results? Discuss this with the interviewer and back your answer with an example, if possible.", "\"I feel that employees should be paid, and rewarded, based on their performance. A new employee would find motivation through being rewarded for performance, and it encourages a healthy competition with tenured employees.\"", "\"I feel both performance and experience should be equally rewarded and weighted.\""]}, {"topic": "Media", "question": "What are your salary expectations?", "answers": ["The best way to discuss your salary expectations is to use your current earnings as an example. Be open, and honest. Transparency is the best choice when salary based questions arise.", "\"Currently, I earn a base salary of $45,000 per year plus a potential 20% annual bonus. Last year my earnings were $52,000, and I would like to stay in the same range or slightly higher.\"", "\"I am currently making $100,000 per year with two bonus opportunities.  I am looking for compensation that is aligned with the role and provides an opportunity for growth.\""]}, {"topic": "Media", "question": "Tell me about a time when you, or a group that you were a part of, were in danger of missing a deadline. What did you do?", "answers": ["This question is designed to learn how well you work under pressure. When choosing an example to share with the interviewer, avoid selecting a time that you were in danger of missing the deadline because of poor planning on your part such as procrastination. Instead, choose a situation that was out of your control. \n\nFirst, start by giving the interviewer an overview of the situation, explaining how much time you had to complete the assignment and why you were in danger of missing the deadline.  \n\nNext, tell the interviewer that you realized how urgent the situation was, and instead of getting worked up about it, you came up with a game plan to conquer the assignment by the deadline.\n\nLastly, explain how you made your plan of attack, pulled in additional people to help if necessary, and met your deadline.", "\"My team and I recently were under a deadline to complete a global employee satisfaction survey.  Our deadline was set to execute the project from start to finish within six weeks.  During weekly status updates, we came across two roadblocks that were going to prevent us from accomplishing this.  Global customs would take six weeks to ship the surveys in and out of the facility.  We came up with a solution to email the surveys and still include the coding that would catalog the results by location and department, while still meeting our deadline. It was our transparency in communications and collaborative work environment that helped us meet a deadline to deliver the results to the leadership team and organizational wide.\""]}, {"topic": "Media", "question": "The media industry is all about communication. At Company ABC, strong communication is at the forefront of what we do. How would you describe your communication skills? Rate your communication skills from 1-10.", "answers": ["In any media related position, you must be a clear and concise communicator. Talk to the interviewer about your communication style and how you feel it will work with the communication standards set by Company ABC.", "\"I would rate my communication skills as a 9 out of 10 because they are exceptional; yet, there is always room for improvement. I would describe my communication style as thorough, upbeat, yet concise. I firmly believe that my communication skills will meet the standards you have set at Company ABC.\"", "\"I will rate myself an 8.5 because I consider myself a strong communicator.  It is the foundation of all success in business.  I am always striving to be a better communicator, so I leave the rest of the scale as an aspirational measure.\""]}, {"topic": "Media", "question": "Tell me about an error or mistake you made because of a breakdown in communication from you or one of your team members.", "answers": ["On occasion, mistakes will happen, and communication will be broken. Talk to the interviewer about a time that this occurred in the workplace. How did you resolve the situation?", "\"I recall one instance where I misread an email from one of my subordinates. The punctuation was incorrect, and I read it in in a dire tone rather than in a positive one, as it was intended. After a tense conversation, the employee clarified her intention, and it seems I was mistaken. She and I agreed to exercise verbal communication on a regular basis to avoid a similar situation from happening again.\"", "\"We recently had a missing link in communications to one of our vendors, who we signed on to provide a large service.  They were not aware of a change in the agreement which cost the company wasted time, resources and money.  We were able to identify the breakdown in communication and change the process to ensure it does not happen again.\""]}, {"topic": "Media", "question": "How would you describe your relationship with your customers or clients?", "answers": ["Do you value your client and customer relationships? How do you nurture them to ensure that they are happy and continue to come back? Talk to the interviewer about your strategy for building strong customer and client relationships.", "\"My customer and client relationships are best described as open and honest. I believe that the more upfront and transparent you are with your clients, the more likely they are to return. I most definitely value my clients and am sure to nurture those relationships as much as possible.\"", "\"My relationships with my customers are the most important part of my job. If I could describe my relationships with them, I would say they are  transparent, professional, yet lighthearted when necessary.\""]}, {"topic": "Media", "question": "Outside of work, what type of creative activities do you like to pursue?", "answers": ["A genuinely creative minded person will have outside activities aside from what's happening in the workplace. Tell the interviewer about the variety of ways in which you express your creativity.", "\"Outside of work I like to attend dance classes and I also attend the odd paint and sip wine nights at a local wine shop. I also enjoy reading as a way of nurturing my creative side.\"", "\"I am very involved in volunteering, outside of work. I spend most of my time with my volunteer commitments and the rest of my time is spent working out or reading.\""]}, {"topic": "Media", "question": "How often do you take work home with you?", "answers": ["The majority of people will work overtime hours or take work home with them on occasion. Talk to the interviewer about how frequently you take your work home.", "\"I make sure to utilize my work hours very efficiently, so the only time that I take my work home is when there is an extremely stringent deadline. I would say that, overall, I take my work home maybe twice per month. It's all about being diligent with your time in the office!\"", "\"I take my work home with me whenever it is necessary. Some positions I have held, I work from home nearly every day. Other roles, such as my current position, I work from home just a couple of times per month.\""]}, {"topic": "Media", "question": "How do you determine priorities when you have multiple projects due?", "answers": ["When you feel torn between multiple projects or tasks, how do you decide which one needs your attention the most? Assure the interviewer that you can be diligent when it comes to assessing your priorities.", "\"I will determine which project requires my attention by the number of hours we are behind and then the project size. I am comfortable delegating tasks when needed, but I am also aware that these times will require an additional commitment of hours from me. Never have I under delivered on a deadline.\"", "\"Assuming that the projects have different stakeholders, I interview each to determine the value of increased productivity, morale or revenue, decreased costs, and the overall impact.\""]}, {"topic": "Media", "question": "What is your greatest weakness?", "answers": ["Pick a weakness that is not a core skill for this position. You can be candid in your answer; recognizing that you aren't great at something and acknowledging your need to improve.  Be sure to have an action plan in place for improving on this weakness. \n\nPerhaps you are watching TED talks to gain skills in a particular area, reading the latest-and-greatest book on the subject, or maybe you are taking a seminar at a nearby community center. We are all human with our weaknesses, so don't be afraid to share yours!", "\"I believe I could improve on some technical skills including Excel and PowerPoint. Currently I am at a beginner to intermediate level; however, I would be more comfortable at an advanced level. I have enrolled myself in an evening/weekend workshop for the next six weeks. We will see how stellar my skills are after that course!\"", "\"This is super cliche, but it's also true. I am not good at delegating to others. When I become submerged in a project, I don't like to give away any of the control. While this can be good, it can also definitely inhibit the outcome of the project and my growth as a team player and individual. I am currently working on this, as I know it is a deficit.\""]}, {"topic": "Media", "question": "Why do you think you will be successful in this role?", "answers": ["Rather than just sharing how you have gone above and beyond, focus on how your qualities will help you to meet and exceed expectations. Discuss the reasons why will you be great at this job. Talk about your qualifications and skills that will help you to do this job well. If you can, match your strengths to the requirements outlined in the job description.", "\"I know I will be successful in this role because I have been working in this industry for five years with great training and mentorship. I have a solid understanding of X, Y, and Z (skills listed in the job description). Also, I have all of my updated certifications as outlined in your job description. I am well-prepared for this next step in my career.\"", "\"I am prepared with experience, equipped with passion and opportunistic about making a valuable contribution to your organization's work through this role.\""]}, {"topic": "Resorts", "question": "Working in hospitality can be a thankless job. How can we continue to motivate you to work hard for Company ABC even on the more challenging days?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know how Company ABC can continue to motivate you, even on those days where you may feel like quitting. Retention is vital to Company ABC. Help them learn how they can best retain you. What are your motivators?", "\"Words of encouragement motivate me. If you see me doing something right - even if it is small - tell me that you noticed. I don't need every day to run 100% smoothly, but I sure like to feel appreciated by my employer.\"", "\"I don't mind a good challenge as long as I feel that my performance is making a difference. Because I have a bit of a competitive streak, you can keep my motivated by including me in the conversation regarding the difference I am making through my work and tenacity.\""]}, {"topic": "Resorts", "question": "How do you feel about performance incentives?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know if you are the type of employee to be motivated by financial incentives or rewards in the workplace. Resorts will often run internal contests for upselling guest amenities and services. If you are not incentive-driven, you can clarify for the interviewer the other ideas in which you are best motivated. Discuss any performance incentives you may have earned in the past.", "\"I think performance incentives are important for driving staff to get results.  For me, as a hospitality manager, I feel incentives give me some skin in the game and get my team engaged in making an impact on the resorts' desired results.\"", "\"I cannot say that I have been offered performance incentives in the past, but that sure sounds like a nice idea. I am a high-achiever, regardless of an incentive being present but it is nice to feel appreciated.\""]}, {"topic": "Resorts", "question": "Would you ever break the rules at Company ABC to make a guest happy?", "answers": ["Breaking the rules, and bending them, CAN be different from each other. Often, hotels and resorts are okay with you bending the rules to keep a customer happy. You need to know your audience, though! If Company ABC is very stringent when it comes to their policies and procedures, then approach this question with caution. If they are well known for being flexible, then you can indeed be more free with your answer.", "\"My current company is pretty strict with their policies, so I do not bend to make a customer happy, but I will escalate the issue to someone who has the seniority to decide that. I have read through your online policies and agree with Company ABC that it's important to offer some flex on policy, within reason of course.\"", "\"Policy and rules are not always strictly enforced in my current company. It isn't for lack of caring but the opposite. Our CEO knows that if we needed to bend a rule, it was for a good reason. With that said, I am comfortable following your policies because they are more than reasonable.\""]}, {"topic": "Resorts", "question": "What does hospitality mean to you?", "answers": ["The term hospitality refers to welcoming people to your place of business and making them feel at home by receiving them warmly and entertaining. The interviewer would like to see that you understand what it means to be hospitable and that you will greet their guests warmly, making them feel welcome during their stay. Discuss what hospitality means to you, and give an example of a time when you were hospitable.", "\"To me, hospitality means making every person feel welcome, and like there is nowhere else they should be. I make my guests and customers feel welcome by asking them what they would like to experience while on the resort, remembering their names, and getting to know their personal preferences.\"", "\"I have always believed that to be hospitable means to welcome people into your home, taking great care of them. While on vacation, Company ABC is the guests' home. So, the best way to be hospitable is to have food and drinks available, be ready to assist at any time, and get to know them.\""]}, {"topic": "Resorts", "question": "How does your post-secondary education relate to a career in the hospitality industry?", "answers": ["Company ABC may or may not specify a preferred degree in their job posting. Either way, the interviewer would like to see how your post-secondary education may relate to, or compliment, the position for which you are interested. Discuss the degree or diploma you may have. If you recall some of the related coursework, you can mention those classes as well. \n\nIf you do not have any post-secondary education, think back to any online classes you have taken, or on-the-job-training that could be transferable.", "\"I have a Bachelor's degree in Business Administration with a focus on the hospitality industry. My coursework included Human Resource Management within the hospitality industry as well as strategic management and operations management classes. I did exceptionally well in the operations management portion. Because of this focus, I feel very prepared for this role with Company ABC.\"", "\"Although I do not possess formal post-secondary education, I have received customer service training and attended a couple of Dale Carnegie sales courses. This education prepared me in a variety of topics such as building rapport, asking for the sale, and recognizing upselling opportunities.\""]}, {"topic": "Resorts", "question": "How would you react if a customer demanded early check-in service?", "answers": ["Early check-in is a common request in the resort industry. Sometimes a resort can accommodate this request and based on volume; sometimes it is not do-able for housekeeping to keep up. You can ask if Company ABC has a policy when it comes to early check-ins and late checkouts. Remember - the higher the occupancy, the more difficult it is for a resort to offer this service. Some resorts may monetize the option, charging an additional fee which may weed out the guests that genuinely need the service, versus those who do not.", "\"I read that Company ABC can offer early check-in service as long as the request occurs at the time of reservation. If a customer arrived early and demanded early check-in, I would, of course, see if we could accommodate. If we could not, I would give a viable timeline, offer to store their luggage, and direct them to the club lounge for a complimentary beverage.\"", "\"If a customer demanded early check-in, I would refer to the policies put in place by Company ABC. My initial instinct would be to allow this if it did not put a strain on housekeeping or other departments. Do you charge a fee for this type of service, upon booking?\""]}, {"topic": "Resorts", "question": "How would you react if a celebrity checked into our resort?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know that you would not turn into a total fan geek should a celebrity come for a stay at Company ABC. Stars are people too, and they need to know that they can have a relaxing stay, where their privacy is respected. Show the interviewer that you have the emotional maturity to respond professionally in this type of situation.", "\"I have lived in LA the past, and celebrity sightings are quite common. I know that everyone, no matter their status, deserves a great get-away where they feel they can relax. I would not bat an eye if a celeb checked into the resort. I would treat the person the same as any other guest.\"", "\"I read online that your resort has seen celebrities such as Selena Gomez, John Hamm, and even former president Obama. I would love to have the experience of checking a celebrity into the resort but, of course, would keep my composure on the outside! I know that everyone should feel safe and relaxed when they are away.\""]}, {"topic": "Resorts", "question": "Are you aware that there are sales goals and other important targets in this role with Company ABC?", "answers": ["Resorts and hotels may not seem like a 'salesy'environment; however, they are a business, and they will have important goals to reach. The interviewer would like to see that you are comfortable selling, upselling, and taking action to ensure that Company ABC hits and exceeds their important targets on a weekly or monthly basis. \n\nSome of the most common KPI's include: \n\n- Occupancy rates\n- Average income per room rental\n- Revenue per available room\n- Revenue per occupied room\n- Average spend per guest on food & beverage\n- Average spend per guest on gift shop items \n\nThere are many more KPI's tracked in the industry, which you will thoroughly be trained on when you start with Company ABC. Show the interviewer that you are able and willing to act as a salesperson and ambassador for Company ABC.", "\"I am more than happy to help Company ABC achieve their sales goals and targets by utilizing my knowledge to upsell each guest with something they could use. I know, I love to upsell the guest in my current position by way of additional spa services. Who doesn't like to be pampered when they are on holidays? I see it as a win/win.\"", "\"I am newer to the resort industry so, I am not 100% aware of what those KPI's might be, but it certainly makes sense to treat each role within your organization as a sales role. I do have basic sales training and look forward to learning more from Company ABC.\""]}, {"topic": "Resorts", "question": "How do you react to an increase in your workload?", "answers": ["Often, resorts are very seasonal, and the work will peak, then slow down, as the travel seasons change. The interviewer would like to know how you adapt when the work starts to pile up. Show that you are willing to work faster, put in overtime, or take work home when needed. You will also want to discuss your time-management abilities.", "\"In my current hotel customer service position, my workload changes depending on the team's availability, and the travel season. I can adapt to those needs quickly and effectively. Just last week I had two team members who were sick, and my workload increased significantly. I worked overtime and met my deadlines.\"", "\"My work is very seasonal, and when workloads increase, I perform at lightning-speed. When workloads decrease, I find new projects to take on. I love having a lot to do as it makes the days go faster and I feel more energized.\""]}, {"topic": "Resorts", "question": "Tell me about a time when you had to work with a difficult person. How did you handle it?", "answers": ["From your work history, picture a co-worker who didn't carry their weight or had a difficult personality. Maybe they were unmotivated or preoccupied with their personal life. Think about what bothered you about this person and how you were affected by their behavior. Most importantly, the interviewer wants to know how you let this person's behavior affect you and your work performance. \n\nAvoid taking this as an opportunity to complain about someone; instead, view it as an opportunity to showcase your ability to deal with difficult people while maintaining your productivity.", "\"In my first position out of college, I worked with a person who enjoyed gossip in the workplace. I found that I could redirect her to work by giving a quick reply and then asking her a pointed work question, which would get her back on task. There were a few key takeaways from this experience. I learned how to concentrate on chatter or disruption better than before, and I perfected my skills at refocusing someone else to the task at hand.\"", "\"In my previous position, I did have a coworker who didn't pull their weight. Our team started to complete most of the tasks when it came to group projects. It didn't take much time before our manager noticed this particular individual was slacking. I feel like, in most instances, the underachievers will weed themselves out over time, and it's rarely worth making a fuss over.\""]}, {"topic": "Resorts", "question": "Have you ever received a negative review from a customer?", "answers": ["Reviews are everything in the resort and hotel industry so; it is the aim of Company ABC to gather as many positive, 5-star reviews as possible. Everyone has received negative feedback from someone at one point in their career. What the interviewer would like to see is that you can bounce back professionally from a negative customer review. If the review was warranted, discuss what you were able to learn from the experience or the feedback that you received.", "\"I have received negative feedback from customers in the past, and always when the customer has not been delighted with the outcome of their dispute. The resort that I have worked for, for the past ten years, has a very stringent cancellation policy. Unfortunately, this means that I do disappoint more people than I would like. I am looking to join an organization that will allow for more flexible offerings when it comes to client dispute resolution.\"", "\"The hotel where I work allows customers to leave anonymous feedback at the front desk. I have received one negative review, commenting that I could 'smile more.' Apparently, when I concentrate, I can appear unhappy! I am glad that this trait was brought to my attention so that I could work on correcting it.\""]}, {"topic": "Resorts", "question": "In which resort or hotel related software and programs do you have experience?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to have an idea of the types of programs you have used in the past, and where you will need additional training. Many hotels and resorts will share similar programs, or at least the basics. If you are unsure which programs of software used by Company ABC you can ask for specifics. \n\nSome of the more common programs used in the resort industry include: \n\n- RMS Hotel\n- Preno\n- Hotelogix\n- SmartHotel\n- roomMaster", "\"I have used a couple of hotel and resort management programs in the past. Primarily, I have worked with Hotelogix. I like that it is cloud-based and can be integrated with online booking systems as well as travel agencies. I am tech savvy and confident in my ability to pick up any new programs quickly. Could you share with me which programs you use at Company ABC? I would be happy to get a head start by taking some online tutorials.\"", "\"I am new to the hotel and resort industry but have worked in retail before, where a customer management system was in place, as well as a robust point of sale system. I am confident that I can study your system and learn it quickly.\""]}, {"topic": "Resorts", "question": "Name me three of our best services or amenities.", "answers": ["Robust online research is the best way to get you through this question with flying colors! Go to the Company ABC website and take a look at all of the amenities that they offer. If you have stayed at the resort, you can give a first-hand response based on your experience.", "\"I have stayed with Company ABC as a guest in the past. Hands down, the best services that I experienced was your award-winning steakhouse, the club lounge, and the eco-friendly spa. I was very impressed with the quality of the staff and customer service as well.\"", "\"After reading many reviews online from previous guests of Company ABC, I see that the most popular amenities are the kids club (hurray for parents getting a break!), the multiple swim-up bars, and the fact that you have so many on-site restaurants from which to choose. Would you agree that these are the most raved about amenities here?\""]}, {"topic": "Resorts", "question": "At Company ABC we have a multitude of vendors. Tell me about your experience working directly with suppliers.", "answers": ["A resort will have multiple vendors from spa supplies, food service, alcohol, cleaning supplies, and more. The interviewer would like to know that you understand the importance of healthy supplier and vendor relationships. These relationships take time to create. Also, with vendors, it's critical that you remain organized as to what is coming in and out of the facility. Invoices need thorough review and orders need to be placed promptly. If you do not have experience working with suppliers, that is okay. Be sure to show that you can comply with the processes in place while maintaining great vendor relationships.", "\"In my current role, I am responsible for receiving all supplies that come for the housekeeping department. I work closely with the vendors to ensure accuracy in our orders, preventing backorders, or late arrival shipments. I also have experience negotiating things like price breaks for bulk ordering and flat rate shipping. I am confident I could work very well with the vendors and supplier relationships critical to Company ABC\"", "\"Although I have not had direct responsibility with vendors or suppliers, I have made calls on behalf of my employer for late shipments or missing items. I have seen the importance of great vendor relationships and will work hard to maintain what Company ABC already has in place.\""]}, {"topic": "Resorts", "question": "How do you communicate with an angry customer?", "answers": ["When you work in the customer service and hospitality industry, you quickly learn that you cannot make everyone happy. And, that is okay! The interviewer would like to understand your approach when it comes to communicating with someone who appears to be upset with you. Do you become defensive, or do you shut down entirely? Are you nervous and unable to respond clearly? Assure the interviewer that you have handled situations like this before with professionalism.", "\"When a customer is angry, I take a few steps to ensure that the situation is handled properly. Calmly, I will respond to their grievance, ensuring that I fully understand their need. I make sure not to take it personally! Then, using my great listening skills, I empathize with their situation the best I can, give an apology, and then ask them what solution they would like to see. Once the situation is resolved, I will take a couple of minutes to myself, to restart my day in a positive mindset.\"", "\"Communicating with an angry customer is never fun, but I get through it by reminding myself not to take the situation personally. I actively listen to their problem, repeat it back to them to ensure full understanding, and then offer an apology. From there, I ask how we can solve their concern and then take corrective action.\""]}, {"topic": "Resorts", "question": "Tell me about a time when you did something special for a customer.", "answers": ["This question is your opportunity to shine! Think of a recent example when you went over and above expectations to deliver extraordinary customer experience. Discuss where you saw the need, how you took action, how the customer reacted, and what your leadership thought of the gesture.", "\"I had a couple check into the resort, mentioning that they were just married. The couple did not have the honeymoon suite booked, and it was open, so I offered a free upgrade. We delivered champagne and truffles to their room later in the day. The guests were beyond thrilled and told me that the honeymoon package was out of their budget, which was why they didn't initially book it. We have allowances for promos like that, and my manager was happy with the initiative that I took to make the guests' experience unforgettable. I am confident that whenever this couple decides to go on another resort vacation, they will choose to return.\"", "\"I often keep my eye out for opportunities to make a guests' visit special.  Last week I noticed a mom who was busy with her kids in the lobby. She seemed frustrated. I approached her, told her about our kid's club, and offered to get her kids signed into the program for the day. She was thrilled, the kids were happy, and my hospitality supervisor appreciated the initiative that I took to help a frustrated guest.\""]}, {"topic": "Resorts", "question": "We are open 24 hours a day, 365 days a year. How flexible is your schedule?", "answers": ["Before answering scheduling questions, it's important to be clear on the interviewer's expectations. If you haven't had a chance to clarify their scheduling needs, now would be the perfect time to ask.\nConsider asking, 'What are the scheduling expectations for this position?' If they expect you to work 12 hour days, it would be important for you to know that before you respond with, 'Absolutely! No problem!' You want to be sure that you can meet their expectations. \n\nIf it turns out their schedule expectations won't work for you, think about what you CAN offer and see if you can meet in the middle. It's much better to discuss these things in an interview than for you to commit to a schedule that won't work for you.", "\"In the resort industry, I anticipate working over 40 hours per week, especially around the peak travel times. Currently, I work on a day and evening rotation which works just fine for me. Could you share with me the expectations for this role?\"", "\"In a salaried role such as this, I don't expect a strict 40 hour per week schedule, but I also know that I'm looking for a work-life balance. As needed, I'd be available to dedicate more time to the team, while hoping to preserve that balance. Would there be any other instances of overtime I should be aware of?\""]}, {"topic": "Resorts", "question": "How would you sort out a problem for an unsatisfied guest?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to see that you have the common sense that it takes to deal with guest problems. Working in the customer service industry, and within the hospitality industry, means that you will come across customer complaints on a regular basis. Most will be simple to solve, but some will take additional thinking and reliance on your customer service training. Walk the interviewer through the ways that you would sort out a problem for an unsatisfied guest.", "\"I have been taught to solve customer complaints in three easy steps. Ask, Repeat, Resolve. What this means is that I ask the guest for a breakdown of what is bothering them. I then repeat their issue back to them, in their own words. Once we have confirmed that the grievance is fully understood, I ask them what they would like to see as a resolution. Guests want to be heard, and they want to see that you are trying to help. If their request can be made, as it usually is, then I comply and work towards a resolution.\"", "\"I am sure that Company ABC has a great training program when it comes to dispute resolution and guest complaints. From instinct, I would say that I would first ensure that I fully understood their issue. Next, I would give a few options as to what I can do to help. Once we concluded, I would follow up a short time later to ensure full guest satisfaction.\""]}, {"topic": "Resorts", "question": "We have multiple locations. Are you willing to relocate to another Company ABC resort?", "answers": ["When many locations are available for work options, the opportunities can be endless! Many resort brands will have spots and roles all around the world. The interviewer would like to know that you are able and willing, to travel or relocate if an opportunity arises. If you cannot, this should not be a deal breaker. Just state that your circumstances do not allow for you to relocate at this time.", "\"I see that Company ABC has locations in A, B, and C. Although I would love to relocate to any of these resorts, my circumstances do not allow for that at this time. As we know, life can change on a dime, so I am certainly open to discussing this again should my situation be different. For now, I would love to dedicate myself full time to your X location.\"", "\"Relocation and travel would be no problem for me. I am not tied to this city and am willing to visit any suitable options you may have within Company ABC.\""]}, {"topic": "Resorts", "question": "What do you know about the Company ABC and our resorts?", "answers": ["Hiring managers at Company ABC may very well receive hundreds of applications per job. If you are lucky enough to land an interview, make some effort to research the opportunity. You don't need to be an expert, but you do need to be knowledgeable about Company ABC before your interview. Start by searching the company website and take particular note of any recent news articles, events or contributions they have made to the community. Identify their mission and values. Be sure to complete your response with an expression of enthusiasm for the role.", "\"I conducted a great deal of research before coming in today.  I see that you are currently developing a world-class resort in Costa Rica.  This expansion is a great sign, and I am thrilled with the idea of being part of a travel company that has seen such great success and happy online reviews.\"", "\"I have researched your organization a great deal and see that you recently earned the 'Worlds' Leading Resort Award' for innovation in resort service and hospitality. You had a lot of competition when it comes to winning this award, so this tells me that your team is incredibly dedicated and focused.\""]}, {"topic": "Resorts", "question": "Have you ever stayed at a Company ABC resort? Tell me about your experience.", "answers": ["If you have been lucky enough to have stayed at a Company ABC resort, take the time to walk the interviewer through your experience. Because this is an open-ended question, it can be easy to get carried away or ramble out of nervousness. Try focusing on critical areas such as customer service, amenities, food and beverages, excursions, or spa treatments. Keep your answer enthusiastic and give specific examples. \n\nIf you have never stayed at a Company ABC resort, take the time to comb through some online reviews and tell the interviewer which customer experiences stood out to you the most.", "\"I have had the pleasure of staying at your resort in Hawaii just a few months ago. The staff was all so friendly, and I couldn't believe that everyone remembered my name! The food was delicious, and I was happy with the premium bar service package that we purchased as well. I would give my experience a 5-star rating, for sure.\"", "\"I have not yet had the pleasure of staying at a Company ABC resort; however, I have combed through many online reviews and am pleased how consistent the feedback is. It appears that your resort offers excellent luxury amenities and that the food service options are far beyond everyone's expectations.\""]}, {"topic": "Resorts", "question": "Our guests come from all over the world. Do you speak multiple languages?", "answers": ["There is a good chance that you will have multiple languages listed on our resume if this is a skill that you possess. This question needs a simple, to the point response. If you do speak additional languages, help the interviewer to understand your level of knowledge by ranking your fluency as a beginner, conversationalist, or fluent, for instance.", "\"I speak English and Spanish fluently, and they are my native languages. I did take French and German in school for a few years. I have a basic understanding of these languages; however, those two are basic and not listed on my resume.\"", "\"I currently speak English only but recently began teaching myself Spanish. I am very much at a beginner level but am happy to fast track my learning to accommodate your Spanish speaking guests.\""]}, {"topic": "Resorts", "question": "Do you have experience working cohesively with multiple departments?", "answers": ["In the resort industry, multiple departments work cohesively to make all of the magic happen, that you rarely see as a guest! \n\nDepartments within the resort industry could include: \n\n- Communications\n- Corporate Planning\n- Executive Office\n- Food & Beverage\n- Human Resources\n- Marketing\n- Procurement/Purchasing\n- Retail\n- Rooms\n- Sales\n- Security\n- Spa/Health Club\n\nTalk to the interviewer about any experience you have working in tandem with other departments. No matter your background, chances are you have worked alongside human resources, accounting, sales, or even security.", "\"I have worked with multiple departments in my previous roles. Primarily, I have collaborated with the accounting and human resources departments when it comes to hiring budgets, onboarding procedures, and new employee training programs.\"", "\"In my previous customer service based position, I have worked with the corporate office and middle-management on tasks such as merchandising, ordering, and inventory. I look forward to collaborating with your other departments, and getting to know your teams.\""]}, {"topic": "Resorts", "question": "Do you know the demographics of our guests?", "answers": ["Before your interview, take note of the types of guests that Company ABC portrays in their marketing materials. Who do they have in their commercials, print ads, and website photos, for instance? There is an excellent chance that this is their demographic. If you are unsure, take an educated guess, and then ask the interviewer for clarification.", "\"I have noticed that your advertising targets young families of various backgrounds. I guess that the guest demographic at Company ABC are families age 34-45 with 2-3 kids, generally from North America. Is this accurate?\"", "\"I have vacationed with Company ABC and my experience is that your guests are primarily couples, on a romantic getaway. I did not notice a lot of children. Is this a correct observation? I would love to learn more about your demographics and who you are reaching with your advertising efforts.\""]}, {"topic": "Resorts", "question": "If you could work in any of our departments, which would you choose?", "answers": ["You may be applying to a specific department, or perhaps your application to Company ABC was a blind one, knowing they may call you when they see a suitable fit. It's highly likely that you are talented and experienced in a range of areas, making you a flexible hire with a few options. Discuss where your primary interest is, and ensure with the interviewer that your desired placement aligns with their needs.", "\"I see that you have openings in a variety of areas within the resort. My background allows me to fit well within guest services, and also the food and beverage department. I have bar experience as well as customer service and administration. Where would you see the best fit for me?\"", "\"As you can see on my resume, my background is quite diverse. I have retail sales experience as well as time spent working for a luxury spa, in a customer service role. I see that Company ABC has opportunities within the Spa and Health Club department as well as the Gift Shops. I believe I can be a fit for either. Would you agree?\""]}, {"topic": "Resorts", "question": "What is your favorite destination? Sell it to me.", "answers": ["This question is one of interest, so the interviewer can get to know you better. There is no wrong way to answer this question; however, extra points if you mention a location where Company ABC has a resort! Take three key points as to why this location is excellent. One may be the culture and shopping; the other may be the sightseeing or landmarks. You could also mention how amazing the food is! Be sure to show excitement for this destination to the point that when you're done talking - everyone will want to book a trip there!", "\"My favorite destination is Trinidad and Tobago. For starters, the food has a strong creole history, with complex and unique flavors. It's easy to find an incredible restaurant as many are family owned, with traditional recipes on the menu. I would highly recommend taking in Maracas Bay, with its amazing beaches. The waves are amazing as well if you like surfing. Overall, the culture is a friendly and celebratory one. It's easy to find great people everywhere.\"", "\"Of all the vacations I have taken, I loved visiting Thailand the most. No matter the experience that you want to have, Thailand offers it all. From street food to high-end restaurants, and amazing nightlife, or a relaxing day on the beach  - there is something for everyone.\""]}, {"topic": "Resorts", "question": "How would you sell Company ABC versus our competitor down the street?", "answers": ["Are you aware of the ways that Company ABC stand out from their competitors who are nearby? To answer this question accurately, you will need to do some competitive research. A great place to start will be their online reviews, and amenities such as spa services, restaurants, and shopping options. Briefly discuss why you feel Company ABC knocks out their competitors. Keep your reply enthusiastic!", "\"It is easy to sell Company ABC against competitors down the street. For starters, your amenities are much more robust when you include the kids club, spa, and four on-site restaurants. Also, your star rating is much higher, and that is very important to most vacationers. In my opinion, choosing Company ABC over the others is a simple decision.\"", "\"I have researched the other nearby resorts and, although they are nice, they do not have the positive reviews that I see for Company ABC on the same travel review sites. It's an easy sell, in my opinion, with your friendly staff, upgraded rooms, excellent restaurant choices, and luxury spa services.\""]}, {"topic": "Resorts", "question": "What questions do you have for me?", "answers": ["It's always a great idea to have questions ready for the interviewer. Review the Company ABC website and other online resources to ensure the queries you have are not mundane, or redundant. The last thing an interviewer wants to hear is a list of items you could have found the answers for from merely watching a video on their website! \n\nHere are some sample questions: \n\n- When would you like to have this position filled? \n- How long has this role been vacant? \n- What is your favorite part about working for Company ABC? \n- What is the primary goal for this position in the next 12 months? \n- Is there anything from my background and experience that I can clarify for you? \n- What do you see as the most significant change in the travel industry over the past three years? \n- Is there any reason why you would not hire me?", "\"I would like to ask if there is anything in my background on which you need clarification? Also, after discussing everything today, is there any particular reason why I would not be the best fit for this Director of Resort Communications role?\"", "\"Thank you for asking! A couple of questions come to mind. What do you see as the biggest challenge your resort will be facing in the next 12 months? Also, what is your employee turnover rate, and could you tell me a bit about the retention plan you currently have in place?\""]}, {"topic": "Resorts", "question": "Besides compensation, what do you value the most in the workplace?", "answers": ["Financial compensation aside, the interviewer would like to know what is most important to you when looking for a new job. Your answer will show the interviewer some direction when they are ready to make you an offer of employment. You can talk about the health benefits, work-life balance, workplace culture, growth, or even continued education opportunities. The sky is the limit!", "\"What I value most in the workplace are growth opportunities. I am missing this in my current role and very much look forward to working with a company who will provide me with bigger moves as I prove myself.\"", "\"I am most interested in working for a company that has a great workplace culture, with a small amount of turnover. As a manager, I like to get to know my team, nurture them, and keep them going for the long term.\""]}, {"topic": "Resorts", "question": "How would you build rapport with our guests?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know your methods when it comes to getting to know your customers, or the hotel guests, and building trust with them. When you have a great relationship with the stakeholders, you will be more successful in your work and more likely to stay longer-term. \n\nSome ways that you can build rapport with your clients include: \n\n- Do what you say that you will\n- Ask them questions about themselves\n- Use the same jargon and industry terms they use \n- Set clear expectations, on both sides, from the start\n- Remember their names \n- Show your extensive knowledge base \n- Always be presentable in looks and actions", "\"To build client rapport, I ensure always to do what I say that I will. The guests of our facility need to be able to rely on me, and feel 100% confident that I will deliver over and above their expectations at all times.\"", "\"In my current role as Front Desk Manager, I am usually the first person that a guest sees. To build rapport, I make sure always to look and act presentable. First impressions truly are everything! I am always friendly, available to help, and with a smile. If I do not know the answer to their question, I will go the extra mile to find out, rather than saying 'I don't know.'\""]}, {"topic": "Travel+Agencies", "question": "What was the most significant change you have had to deal with in your travel career?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know the types of challenges you have had to face in your career within the travel industry. You need to show the interviewer that you can remain productive in the face of change and that you are resilient. Assure the interviewer that you can adapt to significant changes in a professional manner.", "\"The biggest shift for me in my travel career was the introduction and fast growth of online travel services such as Expedia and TripAdvisor. It seemed as though our roles as travel agents were now automated. Once I was able to shift and decided where the value-add was for my clients to continue seeing me in person for their travel needs, I was able to effectively  compete and also overcome objections and challenges presented to me from my client base.\"", "\"I went through a large change last year when our company purchases another small travel competitor. We integrated systems, some staff, and a few policies. The corporate head office did the best they could to make the change a smooth one; however, there were significant challenges. The situation taught me more about workplace resilience, patience, and endurance.\""]}, {"topic": "Travel+Agencies", "question": "When a problem requires a quick solution, how do you respond?", "answers": ["When it comes to complex problem solving, decisions are not always readily reached. It takes practice, experience, and confidence to learn what sorts of decisions yield the best results. Walk the interviewer through your process when it comes to making quick decisions. Do you rely on past experiences? Perhaps you go with a gut feeling. Maybe you have read case studies that you lean on in these instances. \n\nProblems in the travel industry that require you to act quickly can be situations such as flights being canceled last minute, or a terrorist attack in another country, requiring you to re-route your clients. Demonstrate that you are confident and able to react swiftly when the need arises.", "\"I react swiftly in emergency situations, and these do come up from time to time in the travel industry. Perhaps my problem-solving skills come from my years as a parent, having to think fast and put out fires! If a quick solution is required, I will do a fast overview of the facts and make a decision based on risk factors considering the safety of those involved.\"", "\"I thrive under pressure and always have, so when I'm given a time-sensitive situation to address, I light up and get down to business. I am more impactful and even more creative when I have little time to do much besides jump in and take charge. This ability to make fast decisions is especially helpful in my role as manager when there is a travel issue affecting a client.\""]}, {"topic": "Travel+Agencies", "question": "Adult airfare to Barbados is $900. A child's ticket is 75% of this plus 10% for commission and fees. How much is a child's fare to Barbados?", "answers": ["What may seem like a simple math question, could be difficult under pressure. If you are working as a travel agent, you will be required to make all types of calculations. Accuracy and common sense are going to be very important in your new role. Keep your answer brief, and walk the interviewer through your thought process as you solve the problem.", "\"I understand that math is a required skill for this role. To figure out a child's fare to Barbados, I would take $900 minus 25%, which is $675. From there, I would add $67.50, which is the 10% in commission and fees, to $675, making a child's ticket $742.50.\"", "\"I am accustomed to making math calculations at work, and have strong calculation skills, even under pressure. Because 75% of $900 is $675, I would add the 10% commission and fees to $675. The total for a child's fare to Barbados is $742.50.\""]}, {"topic": "Travel+Agencies", "question": "Where is your favorite place to travel, and why?", "answers": ["The interviewer at Company ABC would like to know where you have traveled, and what types of travel you prefer. Chances are, you will more easily sell the kind of trip that you prefer to take yourself. For instance, if cruises are your version of a nightmare, compared to a beach resort, you will likely sell more beach resort packages since it's easier for you to show passion and excitement. Keep your reply simple and to the point, being sure to support your answer.", "\"My favorite place to travel is the Amalfi Coast in Italy. My family is Italian, and I believe it's essential to visit ancestry roots.  The cliffside towns are stunning, and it's home to some of the worlds' most luxurious hotels.\"", "\"My favorite place to travel is The Maldives. Have you been? The turquoise waters are among the brightest in the world, and the beaches have the whitest sand.  It's a great place to relax with many overwater huts available. Also available are underwater restaurants which are incredible.\""]}, {"topic": "Travel+Agencies", "question": "What do you believe to be the most common travel grievance among your customers?", "answers": ["The interviewer is looking for a pattern when it comes to your customer service and any complaints or issues that you may be coming across. When you mention your customer grievances, you will want to stick to examples that you were able to repair. We all need to learn and grow in our jobs; however, you will want to avoid an example that may seem like you are not capable of doing a great job in a customer service environment.", "\"If I were to analyze common travel grievances, I would say that the most common is the unexpected fees that come along with travel. I try my best to prepare my clients for those additional fees; however, they do add up and are sometimes a bit shocking.\"", "\"I believe the most common travel grievance that I hear lately is the lack of safe places to travel. The world is different than it once was and we cannot travel as freely to some areas of the world. I have a list of the safest places to go, and provide that to my clients who inquire.\""]}, {"topic": "Travel+Agencies", "question": "How strong is your geography knowledge?", "answers": ["If you can rate your knowledge from beginner, intermediate, or expert, that is a straightforward way for the interviewer to be able to understand your knowledge level. Also, you could rate your geography knowledge from 1-10. Whichever way you choose to reply, be sure to let the interviewer know that your understanding is strong but so is your willingness to learn. If you need to study and strengthen your skills, that is okay too. Be honest and show that you are eager.", "\"I can safely say that my geography knowledge is at an intermediate level. I am confident; however, I do not know it all. Are there any courses or training that you would recommend, to strengthen my knowledge?\"", "\"I am newer to the travel industry and would rate my knowledge as a beginner. With that said, I have an app on my phone that I use every day, which tests me on all things geography. It's helping a lot. I should be at an intermediate level soon.\""]}, {"topic": "Travel+Agencies", "question": "Do you keep up to date on global travel restrictions?", "answers": ["As a professional working in the travel industry, you will be required to remain in-the-know, when it comes to global happenings, travel restrictions, and how those affect your clients. It's very likely that Company ABC has a database for this or apps and tools to help you stay efficient and knowledgeable. Discuss with the interviewer how you currently stay up to date on global travel restrictions, and other related news.", "\"I will often refer to the government or state website to read up on any restrictions. In my current role, we use a program called Tripfuser to assist with booking and any alerts that we may need to know. Do you have a similar system at Company ABC?\"", "\"I do keep up to date on global travel restrictions. My favorite resources are the government website, and I also follow a few trending hashtags on Twitter, related to travel safety and other important government alerts. Do you have any recommendations for great resources?\""]}, {"topic": "Travel+Agencies", "question": "How would you ultimately describe your work style?", "answers": ["This question is not referring to your personality or character, but more towards your methodology when it comes to getting your work done. Talk to the interviewer about your day-to-day approach to projects, communicating with coworkers, or collaborating with clients. \n\nYour work style might be:\n\n- Collaborative \n- Well-Planned\n- Speedy\n- Flexible or Adaptive\n- Independent \n- Company-focused\n- Team-based", "\"I would describe my work style as highly team-based. I keep in mind that my pace, quality of work, and the outcome will always affect multiple people on my team, not to mention the travel experiences of my clients. If I am unsure of the path to take on a project, I will consult with my team to ensure that my ideas align well with theirs.\"", "\"I have an adaptive work style that changes based on the customers that I am serving at the time. I like to work with my customers' personalities and needs. If they are the no-nonsense, busy corporate type, then I speed up my work. If they are elderly and need more time, I slow down to explain everything they need to make a decision.\""]}, {"topic": "Travel+Agencies", "question": "How do you build rapport with your clients?", "answers": ["When it comes to the travel industry, a lot of your business may come from repeat clients that know you and trust you. You may also have a solid customer base from your referral network. The interviewer would like to know your methods when it comes to getting to know your customers and building trust with them. When you have a great relationship with your clients, you will be more successful in your role with Company ABC,  and more likely to stay long-term. \n\nSome ways that you can build rapport with your clients include: \n\n- Do what you say that you will\n- Ask them questions about themselves\n- Use the same jargon and travel terms they use \n- Set clear expectations, on both sides, from the start\n- Remember their names \n- Show your extensive knowledge base \n- Always be presentable in looks and actions", "\"To build client rapport, I ensure always to do what I say that I will. My clients need to be able to rely on me, and feel 100% confident that I will deliver over and above their expectations at all times.\"", "\"I am a naturally curious person which means that I often build a rapport with my clients by asking them questions about themselves. I like to know about their business, their favorite activities and hobbies, family, and upcoming important dates. Most people enjoy talking about themselves, so this approach is usually a very successful one. It helps me to build a connection while also upselling based on our latest travel offerings.\""]}, {"topic": "Travel+Agencies", "question": "On a scale of 1-10, how would you rate your technical abilities?", "answers": ["As a travel agency employee, much of your work will occur online. The interviewer would like to know how you rate your technical skills. Likely, they will mention specific tech skills needed, in the job posting or job description. \n\nFirst, on a scale of 1-10, discuss how skilled are you in their tech requirements. Try to avoid giving yourself a 10, since nobody is perfect, and you do not want to come across as overly confident or someone who has no room for feedback and improvement. Alternately, avoid giving yourself too little credit. You do not want to paint the picture that you are a tech dud! Try to remain in the 7.5-9.5 range while staying honest and accurate. Be sure to list which programs, apps, or systems in which you shine!", "\"I rate my technical skills as a 9/10 as I will, on occasion, have times when I am not as savvy as I would like to be. My supervisor and co-workers will attest to my ability to pick up new tech very easily. I would say I'm strongest in TravelWorks and ResVoyage.\"", "\"I will rate myself an eight because I value strong technical capabilities but, just like most people, I have things to learn. My strongest technical skills are in the Microsoft Office suite including Word, Excel, and PowerPoint. I have also used Juniper Booking for about five years.\""]}, {"topic": "Travel+Agencies", "question": "Tell me about a time when you had to address an angry customer. What was the problem and how did you resolve it?", "answers": ["Working in the travel industry can be high-stress and performance-based, with very little room for error. The interviewer wants to know that you can handle stressful or uncomfortable situations in a professional manner. Keep your answer simple and precise. Stay away from long drawn out stories. Briefly, describe a time when you resolved a customer service issue. Highlight your ability to remain patient and rational.", "\"Currently, I work in a retail-based travel center and have to navigate angry customer experiences more times than I like. People who are upset want to be heard and respected. I will listen, empathize and reassure the client that I am there to support them and resolve the matter. Communication and reassurance are important throughout the process. If I need to check on flight status or get back to the customer, I will set expectations and explain when they can expect to hear back. I am proud to say that I have successfully turned around more customer service issues than anyone else in our location.\"", "\"I once was a customer service manager at a travel call center. I had many angry customer calls, but one, in particular, I remember well. The customer had booked a return flight and was double billed. She had unfortunately sat on hold with us for over 30 minutes waiting to be helped and was irate when I told her that our policy was that refunds were not immediate, but issued in 48-72 hours. She ended up getting a refund and promised never to book through that company again. I did make sure she received her refund, and I spoke with our corporate head office about the long wait times and the possibility of changing our refund policies. It was not a good situation, but I made the best of it.\""]}, {"topic": "Travel+Agencies", "question": "If given the opportunity, what coursework would you take to further your education in travel services?", "answers": ["Perhaps Company ABC offers continued education opportunities, or maybe the interviewer is curious about your specific areas of interest. It is essential that you express an interest in expanding your travel related knowledge. If there is an area you need to strengthen, to be considered for a promotion in the future, you could mention that as well.", "\"I saw on your website that to be considered for a Global Sales Director role, I would need a completed MBA in Business. For that reason, if I could take additional coursework, I would apply my time to an MBA. I am very interested in working my way up, at Company ABC and feel that would be an excellent start.\"", "\"I would like to complete my Bachelor's Degree in Travel and Tourism. Currently, I have a Diploma; however, it would be great to elevate that education and boost my career at the same time.\""]}, {"topic": "Travel+Agencies", "question": "How competitive are you?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know if you have a competitive spirit. Being a competitive person is an excellent thing if you are appropriately competitive in the workplace. Assure the interviewer that you have a tremendous competitive edge when necessary but are still able to balance that competition healthily.", "\"On a scale of 1-10, I would rate myself as an 8 when it comes to being competitive. I love a great competition in the workplace when it comes to sales goals and breaking through last years' numbers. I am not competitive to the point that it would hurt my clients or colleagues.\"", "\"Competition in the workplace can be a great thing. I create small competitions with the staff, and I love to see how it motivates them. I then look at the numbers and see how much my workplace challenge has affected productivity, compared to the week before. I am a numbers person, so my competitive streak is satisfied by knowing I have improved productivity from week to week.\""]}, {"topic": "Travel+Agencies", "question": "How do you like to be recognized for your accomplishments?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know what motivates you to be an over-achiever in the workplace. We all want recognition in some way for our accomplishments in the workplace. Perhaps you enjoy surprise gifts, financial perks, public attention, kind words, added responsibilities, or title promotions. Share with the interviewer how you would like recognition for your hard work, should you be hired at Company ABC.", "\"I am a highly competitive person who is compensation driven. I like to recognition for my accomplishments through monetary bonus' or contests where the stakes are high.\"", "\"The success of my team is a direct reflection of my success as a manager. For that reason, I prefer that my team receive accolades for a job well done. For instance, our group exceeded our targets for the past business quarter. Thus we were collectively rewarded. This method of recognition is my preference.\""]}, {"topic": "Travel+Agencies", "question": "Do you consider yourself a persuasive person?", "answers": ["Part of being an excellent communicator is also having the power of persuasion when necessary. There is a difference between persuasion and debating - or even convincing. Persuasion is used when you want to influence someone rather than tell them that they are wrong, and you are right. \nThe power of persuasion is essential if you are selling or pitching anything. It is also a helpful skill when you want to gain momentum with your coworkers or have your boss better understand your approach on a project. It is not a negative thing to be persuasive. Talk to the interviewer about whether or not you consider yourself to be a persuasive individual.", "\"Persuasion is a key skill of an effective leader, in my opinion. Have you ever read the book, 'Pre-Suasion,' by Robert Cialdini? He speaks of the science in persuasion and that there are significant moves to be made before ever asking someone to do something on your behalf. This book has greatly influenced how I use persuasion.\"", "\"Persuasion and travel go hand in hand since many people are hesitant to spend their money on vacation for themselves, let alone, a lavish one. My approach is not sly or combative in any way. I go about persuading others by displaying how my recommendations and expertise could benefit them and make their lives richer.\""]}, {"topic": "Travel+Agencies", "question": "Why are you the best candidate for this position with Company ABC?", "answers": ["Bragging about yourself in an interview can be tough to do, but this is your time to shine! Which characteristics and career accomplishments have made you a stand-out candidate? Perhaps you have received some academic awards or have been given accolades in your most recent position. There is nobody like you, and now you need to express that to the interviewer so they can see you are the best fit for Company ABC.", "\"I am the best candidate for you because I have a consistent history of exceeding my targets and goals for the past three years. I have been promoted two times in the last year which is nearly unheard of in my current travel agency. In addition to these successes, I have cold and warm calling techniques which I will put to work immediately after being hired by your company.\"", "\"I have the necessary experience, skill sets, and high level of ambition to add great value to this travel agency. I come well trained in upselling, team leadership, and sales methods. In addition to this, I have led teams up to 15 with minimal employee turnover.\""]}, {"topic": "Travel+Agencies", "question": "How would your co-workers describe your attention to detail?", "answers": ["It should go without saying that your attention to detail, being in the travel industry, should be impeccable. One rogue click of the mouse and you could be sending a client to the wrong destination! The interviewer would like to know more about your attention to detail. It is always best to support your reply with a real-life example. Talk to the interviewer about your level of attentiveness when it comes to the smaller details.", "\"I have a well-honed ability to point out discrepancies in my work, and the work of my team. Being in the travel industry for seven years has helped me to streamline many processes and avoid a lot of error. I plan to bring this same discretion with me to Company ABC.\"", "\"My co-workers would describe my attention to detail as very strong. I can very easily point out spelling discrepancies in communication and will notice the small things. I think big-picture as well but have always had a knack for details.\""]}, {"topic": "Travel+Agencies", "question": "When is it okay to stretch the truth to sell a travel package?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know if you would stretch the truth to sell a travel service to a client. Of course, you already know that it is not okay to fib to make a sale. Talk to the interviewer about your ability to sell without stretching the truth.", "\"When selling a travel service or package, describing features and benefits is the best approach. It is not in anyone's best interest to stretch truths. In the travel industry, I have heard of agencies exaggerating how luxurious a particular resort is, for instance. It's a terrible thing to mislead someone to gain a sale or booking. If I tell the truth about everything, I am more likely to have a happy, repeat client in the end.\"", "\"I am not in the habit of stretching the truth. I believe that fact-based decision making is the best route for everyone. I would not want to make an important decision with information loosely based on fact, so I would not do the same to my customers.\""]}, {"topic": "Travel+Agencies", "question": "What gives you satisfaction in your travel services career?", "answers": ["Job satisfaction is a significant factor in whether people stay or leave their employers. Talk to the interviewer about what satisfies you about your career in the travel industry, and why you continue to remain on this particular path.", "\"I am delighted with my career as a travel agent, and I believe it is because I can help people on a daily basis. It is important for me to feel as though I am contributing to bettering the lives of others and this career certainly generates those feelings. I help grandparents safely travel to their granddaughters' destination wedding. I help newlyweds book a honeymoon they will never forget, and I get to help parents plan the best trip ever for their kids, to Disney. What could be better.\"", "\"I have worked very hard to make a positive name for myself in the travel industry. Having a great reputation gives me the sense that my work and actions genuinely matter to other people. If my work ethic and attitude can positively influence someone else, or even give them the best vacation experience of their lives, that is the most satisfying for me.\""]}, {"topic": "Travel+Agencies", "question": "Are you comfortable being paid on a 100% commission basis?", "answers": ["Many travel based roles are highly commission based. The interviewer would like to know if you are happy with being paid solely on your performance and results. Whether the job with Company ABC pays 100% commission or not, may not be the point of this question. Assure the interviewer that you are confident in your ability to be a top performer, regardless of commissions or a comfy base salary. Are you able to work hard and be paid based on your performance alone?", "\"I can assure you that my performance is always top notch and I am comfortable being paid based on my performance. I have earned solely on commission, as a travel agent, for many years.\"", "\"As a formerly independent travel professional, I learned to become motivated to drive my performance without outside factors driving me. Working in a 100% commission sales environment allows me to determine my compensation and manage my business and income accordingly.\""]}, {"topic": "Travel+Agencies", "question": "Besides compensation, what do you value the most in the workplace?", "answers": ["Financial compensation aside, the interviewer would like to know what is most important to you when looking for a new job. Your answer will show the interviewer some direction when they are ready to make you an offer of employment. You can talk about the health benefits, work-life balance, workplace culture, growth, or even continued education opportunities. The sky is the limit!", "\"I am most interested in working for a company that has a great workplace culture, with a small amount of employee turnover, and a solid client retention rate. I like to get to know my clients, nurture those relationships, and keep them going for the long term. Regarding co-workers, I want to feel that I can trust the team environment and know that my company embraces values that align with my own.\"", "\"For me, the room for creativity and a flexible workspace is significant. This flex could include a great office where it's easy to collaborate, or the ability to work from home when needed.\""]}, {"topic": "Travel+Agencies", "question": "What are your thoughts on online travel booking sites, and how can we best compete?", "answers": ["Online travel sites shook up the traditional travel industry, and now the interviewer would like to know your thoughts on how brick and mortar travel agencies can best compete. Some of the benefits of hiring a travel agent include: \n\n- Save time combing the web for deals. A travel agent already has the best deals on hand. \n- If any emergencies occur, you have someone to assist you during your trip.\n- Travel agents often specialize in specific vacations like Disney or cruise lines. \n- Travel agents are also like an event planner, helping you maximize your time and experiences. \n\nDraw from this list, or create your own ideas, as to how Company ABC can best compete with online travel sites.", "\"I think that online booking sites are great for people on really tight budgets or young singles who don't need to arrange the happenings and comfort for an entire family. Where a company like Company ABC can best compete is offering convenience and support to people traveling for important events, or with young kids, where there is little room for error or surprises.\"", "\"I believe there is a time and a place for both. If I am booking a hotel in Chicago to see my parents, I will book online at Hotels.com or something of the like. However; when I planned my family vacation to Disney, there was no way I was taking any chances. I hired a professional. I think Company ABC can best compete by continuing to show value when it comes to professional knowledge, travel support, and convenience for busy families and travelers.\""]}, {"topic": "Travel+Agencies", "question": "In your opinion, what are the three most important things you need, to make a sale.", "answers": ["Working in the travel industry requires a great deal of sales fortitude. Many of the positions are highly commission based, if not 100% commission driven at the start.  Show the interviewer that you are capable of closing sales, and hitting your targets. If you have received formal sales training, you can discuss those experiences as well.", "\"I have taken a variety of sales courses through my past employers and find that the most important parts of a sale include finding and qualifying the right prospect, being comfortable making cold and warm calls once the prospect has been qualified and then, of course, asking for the sale.\"", "\"First and foremost, asking for the sale is one of the most important steps in sales that many people refuse to do, or completely forget to do in some instances. The other two important steps are keeping your pipeline filled with qualified prospects and, of course, keeping in touch with those prospects on a regular basis so that a relationship grows. I recently attended a Dale Carnegie training course on 'Winning with Relationship Selling.' In that course, I learned a great deal on active listening skills, and building profitable relationships.\""]}, {"topic": "Travel+Agencies", "question": "Why would you choose to work at Company ABC over any other travel agent?", "answers": ["The interviewer is looking for the specific reasons why you want to work for Company ABC. When responding, it's essential that you dig more in-depth than the fact that their office is close to home, or their benefits are great. You will want to look into the heart of the company and comment on how they got started, what they do for the communities around them, or their culture and how they embrace diversity and inclusion.", "\"I would like to work at Company ABC over any other travel agent because of your commitment to responsible business. You collaborate only with travel partners that offer the best and are ethical in their ways. I appreciate this about your company and look forward to joining an organization that is so conscious.\"", "\"There are many great reasons to choose Company ABC; however, the stand out for me is the fact that you are so highly involved in community efforts, and giving back. I read that your organization regularly contributes resources to victims of environmental disaster or war. I have a passion for socioeconomic issues, and it's great to see corporations join in relief efforts. I would be very proud to work here.\""]}, {"topic": "Travel+Agencies", "question": "At Company ABC you will have access to sensitive customer information. Are you willing to pass a psychometric test and background check?", "answers": ["Working for Company ABC means that you will have access to passports and other highly sensitive information. The interviewer needs to know that you can be trusted with this type of information. Background checks, and even personality and psychometric tests. The best answer to this question is that, yes, you are willing to comply. Keep your answer brief, and if you need to disclose anything from your past, this is the time to do so.", "\"I am willing to comply with any pre-employment checks and testing that you require for this role. My background is clear; however, you can never be too careful in the travel industry, so I completely understand.\"", "\"I will comply with any pre-employment checks required to work for Company ABC. I do have a small mark on my record from 2007; however, it is a driving-related offense. There are no restrictions by which I have to comply, and I can freely travel.\""]}, {"topic": "Travel+Agencies", "question": "The target is to sell $40,000 per month in travel services. How do you plan to meet your sales goals right away?", "answers": ["Since being a travel agent is a sales and customer service based role, the interviewer would like to know that you can reach your goals and targets. You may need to get creative some months and others, like when you first start your job, may require you to dig deep into your resources. Describe to the interviewer how you plan to reach your goals immediately.", "\"I plan to reach my targets immediately by calling all of my contacts, including family, and friends, to let them know where I am working and reviewing how I can help them book a wonderful trip.\"", "\"I have always met or exceeded my targets. When working for Company ABC, I plan to do so immediately by tapping into my network and digging into your database for past clients who could benefit from a warm call. The path of least resistance includes reaching out to those who have already purchased from Company ABC versus taking the time to find an attract an entirely new customer base.\""]}, {"topic": "Travel+Agencies", "question": "If a client had an unlimited budget for a beach vacation, where would you send them and what would you plan?", "answers": ["You can have some fun with this question, helping the interviewer to understand how creative you can get when planning an epic getaway for a client. Let's say there is an unlimited budget. Where would you start? With a high-end vacation, you need to make sure that you account for every small detail. Keep your reply on track, but play around a bit with your response.", "\"I keep a list of the Top 10 luxury beach resorts in the world, and cannot wait to take a vacation of the sort myself, someday. If a client had an unlimited budget, my go-to recommendation would be Constance Moofushi, in the Maldives. It's a small private island where you can have your own personal 'hut' on the water. The area boasts some of the best scuba diving experiences money can buy, as well as many on-site luxury services such as a spa, private tours, and premium food and beverage experiences.\"", "\"An absolute dream vacation, where a traveler could spend an unlimited amount of money, would be Xaranna Okavango Delta Camp located in Botswana. It is a luxury safari lodge where guests can enjoy tented suites with large soaking tubs, a private pool, and cushy cabana areas. You can see wildlife such as lions, leopards, hippos, and elephants. There is a private chef on site also. For those who enjoy ultra-remote vacation experiences, it's a must-go.\""]}, {"topic": "Travel+Agencies", "question": "What do you believe to be peak travel times, and slower travel times?", "answers": ["Show the interviewer that you understand the ebbs and flows that come with working in the travel industry. If you are applying for a 100% commission based role, you should be extra mindful of the expectations and earning potential during any travel. Feel free to ask questions surrounding peak travel times, and how Company ABC operates during the slower times.", "\"From what I understand, in the Northern Hemisphere, peak travel times are June to August. Offseason is generally November to March with some peaks in March, April, June, September, and October, around school breaks and a few significant holidays. Could you share with me how Company ABC successfully navigates the slower times?\"", "\"I am new to the travel industry; however, I believe that the peak travel times would be when kids are out of school. Families like to travel together so perhaps June to August and again during winter and spring breaks. Is this accurate to say? I am eager to learn more about how Company ABC keeps business coming in steadily throughout the year.\""]}, {"topic": "Travel+Agencies", "question": "Travel agent positions are just the beginning of a career with Company ABC. Which other roles interest you?", "answers": ["Take a look at the positions available with Company ABC, far beyond their retail or baseline travel agency positions. You can find a list of opportunities on the company website or LinkedIn page. The interviewer would like to know the type of growth that you are interested in earning. Discuss what has caught your eye and be sure to express that you understand it will take work and dedication to reach your career goals.", "\"I would like to earn my way into a Travel Coordinator role, working with higher end and corporate clients. From there, a Global Travel Director would be incredible. I realize that this step would require many years of successful service with Company ABC and I am ready to put in the work.\"", "\"The Travel Manager position that you have listed on your LinkedIn jobs caught my eye. It would be a great opportunity to work in your Global Travel department and travel to the UK. I see that you look for experience in developing and implementing travel policies, operational procedures, and other service agreements, so I plan to expand my education to include these skills.\""]}, {"topic": "Travel+Agencies", "question": "In your opinion, what are the top 3 landmarks in Paris?", "answers": ["The interviewer is testing your knowledge when it comes to the most popular travel landmarks in the world. Many people want to see Paris, but not only just for the Eiffel Tower. Show the interviewer that you have a solid knowledge base when it comes to travel hot spots. \n\nSome of the most famous Paris landmarks include: \n\n- The Eiffel Tower\n- Arc de Triomphe\n- Basilica of the Sacr?-Coeur\n- Louvre\n- Pantheon\n- The Catacombs \n\nThe list goes on. If you have ever visited these places or attractions, this is a great time to mention your hands-on experience.", "\"I have been to Paris a couple of times and have to say, without a doubt, the most enjoyable landmarks were The Eiffel Tower, The Catacombs, and the Louvre. There are so much culture and experience to soak in, in Paris, that it's difficult to get all of it in just one trip.\"", "\"There are many great landmarks in Paris, and although I have never been, I hear the most positive feedback from my clients who have seen Arc de Triomphe, the Basilica of the Sacr?-Coeur and its views over Paris, then the famous Notre-Dame de Paris Cathedral.\""]}, {"topic": "Upscale+Hotels", "question": "Tell me about the worst guest you have ever dealt with, and how you persevered through the situation.", "answers": ["Guests will complain, be nit-picky, snarky, and at times - downright rude. Situations like this are par for the course in the service industry. Luckily, these experiences are not the norm, and you get to choose how you react. Show the interviewer that you are not one to take it personally if a guest is acting out. Discuss a time when you have been in an awkward situation, and how you came out of it unscathed.", "\"I once had a guest dislike their appointed room so much that they threw their suitcase at the bellman! It was the oddest experience for me to see a grown adult throw what looked like a tantrum. I politely let him know that we would seek out another room for him, according to his preferences. His behavior was disturbing, yes, but it was important to us that we delivered our 5-star service standards, regardless.\"", "\"We once had a couple arrive at our hotel, and unpack their car, when the wife realized that her husband did not pack her suitcase. She was verbally berating him in front of everyone, and the situation was very uncomfortable. I empathized with both of them and let them know that we would have the situation fixed before the morning. We put our heads together and decided that our senior service staff member would drive the three hours to their home, to retrieve the wife's bag. He drove the six-hour return trip in the name of customer service. Luckily the situation was saved, as was the husbands' feelings.\""]}, {"topic": "Upscale+Hotels", "question": "In this role with Company ABC you will move from reception duties to task delegation, to assisting other departments. How do you deal with pivoting activities on a regular basis?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know that you can successfully juggle multiple high-stakes responsibilities at a time. When you feel torn between a variety of projects or tasks, how do you decide which one needs your attention the most? Assure the interviewer that you can be diligent when it comes to assessing your priorities, yet getting all of your work done on time.", "\"I am very good at taking on multiple tasks from various departments. Assuming that the projects all have varying levels of urgency, I first stop to determine the value of each task and prioritize them from there. This prioritization method ensures the best productivity, and that revenue is optimized.\"", "\"It's essential to have team members that you can rely on to step in when you become too busy. The same applies to being cross-departmentally trained. I am not afraid to ask for assistance when needed and appreciate being in-the-know when it comes to being able to assist my co-workers in other departments.\""]}, {"topic": "Upscale+Hotels", "question": "How do you keep abreast on tourist and business traveling information?", "answers": ["It is essential that you stay on top of the travel happenings in your region. As an employee of an upscale hotel, your guests will often be from out of town, looking for special events, landmarks, and other impressive things to take in, and do. Talk to the interviewer about the resources you use to stay in-the-know. You can also ask the interviewer about the resources they use if you want to learn.", "\"I am a member of the local Chamber of Commerce. This membership ensures that I network with the best of the best, and am always up to date on what is coming up in our city from hot new restaurant openings to galas, to theatre events.\"", "\"Currently, I have a Google alert set up with our city's name. This way, I am always alerted to a new event, festival, or restaurant grand opening. I would love to hear about your favorite resources as well. It's always better to be in the know!\""]}, {"topic": "Upscale+Hotels", "question": "Are you comfortable ensuring your guest services team is well groomed, meeting our clients' satisfaction expectations?", "answers": ["Appearances are everything when it comes to the guest services team of an upscale hotel. Before your interview, take a good look at the presentation of the staff at Company ABC and note what you see. Is everyone in a pristine uniform? Chances are, the team looks very well put together, approachable, and well kept. \n\nAs a manager for Company ABC, it would be your responsibility to ensure that everyone on your team arrives to work in the best shape possible. Express to the interviewer that you are comfortable having these types of conversations with your team. How would you handle the situation, if a team member showed up to work unshowered and unkempt?", "\"For the past two years I have worked as a sales manager for a high-end leather goods store where our dress code and appearance expectations are stringent. I fully understand the importance of having a well-groomed team, especially in a luxury and upscale setting. If I need to have a conversation with a team member about their appearance, I will handle it with tact and sensitivity, just as I would any other constructive conversation.\"", "\"Just last year I had a team member who was not abiding by the dress code. He was showing up with wrinkled clothes, unshowered, and very messy looking. I pulled him aside and asked him if he could return home, and come back asap, abiding by the employee presence expectations. We have all of our staff members initial this part of their employment agreement, so I always have that that to fall back on, should the situation escalate.\""]}, {"topic": "Upscale+Hotels", "question": "Have you ever worked in a luxury or upscale environment?", "answers": ["Take a few minutes to bring your resume to life, for the interviewer. Walk them through any experience you have in an upscale environment, being sure to touch on the training you have received. If you have not worked in a luxury environment, express your interest and show a high level of enthusiasm to learn.", "\"I have five years' experience in a retail environment; however, in more of a mid-level range when it comes to the cost of goods sold. I have an immense amount of sales training, all which touched on the importance of exceptional service, no matter who your clientele is. I look forward to learning from Company ABC and rest assured, will be a highly professional addition to your esteemed team and brand.\"", "\"I have worked in an upscale resort environment for the past two summers, on a work visa. I have also attended some professional butler training which includes discretion, professional etiquette, and excellence in service.\""]}, {"topic": "Upscale+Hotels", "question": "How do you demonstrate high levels of customer care?", "answers": ["Company ABC thrives on being known for their exceptional levels of customer care and attention. Now, the interviewer would like to see how you feel that your work will measure up to their expectations. Excellent customer care goes beyond doing precisely as your expected, and it's more than having a smile on your face when the hotel guest is looking. Customer care means that you actively seek out the opportunity to deliver more than the standard. Share with the interviewer how you have done this in the past.", "\"I demonstrate high levels of customer care by remembering important details of the guest. Their names, the names of their children, food allergies, entertainment preferences, and things of the sort. When a guest arrives and feels like I have their back, they are more relaxed and primed to have a much better stay.\"", "\"Delivering high levels of customer care is my specialty! I am friendly, engaged, and will never say to a guest, 'No,' or 'I don't know.' I will always find a way to make their stay more relaxed and more comfortable, whether that is taking their drycleaning across the street, ordering their Towncar with ample time to spare, or making a reservation at a new restaurant hot spot, knowing ahead of time the cuisine and atmosphere they prefer.\""]}, {"topic": "Upscale+Hotels", "question": "Our hotels host highly discerning guests. How will you accommodate the needs of these special guests?", "answers": ["With high-end, luxury accommodations usually come guests who are very particular about their experience. Are you able to brush it off when a guest is extra fastidious, or do you take the event personally? Assure the interviewer that you can keep professional composure when it comes to fussy customers.", "\"I handle an extra-discerning customer with utmost care! I listen and do my best to deliver above their expectations. In my current role, I keep highly detailed notes of every guests' needs and preferences in our customer management system. The next time they visit, I am one step ahead and ready to impress.\"", "\"I have spent many years working in the resort, hotel, restaurant, and other customer service based industries. I no longer take it personally when a customer is difficult to please. I will do my best to make them happy, learning their preferences and being one step of head of them, at all times.\""]}, {"topic": "Upscale+Hotels", "question": "What do you know about the Company ABC guest loyalty program?", "answers": ["Most hotels will have guest loyalty, or rewards programs, for regular customers. There are often different programs available for personal, and business customers, and even corporate accounts. Before your interview, visit the Company ABC website and take note of the various offerings available to their most loyal customers. Talk to the interviewer about the perks and benefits that you noticed. With enthusiasm, you could also discuss the perks that excited you most. \n\nMany hotel loyalty programs include: \n\n- Higher service levels on-site\n- Preferred availability and priority waitlisting during peak times\n- Discounts on spa bookings\n- Invitations to exclusive events", "\"I was most impressed with the loyalty rewards and generous discounts offered by Company ABC when it came to the luxury spa services. I know that if I traveled as frequently as many of your guests do, I would greatly appreciate an offer of a spa discount to help me get some rest.\"", "\"I researched online and saw a brief description of the loyalty program at Company ABC such as exclusive events, a club level with complimentary beverages and snacks, and also discounts on some of the luxury service. I would love to learn more in detail, when it comes to how guests qualify, for example.\""]}, {"topic": "Upscale+Hotels", "question": "Do you believe Company ABC should collaborate with online booking sites? Why or why not?", "answers": ["Online booking sites offer their pros and cons for the hotel and travel industry. \n\nThe downside may be: \n\n- Less revenue for the business\n- Steep discounts offered\n- Integrating the system with your own CRM\n- Less control of customer service standards \n\nThe upside may be: \n\n- Fewer rooms are sitting empty \n- Help with bookings during slower times\n- More exposure for your business\n- Some online booking sites will upsell your spa packages, etc\n\nDiscuss with the interviewer your thoughts but try to remain neutral if you are unsure where Company ABC stands when it comes to this type of service.", "\"I have primarily worked for hotels who collaborate with online booking sites and have seen both the upside and the downside, to this service. Yes, rooms fill at a faster rate; however, there is a significant drop in revenue per room, and it can affect the hotel's overall KPI's. I would be interested in your thoughts on the use of online booking sites and this hotel.\"", "\"Like all great things, there can also be the con's that come along. Does Company ABC collaborate with online booking sites? I am newer to the hotel industry; however, I would guess that the service could be great during travel lulls but perhaps not during peak times. I would love to know more.\""]}, {"topic": "Upscale+Hotels", "question": "How would you build rapport with a guest who intimidates you?", "answers": ["In the upscale and luxury service environment, you may come across guests who are intimidating, forward, or difficult. Show the interviewer that you have the smarts, and maturity, to recognize when this is happening, and the ability to overcome whatever factor is causing you to feel intimidated in any way.", "\"Earlier in my guest services career, I had a couple of visitors who would be very aggressive on the phone with their reservation requests, and I would sometimes get tripped up on my words when they called. I made myself a telephone script related to those specific instances and memorized it. This script helped me to remain on track with my thoughts when those more intimidating hotel guests would call.\"", "\"When someone intimidates me, such as an upset customer who is demanding a special request that I cannot give, I will focus less on how I am feeling and more about how they are feeling. I remind myself that they are possibly having the worst day ever. By empathizing with them, the situation becomes less scary, for sure.\""]}, {"topic": "Upscale+Hotels", "question": "How would you react if a celebrity checked into our resort?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know that you will not go into full-fledged fan mode, should a celebrity come for a stay at Company ABC. Stars are people too, and they need to know that they can have a relaxing stay, where their privacy is respected. Show the interviewer that you have the emotional maturity to respond professionally in this type of situation.", "\"I have lived in LA the past, and celebrity sightings are quite common. I know that everyone, no matter their status, deserves a great get-away where they feel they can relax. I would not bat an eye if a celeb checked into the resort. I would treat the person the same as any other guest.\"", "\"I read online that your resort has seen celebrities such as Selena Gomez, John Hamm, and even former president Obama. I would love to have the experience of checking a celebrity into the resort but, of course, would keep my composure on the outside! I know that everyone should feel safe and relaxed when they are away.\""]}, {"topic": "Upscale+Hotels", "question": "How would you respond if a customer left a negative review of yourself or Company ABC online?", "answers": ["In our digital age, with so much riding on our online reviews, it's imperative that negative reviews see a swift and adequate response. Some businesses will hire experts to handle their online reputation. These online reputation management services are precious to companies, such as hotels and resorts, where many potential customers first go online to read reviews before making a reservation. \n\nIf this situation has happened to you before, you could give an example; however, be careful not to draw too much attention to the negatives and focus primarily on the positive outcome. \n\nExperts suggest the following when dealing with negative online reviews:\n\n- Respond quickly to any reviews that are reasonable or understandable \n- Do not become defensive \n- Give a brief public response then offer a more personal private response if possible\n- Address the most important parts of the feedback\n- Reinforce the fact that you care about your quality and customer experience", "\"I would be upset to see a negative review online because I put so much pride in the service that I give. However, I would address the situation quickly without becoming defensive. If the complaint were legitimate, I would ask the customer how I could win them back. Do you have an online reputation team at Company ABC? If so, in that case, I would follow their lead and recommendations to the letter.\"", "\"I am sure Company ABC has an effective protocol in place when situations like this occur. If a customer wrote a bad review online, I would respond if it was appropriate to do so. I put a great amount of pride in the customer service that I deliver and hope that every one of my customers leaves, thrilled with the service they received.\""]}, {"topic": "Upscale+Hotels", "question": "Describe for me your idea of a luxury holiday.", "answers": ["There is no right, or wrong, reply to this question. The interviewer wants to get to know you, and what your expectations may be when it comes to a luxury experience. When a question is open-ended like this, it is easy to ramble on, so be sure to stick to a few key points. For instance, discuss where in the world you would go, where you would stay, and how you would be treated. Perhaps you can mention which amenities would be available to you, on this ideal luxury holiday.", "\"I would love to stay at the Emirates Palace in Abu Dhabi. Did you know that the project cost $3B to build? I have read about how exquisite it is, with a thousand crystal chandeliers throughout the property, fountains, and pools everywhere, and the most luxurious spa. I would purchase their 5 1/2 hour spa day which includes a steam body cleanse, pedicure and manicure, full body massage, and a sea salt exfoliating ritual. To me, it sounds like the ultimate luxury holiday.\"", "\"Staying with Company ABC sounds like a luxury vacation stay, to me. I have not had the opportunity to travel often in my life so the chance to stay here, and experience your luxury spa, fine dining, and relaxing pools would be an incredible experience.\""]}, {"topic": "Upscale+Hotels", "question": "How has your post-secondary education prepared you for this role with Company ABC?", "answers": ["Most upscale hotels will prefer to see education within hospitality, travel and tourism, business administration, or something of the like. Walk the interviewer through your post-secondary education, discussing any specific coursework that may relate to this role. If you do not have formal education, you can refer to on-the-job training that you have received, or even skills that you have acquired along the way, which would help you succeed in this role with Company ABC.", "\"I have a Bachelor's degree in Hotel Management. My best courses were Communication and Presentations Skill as well as Organizational Behavior in Tourism. These courses gave me a great amount of knowledge in how to best communicate with my team, and guests, always delivering over and above expectations.\"", "\"My on-the-job training includes courses and workshops on Special Events Management, Food Production and Safety, as well as Food Costs and Budgeting. My current employer gave me the opportunity to take these courses, based on my exemplary work ethic. I am confident that I could help the Company ABC food and beverage department in many ways including keeping costs low, and training service staff to deliver exceptional experiences to your guests.\""]}, {"topic": "Upscale+Hotels", "question": "What does the word 'hospitality' mean to you?", "answers": ["Hospitality is referring to the exchange between a customer and someone in the service industry. The interviewer understands what hospitality means, and now they want to see that you know the nuances behind providing excellent levels of hospitality to the esteemed guests of Company ABC.", "\"There is a famous quote by Maya Angelou that says, 'People will forget what you said, forget what you did, but people will never forget how you made them feel.' To me, hospitality is making my guests feel comfortable, cared for, and welcomed. They should always leave with a smile on their face, knowing they received the utmost care and respect.\"", "\"When a guest is smiling, appears relaxed, and tells me that they are coming back or recommending the hotel to a friend, I know that I have delivered utmost hospitality. The concept is not only being hospitable but also making people want to return again and again.\""]}, {"topic": "Upscale+Hotels", "question": "How would you handle a co-worker who was acting unprofessionally towards our guests?", "answers": ["One difficult workplace situation is when a co-worker is not performing how they should be, yet, you may not be the manager or supervisor. The problem is - do you interfere or do you let it go? Talk to the interviewer about a time when you have been in a position like this, and discuss what you did to remedy the situation.", "\"I once worked with a co-worker who unknowingly rolled her eyes a lot. Our hotel would be put off, and she wouldn't understand why she continually received complaints. I asked her if she was open to receiving feedback, and she agreed. I went on to explain to her that she was an unintentional eye roller. She had no idea! We worked together for a few weeks on it, and she eventually retrained herself to no longer make that expression.\"", "\"It's important to the reputation of Company ABC that everyone is held accountable for their behavior. If the hotel receives a negative review, that could affect my livelihood as well. If a co-worker were unprofessional, I would discreetly pull them aside to discuss my concern.\""]}, {"topic": "Upscale+Hotels", "question": "Do you have experience collaborating with various departments to ensure all guest requests are addressed efficiently?", "answers": ["Hotels have multiple departments including: \n\n- Housekeeping \n- Front Office\n- Human Resources\n- Security \n- Spa & Retail\n- Food & Beverage\n\nWhen it comes to all of these departments (and more!), operations will run smoothly when communication is strong. Talk to the interviewer about the experience you have working cross-departmentally. If possible, give an example of how you diverted a crisis or gave excellent customer service, by actively collaborating with the team members of another department.", "\"In my current role, I work alongside the Human Resources and Accounting departments on a nearly daily basis. When I need to hire a new team member, my Front Office department holds a meeting with HR and Accounting to determine budget, timeline, and process. Positive cross-collaboration is critical to the success of a hotel operation as it takes all of these specialties to make a business run effectively.\"", "\"The bulk of my experience is working independently; however, I do meet with my corporate head office on a monthly basis, where we hold brainstorm style meetings. I enjoy the feeling of team collaboration. I look forward to meeting your various teams, and working cohesively with all of the important departments at Company ABC.\""]}, {"topic": "Upscale+Hotels", "question": "Have you ever been involved in the development and preparation of a hotel's strategic plan or budget?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know more about your exposure to the financial side of the hotel business. If you have experience in strategic planning, and budgeting, outline this for the hiring manager, including the size of the budget in which you have experience. If you do not have experience with budgeting or financial plans, think back to what you may have learned during your post-secondary education.", "\"I have not had direct involvement in strategic financial planning; however, part of my business degree included courses on financial planning. I am a quick study, and look forward to learning more about the budgetary and planning needs of Company ABC.\"", "\"In my current role, I work alongside the accounting department to ensure that our hiring targets are met, and under budget. Currently, I am responsible for an onboarding budget of $800K per year. Could you share with me more about the budgetary requirements in this role?\""]}, {"topic": "Upscale+Hotels", "question": "Discuss your experience in working and collaborating in a multinational environment.", "answers": ["Whether it be your guests or your co-workers, you are sure to find a diverse environment with you work for Company ABC. The benefits of a diverse workplace include a more innovative workforce, potential opportunities to explore globally, better culture within the organization, a stronger company brand, and elevated customer service. Outline for the interviewer the experience you have working in a multinational environment.", "\"In the past, I spent six months working on a cruise ship where over 200 nationalities were represented. It was one of the most incredible experiences of my life, opening myself up to new cultural experiences. I even learned a few words in various languages. It's important for any workforce to be diverse since it adds to the creativity of the team, and offers a better experience for the customer.\"", "\"I have worked with professionals from all around the world, and appreciate that Company ABC offers a diverse environment as well. With guests from all around the globe, to employees that represent a variety of nations, I am happy with what I see here.\""]}, {"topic": "Upscale+Hotels", "question": "In which hotel management programs and software do you have experience?", "answers": ["There are a variety of programs that hotels use, and the usual suspects are often listed in job postings for hotels and resorts. These programs may sound familiar to you:\n\n- Hotelogix \n- RMS Hotel\n- Preno\n- SmartHotel\n\nShare with the interviewer the programs that you have used. If you are new to the hotel industry, you can discuss any CRM, Point of Sale, or other customer tracking database with which you are familiar. Assure the hiring manager that you can quickly pick up any programs and that you will take the initiative when it comes to learning theirs.", "\"I am new to the hotel and resort industry but have worked in retail before, where a customer management system was in place, as well as a robust point of sale system. I am confident that I can study your system and learn it quickly.\"", "\"I have used a couple of hotel and resort management programs in the past. Primarily, I have worked with Hotelogix. I like that it is cloud-based and can be integrated with online booking systems as well as travel agencies. I am tech savvy and confident in my ability to pick up any new programs quickly. Could you share with me which programs you use at Company ABC? I would be happy to get a head start by taking some online tutorials.\""]}, {"topic": "Upscale+Hotels", "question": "Give me one idea how you would follow up on lost business or guests who have not returned in more than 12 months.", "answers": ["Company ABC thrives on returning guests, referrals, and loyalty programs. Now, the interviewer would like to see that you understand the importance of customers returning. It's time to put your sales hat on! Think of one unique way you could gain the business of a past customer. Dig deeper than sending an email or a promotional item. The hiring manager would like to see some enthusiasm and creativity.", "\"One way that I would follow up on lost business, or guests who have not returned in more than 12 months would be to research their preferences in the CRM. If I found that they were an Opera fan, I would check to see which shows were playing over the next three months. Then, I would create an email with an invitation to stay with us should they be interested in the show. By expressing interest in the guests' likes, I think you would convert many of them to a booking.\"", "\"Customer service and sales are my forte. In my current role, I have the CRM to alert me of upcoming birthdays. I then call and wish the customer a happy early birthday and ask if they have special plans for their day. If they do not, I will invite them to stay with us, with a no-charge upgrade. This technique, of course, is reserved for our guests who have stayed multiple times, but have dropped off in the past 12 months or so.\""]}, {"topic": "Upscale+Hotels", "question": "What is RevPAR, and how do you calculate it?", "answers": ["There are many KPIs to keep an eye on, in the hotel industry. RevPAR stands for Revenue Per Available Room. The interviewer would like to know that you have an understanding of how Company ABC is profitable. The better you understand, the more likely that you will be able to contribute to their bottom line successfully. Keep your response to the point, and easy to understand.", "\"I have received training in hotel KPIs and understand REVPAR to be Revenue Per Available Room. To calculate this, I would take the total room revenue of Company ABC divided by the total amount of rooms available.\"", "\"RevPAR is the total room revenue over the total amount of rooms available. For instance, if Company ABC earns $100,000 per day divided by your 200 rooms, your REVPAR is $500. I have a great understanding of additional hotel KPIs such as Average Daily Rate and Occupancy Percentage.\""]}, {"topic": "Upscale+Hotels", "question": "Are you able to offer flexibility in your schedule?", "answers": ["Hotels are a 24/7 operation, and for that reason, the hiring authority would like to know that they can schedule you for a variety of shifts. Before answering scheduling questions, it's important to be clear on the expectations at Company ABC and how they operate their shifts. If you haven't had a chance to clarify their scheduling needs, now would be the perfect time to ask! \n\nConsider asking, 'What are the scheduling expectations for this position?' If they expect you to work 12 hour days, it would be important for you to know that before you respond with, 'Absolutely! No problem!' You want to be sure that you can meet their expectations. \n\nIf it turns out their schedule expectations won't work for you, think about what you CAN offer and see if you can meet in the middle. It's much better to discuss these things in an interview than for you to commit to a schedule that won't work for you.", "\"If you need overtime in this role, I am happy to accommodate whenever I can. My only restriction is that I cannot work Wednesday nights as I have an evening course those days.\"", "\"In the hotel industry, I anticipate working over 40 hours per week, especially around the holidays. That said, that comes with some limits as I do value my work-life balance. Could you share with me the expectations for this role?\""]}, {"topic": "Upscale+Hotels", "question": "What would you do if a guest accused the housekeeping staff of theft?", "answers": ["Company ABC will have their policies and procedures when it comes to guest concerns and complaints. It's crucial that every grievance is documented so that past data on employees and guests can easily be retrieved. If you are new to the hotel industry, try to do some research on how a typical hotel would handle a theft accusation. You can also ask the interviewer to clarify their policy when it comes to stressful situations such as this.", "\"If a guest accused a housekeeper of theft, I would not immediately accept blame; however, I would create an incident report with the description and value of the item. From there, I would run a report on the guest-room lock. Then, set up interviews with all employees who entered the room. Depending on the value of the missing item. I would also offer to get the police involved.  If the situation were continually pressed, I would ask my corporate office to escalate the situation to the insurance team.\"", "\"I am aware that each state has its laws when it comes to hotel liability. I am sure Company ABC has a disclaimer posted, and you also offer an in-room safe for every room. Could you share with me your policy when it comes to situations such as this?\""]}, {"topic": "Upscale+Hotels", "question": "How have you demonstrated a focus on personal development and career progression in the past six months?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know the ways that you have worked to develop yourself, and your career this year. With self-development always being a hot topic, you will never find that it's time wasted. Whether it's listening to podcasts, reading a book, finding a mentor, going to TED Talks, or investing in a workshop, there is a multitude of ways you can work to develop yourself.", "\"I fully believe in the importance of self-development. This year, I committed myself to read one new book a month, focused on developing my skills in customer service, hospitality, and sales. I also took a Dale Carnegie workshop. Could you share with me the ways you help your employees grow and develop?\"", "\"In the past six months, I have taken three online courses related to leadership, and talent management. I believe that personal, and professional development is critical to my success.\""]}, {"topic": "Upscale+Hotels", "question": "Do you consider yourself of good style and taste?", "answers": ["Of course, you consider yourself to be of good style and taste! Now, you do not need to be an interior designer or fashionista extraordinaire; however, the interviewer would like to see that you understand the importance of showing good taste in an upscale environment such as Company ABC. Briefly discuss how you would let your good taste shine when it comes to customer interactions.", "\"I know my luxury goods when I see them. Often, I will comment on a customers' watch or other fine accessories, letting them know that I recognize their excellent taste. I have taken some professional butler training as well, so my behavior  and comments are always tasteful and on point.\"", "\"I may not be the most stylish person that I know, but I do understand how to put my best foot forward, how to be tactful, tasteful, and professional in every guest interaction.\""]}, {"topic": "Upscale+Hotels", "question": "In which languages are you fluent?", "answers": ["There is a good chance that you will have multiple languages listed on our resume if this is a skill that you possess. This question needs a simple, to the point response. If you do speak additional languages, help the interviewer to understand your level of knowledge by ranking your fluency as a beginner, conversationalist, or fluent, for instance.", "\"I speak English and Spanish fluently, and they are my native languages. I did take French and German in school for a few years. I have a basic understanding of these languages; however, those two are basic and not listed on my resume.\"", "\"I currently speak English only but recently began teaching myself Spanish. I am very much at a beginner level but am happy to fast track my learning to accommodate your Spanish speaking guests.\""]}, {"topic": "Upscale+Hotels", "question": "Company ABC has KPIs to meet. Do you have any sales training?", "answers": ["Company ABC runs on a strict set of KPIs, of which most of the staff are aware. Because of this, the hiring manager wants to ensure that you understand the basis of sales and that you will view every guest interaction as an opportunity to upsell. \n\nKPI's at Company ABC may include: \n\n- Occupancy rates\n- Average income per room rental\n- Revenue per available room\n- Revenue per occupied room\n- Average spend per guest on food & beverage\n- Average spend per guest on gift shop items \n\nShare with the interviewer any sales training that you have. If you do not have any formal sales training, refer to on-the-job education you may have received, or even sales related books you have read. Self-directed education counts too! Have you taken any online sales courses recently?", "\"Just this month I discovered HubSpot Academy and their free sales courses. I just finished their course on 'Inbound Sales Techniques.' I learned a great deal and was able to apply what I learned already, to boost our average spend per guest by 8%.\"", "\"Although I do not have formal sales training, I love to read and teach myself new sales techniques. Last month I finished reading Pitch Anything by Oren Klaff and currently, I am diving into Zig Ziglar's Secrets of Closing the Sale. I do understand that each guest touch point is an opportunity to upsell. I look forward to learning more from the training program at Company ABC.\""]}, {"topic": "Upscale+Hotels", "question": "Is compensation the most important factor for you when taking a new job?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know how much emphasis you put on pay when considering a new position. In addition to compensation, there are many other factors to a fulfilling career in the hospitality industry. These other factors may include:\n\n- work/life balance\n- amount of travel involved in the role\n- overall medical and health benefits\n- additional perks such as car allowance, cell allowance, spending account\n- amount of vacation time\n- career growth opportunity\n- the size of your new team\n- the company's reputation\n- overall workplace culture\n\nTalk to the interviewer about other factors that are important to you when considering a new job. If you are not sure on details for this role, you can ask!", "\"Several factors are important to me when taking a job. Compensation is a driving component but so is the company mission, culture, benefits, and employee perks. I am looking to have an easier commute than I currently experience.\"", "\"I am seeking first a hotel group that I am proud to stand behind. Compensation and commissions will increase when I am happy with my job so I would say that culture and company reputation is most important to me.\""]}, {"topic": "Upscale+Hotels", "question": "Are you applying for any jobs with Company ABC competitors?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know if they will need to compete with other luxury hotels when it comes to hiring you. It always puts a little bit of fire under the hiring manager if they are aware that you are actively looking for a new position. Tell the interviewer about your search so far without disclosing every single detail. It's crucial that you are truthful with your reply as many of these hotels have close HR circles, and exchange information about candidates.", "\"I am in the process of exploring opportunities at hotels and resorts that appeal to me; however, I am selective about where my applications go. I have applied to Hotel A, and Hotel B; however, I am very excited about this particular opportunity and look forward to the next round of interviews.\"", "\"I am applying to other jobs, and am actively interviewing. I do have a strong interest in your role and am wondering what your timeline looks like for the next round of interviews?\""]}]